受热固体在其冷却过程中的收缩作用，被利用在铆接上。

Contraction during cooling of heated solids is made use of in riveting.

曾试图再生催化剂，其方法是在300℃的温度下以8cm3/s的流速对催化剂通氧4小时。

Attempts were made to regenerate the catalyst by passing oxygen at the rate of 8cc/sec. for 4 hours at 300℃.

电能可以储存在由一绝缘介质隔开的两块金属极板内。

Electrical energy can be stored in two metal plates separated by an insulating medium.

这类装置称之为电容器，其储存电能的能力叫做电容。

Such a device is called a capacitor, or a condenser, and its ability to store electrical energy (is called) capacitance.

电容的测量单位是法拉。

It is measured in farads.

所有信号分成许多组，而若干组信号又组合成一个复合信号。

The signals are grouped into packages and a number of packages (are) combined into a composite signal.

顶风时速度为每小时20英里，顺风时速度为每小时80英里。

The speed against the wind is 20 miles per hour and with the wind 80 miles.

第一个计划将需要至少108周，而第二个计划将只需72周。

The first program would require a minimum of 108 weeks, the second only 72 weeks.

在本书中T将只表示温度，除非另有说明。

T will represent temperature alone in this book unless otherwise stated.

自然界中发现的元素大部分是同位素的混合物。

Most elements as found in nature are mixtures of isotopes.

在河口湾出现的混合物越强烈，次表层向陆地方向的流量越来越大。

The more mixing that occurs in the estuary, the greater is the landward flow in the substance layer.

由于空气是由几种不同的纯净物组成，它是一种混合物。

Composed of several different substances, air is mixture.

拉力性能的改善确实确实取决于热处理过程。

The improvement of tensile properties depends indeed on the procedures of heat treatment, as in Fig. 5.

围绕中心向内吹的风与等压线构成20°～40°的夹角。

The wind directed inward around the center makes angles of 20°to 40°with the isobars.

标量是只计大小的量。

A scalar quantity is one defined by its magnitude alone.

这样给的数字不能提供什么有用的情报。

Thus presented, the figures give no useful information.

这些小装置设有电动压缩泵，因而有“电”冰箱之称。

These small units have an electrically compressive pump, hence they have the name “electric” refrigerator.

如果在一张世界地图上把具有相同温度异常的地点以等异常线画出来，结果就可得到一张气温等异常图。

If lines, called isanomals, are drawn on a world map, joining places of equal thermal anomaly, an isanomalous map is the result.

如果把这些物质放在一起并在常压下加热到25℃，则结果会产生一种新的化合物。

If put together and heated to 25℃ at constant pressure, these substances will result in a new compound.

电子学是一切电信系统的基础。

Electronics is the basis of all telecommunication systems.

很多年以前，科学家们就认识到疟疾是由病菌引起的，该病菌是由某种蚊子携带的。

Many years ago, scientists were convinced that malaria is caused by a germ carried by a certain species of mosquito.

食盐溶于水。

Common salt dissolves in water.

图2示出了炼油厂的总布置图。

Figure 2 shows the principal layout of an oil refinery.

锡可以耐受空气或水的腐蚀的。

Tin is resistant to corrosion by air or water.

反应已经终止。

The reaction has already come to an end.

现代科学的最显著特点之一，就是全世界科学家及科学机构之间不断发展更为密切的合作的趋势。

One of the most striking characteristics of modern science has been the increasing trend towards closer cooperation between scientists and scientific institutions all over the world.

帕斯卡把一根水银管带到山顶上，当即发现水银柱随高度的增加而降低。

Pascal carried a mercury tube to the top of a mountain and observed that the column fell steadily as the height increased.

培养方式A显示有大量的干重，而这种培养方式所使用的铵盐量最大。

The highest dry weight is shown for culture A, which received the greatest amount of the ammonium salt.

这可能意味着添加的氨量是这些实验的决定性条件。

This may mean that the amount of nitrogen added was the determining condition for the experiments.

在这些试验的其他条件不变的情况下，当土壤里添加了硫酸铵时，稻子生长得较好。

Rice grew better, under the other conditions of these tests, when ammonium sulphate was added to the soil.

直到1949年急流才作为一种气象实体现象为人们充分认识到。

The jet stream was not fully recognized as a meteorological entity until 1949.

据报道，科学工作者曾针对储存太阳能的问题进行过多年的研究。

It was reported that scientists had worked at the problem of storing the sun’s heat for many years.

资料刚在图上填完，分析就开始了。

The data had no sooner been charted than analysis was started.

这些科学家和技术人员下月将进行一项非常重要的测试。

The scientists and technicians will carry out a very important test next month.

受压缩的气体的温度将会升高。

A gas under compression will become hotter.

在进行激光淬火时，工件表面先用能增大其吸收能力的物质（例如石墨或磷酸锰）涂敷，再借助高功率密度的光束的冲击而加热到奥氏体化温度；当移去光束时，就会因向工件体内的热传递而发生快递的冷却，快得足以促发马氏体转变，而无需施加外部冷却。

In laser hardening, the surface of the workplace, coated with a substance (e.g. graphite or manganese phosphate) which increases its absorptivity, is heated to austenitizing temperature by impingement of the beam at high power densities; on removal of the beam, cooling, sufficiently fast to promote martensitic transformation, takes place by heat transfer to the body of the component, no external cooling being applied.

根据这种应用，多小型机系统中数据库的处理可以分配给专用的、通常可被系统内所有小型计算机访问的后端数据库管理处理器，或通过把原始数据转移到现场数据库的办法而把数据库分配到整个系统中去，并借助于最大限度减少通信设备负载来完成计算更新。

Depending on the application, database handling in a multimini system may be assigned to a special-purpose back-end data base management processor that usually can be accessed by all the minis in the system, or the data bases may be distributed throughout the system in such a way that transfer of raw data is to site of the database and computing updates are performed in a manner that minimizes the load on the communications facility.

氧气也是穿过耐火炉壁向上喷吹到炉池中，从而达到热状态与化学条件的严格控制、良好的工艺灵活性和很高的反应速度，并将耐火材料问题、烟尘问题以及其他采用一般常规风口或顶吹法时所遇到的问题减小到最低限度。

Oxygen is also injected upwards into the molten bath through the refractory walls providing close control of thermal and chemical conditions, superior process flexibility, high reaction rates and minimization of refractory, dust, and other problems encountered with conventional tuyeres or top-blowing methods.

在切削金属之前，应当把机器清理干净。

Before cutting metal you should carefully clean the machine.

此螺钉也可用在用以精密测量小物件直径的卡钳上。

The screw is also used in calipers for measuring very accurately the diameters of small objects.

从这个化合物中释放氧是相当有难度的。

To liberate oxygen from this compound is rather difficult.

当往熔融生铁中吹氧时，硅首先开始氧化。

When oxygen is blown into molten pig iron, silicon begins to oxidize first.

实验表明，存在着化学性质和X射线光谱完全相同但原子量等行之却迥异的两种铅，由此第一次证明了同位素的存在。

The experimental demonstration of the existence of two kinds of lead, identical in chemical properties and X-ray spectra but different in properties involving atomic mass, was the first proof of the existence of isotopes.

每当时机出现时，都应当进行精深观测以便获得这一大气事件的精细结构的资料。

Whenever occasion arises intensive observations are to be done to get the information on the fine structure of the atmospheric event.

在清风吹拂或河道流量减少期间，海岸附近的洋流往往会小得几乎难以察觉。

During periods of light winds or reduced river flow coastal currents often become so weak as to be barely discernible.

该热量能促使反应加速进行。

The heat causes the reaction to be accelerated.

在通讯系统中，电子学要解决的问题是如何把信息从一个地方传送到另一个地方。

In communication, the problem of electronics is how to convey information from one place to another.

要使潮波在赤道上移动的速度跟得上月亮，海洋深度必须为22千米左右。

In order for the tide waves to move fast enough at the equator to keep up with the moon, the ocean would have to be about 22 km deep.

如果与风暴中产生的巨浪相结合，飓风涌浪可具有极大的破坏性。

Combined with extremely high waves generated by the storm, hurricanes surges can be highly destructive.

纯铁是银白色的金属，熔点为1535℃.

Pure iron is a silver-white metal, melting at 1535℃。

建造于古代，这些皇家墓葬群而今已成为最令人振奋的考古遗迹之一。

Built in ancient times, the imperial graves have now become one of the most exciting archaeological sites.

如果我们让三个气团—一个冷气团，一个暖气团和有一个冷气团—依次由西向东运动，则会出现两个峰。

Two fronts will exist if we have three air masses, a cold, a warm, and a cold, moving from west to east one after another.

这次实验的结果令人颇为失望，因此该实验必须从头再来一次。

The result of the experiment is rather disappointing, so it has to be done all over again.

其他条件相同时，蒸散率随湿度增大而减小。

Other things being equal, the evapotranspiration rate decreases with increasing humidity.

一种流体走外管，另一种流体走内管，通过管壁进行热交换。

One of the fluids flows through the outside pipe, the other through the inside pipe, with heat exchange taking place through the wall.

一物体绝不会对另一物体施加作用力而不受到该物体的反作用力。

One object never exerts a force upon another without the second reacting against the first.

受热时，装在气囊里的空气就膨胀，于是气球就上升了。

On being heated, air trapped in the gas bag expanded, so the balloon rose.

串联电路的优点是能在需要时加大电阻以减小电流。

Series circuits have the advantage of increasing resistance to reduce current when this is desirable.

切削金属绝非简单的操作。

Cutting metal is no simple operation.

这一工序叫做定向冷却。

This process is called directional cooling.

设备中的热熔线圈出了故障。

There is something wrong with the heating coil in the device.

这解释了融化中的冰和结冰中的水会具有相同温度的原因。

This accounts for melting ice and freezing water having the same temperature.

油轮把原油运到炼油厂，在那里对原油进行加工。

The oil tanker carries crude oil to a refinery, where the oil is processed.

始终存在着交叉的横向稳定磁场和纵向交变磁场。

There are always crossed transverse steady and longitudinal alternating fields.

这一可能性在试验中于一定程度上得到了证实。

This possibility was supported to a limited extent in the tests.

只需再经过几次试验，价格低廉的人工心脏很快便可研制成功。

The development of an economical artificial heart is only a few transient failures away.

橡胶性软，受压会变形。

Rubber is not hard; it gives way to pressure.

每件产品均须达到严格的质量标准。

Each product must be produced to rigid quality standard.

几乎各类车辆都一直靠汽油机驱动；现在它也用于飞机和汽艇。

The petrol engine has been used to drive almost every kind of thing that runs on wheels; it is also used for aeroplane and small boats.

工程陶瓷主要由所谓耐热氧化物以及许多过渡金属的硼化物、碳化物、氮化物和硅化物组成。

The engineering ceramics consists mainly of the so-called refractory oxides and the borides, carbides, nitrides, and silicides of many of the transition metals.

金属铁的含量是通过电化学溶解的方法用硝酸铜溶液加以确定的。

Metallic iron contents were determined by electrochemical solution of the iron with copper nitrate solution.

铝箔和铝带的制造原理进来一直是一系列研究的主题。

The principles of aluminum foil and strip manufacture have been the subject of a series of investigations recently.

比如说，对纽约市进行人工降雨可能意味着在该市上风不过几英里处进行一次撒播作业。

For example, the artificial modification of rain at New York City may suggest a seeding activity just a few miles upward of the metropolis.

为了进行天气预报，自古以来人们就一直观察天象、风向、大气以及其他各种天气征兆。

Since earliest time, men have watched the sky, the wind, and the atmosphere, as well as a variety of other weather signs, in order to make weather forecast.

这里的设想是，在气象记录中找出一些尽可能类似于当前天气状况的气候条件。

The idea here is to locate in the weather records conditions that are as analogous to the current conditions as possible.

气体不管装在何种容器里，都会把容器充满。

A gas occupies all of any container in which it is placed.

去除这种酸性污染物的最有效的方法是对废气进行冷却，然后加以中和。

The most effective method of removing this acid contaminant is to cool and then neutralize the exhaust gases.

图2为阐明SL/RN法的流程图。

The flow sheet shown in Fig.2 is intended to illustrate the SL/RN process.

我认为，网络经济、中国的经济改革、新技术的采纳和快速增长的国民经济的相互交融，把中国推向了一个突出的位置。

It's my belief that this confluence of a networked economy, China’s reforms, embrace of new technologies and a rapidly growing economy put China in a unique position.

人类破坏大自然的同时也就是在摧毁人类自身，反之亦然，这不仅是在理论上是可能的，而且在现实中也是完全可能的。

It is not only possible but altogether probable that by diminishing nature we diminish ourselves, and vice versa.

氢是所有元素中最轻的元素。

Of all elements, hydrogen is the lightest one.

用高倍望远镜观察到的恒星，绝大多数都在银河系。

By far, the largest number of the stars that we see through a powerful telescope are in the Milky Way System.

不论运动方向怎样，摩擦总是与运动城反作用。

Friction always oppose the motion whatever its direction may be.

刀具使用前，应仔细加以检查。

Cutting tools should be inspected carefully before they are used.

用电解法生产的氢几乎是纯氢，虽然比用热裂法制取氢昂贵得多。

The hydrogen produced by electrolysis is nearly pure, though rather more expensive than that obtained by the thermal cracking process.

粉煤喷吹显然早在1948年就在（前）苏联实现了。

Powder coal injection was apparently accomplished as early as 1948 in Russia.

而西方国家报道的第一次工业试验，则是在1962年才由（美国的）国民钢铁公司和伯利恒钢铁公司完成的。

However, the first commercial scale trial reported by a western country was carried out by National Steel and Bethlehem Steel in 1962.

导线越粗，电阻越小。

The thicker is the wire, the smaller is the resistance.

空气的温度越高，它能吸取的水蒸气就越多。

The air can absorb the more water, the higher its temperature is.

雨水少的地方，水库就会给我们提供水。

Where there is little rain, the reservoir would provide us with water.

无论控制系统什么地方发生故障，都会发出信号。

A signal will be shown wherever anything wrong occurs with the control system.

病菌可通过煮沸或少量加入某些化学药品加以杀灭。

Disease bacteria may be killed by boiling, or by adding small amounts of certain chemicals.

许多人造材料正在取代某些天然材料，这或者是因为天然产品的数量不能满足人类不断增长的需求，或者更多的是因为合成物（这是各种人造材料的统称）的物理性能被选中，甚至受到极大的重视，因而使得它将会在即将加以应用的领域发挥最大的功效。

Many man-made substances are replacing certain natural materials either because the quantity of the natural products cannot meet out ever-increasing requirement, or more often, because the physical properties of the synthetic substance, which is the common name for man-made materials, have been chosen, and even emphasized so that it would be of the greatest use in the field which it is to be applied.

（前）苏联成千上万家企业层采用的产品质量综合管理体系，是在整个企业范围内实行质量管理过程中使企业内各个管理机构和各种管理对象相互作用的综合体，这种互动是借助于材料部门、技术部门和信息部门实现的。

The integrated product quality control system once used by thousands of enterprises in the Soviet Union is a combination of controlling bodies and objects under control interacting with the help of material, technical and information facilities when exercising QC at the level of an enterprise.

每一个家族企业，无论规模大小，技术含量高低，众所周知还是默默无闻。

Whether large or small, high-tech or low, public or private, ever family-owned business is different.

真空管脚是制成针状，装在管子底部。

The terminals of the tube are made in the form of pins at the base of the tube.

这种转子的结构设计得很好，它由一个迭片铁心构成，铁心上绕着线圈。

This type of rotor has a well-designed structure consisting of a laminated core containing a winding.

金属在淬火之后必须回火。

Having been hardened, the metal must be given a temperature treatment.

当普通的棒硫溶解于少量称为二氧化硫的不可燃液体中，并且将此溶液倾倒入结晶盘内，我们便发现该溶液会缓慢地蒸发，而以留下呈细小晶体状的硫。

When ordinary roll sulphur is dissolved in a small quantity of the inflammable liquid known as carbon bisulphide and the solution is poured into a crystallizing dish, we find that the solvent slowly evaporates leaving the sulphur in the shape of crystals.

假如允许通过安培计的电流太多，则当接通该安培计时就会使电压会下降，因而所测得的电压值便是错误的。

If too much current flowed through an ammeter, the voltage would fall when it was connected, and the measured voltage would be wrong.

如果甲烷受到冷却和压缩，它就会液化。

If methane is cooled and compressed, it liquefies.

气缸中的爆燃温度是如此之高，以致气缸壁的金属材料经受不住。

The temperature of the explosion in the cylinders is so high that the metal of the cylinder walls cannot stand it.

我们必须有重量、体积和长度单位，以便度量物质。

We must have units of weight, volume, and length to measure matter.

某些合金元素能使钢的晶粒细化，从而提高了钢的硬度和强度。

Some alloying elements make the grain of the steel finer, thus increasing the hardness and strength of steel.

而今，气象学家们对于飓风形成、运动和消失的机理已经了然于胸。

Nowadays meteorologists have already been clear about how the hurricane forms, moves and disappears.

催化剂和稀释剂先给入混合槽中，而后同乙烯和氢一起送入反应器。

Catalyst and diluent are initially fed to a mixing tank prior to being passed on to the reactor along with ethylene and hydrogen.

现时对光子计算甚感兴趣的基本原因，乃是总也不能满足的对更快速计算机的需求。

Underlying much of the current interest in optical computing is the insatiable need for faster machines.

全世界都采用相同的数学符号。

Through the world come to use the same signs and symbols for mathematics.

只有以这种方式你才能成功地做好这个实验。

Only in this way can you succeed in making the experiment.

一定重量的气体的体积与绝对温度成正比，假如压力不变的话。

The volume of a given weight of gas varies directly as the absolute temperature, provided that the pressure does not change.

宏观物质的波动特性不明显，因为其波长很短，难以察觉。

The “wave” properties of macroscopic matter are not apparent because the wavelength is undetectably small.

传播在这张图上表现为向某一方向倾斜的表示云量的连线。

Propagation is manifested on this diagram as a coherent line of cloudiness sloping in one direction or another.

我们正在慢慢摸索着去理解这些事物。

We are slowly groping towards an understanding of those things.

电热器能将其电能转化为热能。

Electric heaters can have their electric energy transformed into heat.

性质与光相似的辐射能

radiant energy similar in nature to light

该金属对酸性腐蚀的耐受性

resistance of the metal to acid corrosion

从静止状态开始落下的自由落体

a freely falling body starting at rest

能量以波的形式从太阳传播到地球上。

Energy comes to the earth from the sun in the form of waves.

许多年以前，人们并不了解这个事实：是地球围绕太阳转而不是相反。

Many years ago, people did not learn about the fact that it is the earth that revolves around the sun instead of the latter revolving around the former.

这种金属是采用空气熔炼还是真空熔炼。

It is no matter that the metal melts in air or vacuum.

电解质就是其水溶液能导电的那些化合物。

Electrolytes are compounds whose water solutions conduct electricity.

像拉乌尔定律一样，亨利定律适用于一定范围，该范围对每一体系而言是不同的，但亨利定律仅只在低浓度时才有效。

Like Raoult’s law, Henry’s law applies within a concentration range whose extent varies from one system to another, but it is valid only at low concentration.

运动部件间的摩擦力使金属磨损，这就缩短了这些部件的使用寿命。

Friction wears away metal in the moving parts, which shortens their working life.

静止的物体不可能运动，除非对它施加作用力。

A body at rest cannot move unless a force acts upon it.

力可用磅来计算，不管它是怎样产生的。

Force is measured in pounds, no matter how it is produced.

合金是介于混合物和化合物之间的一种中间结构。

Alloys belong to a half-way house between mixtures and compounds.

好塑料的必要条件是合意的塑性、对酸碱的耐蚀性和混入各种色料的可能性。

The requirements of a good plastic are desirable plasticity, acid and alkali resistance, and the possibility to mix with various colors.

人们将这种变化称之为化学变化。

People call this kind of change chemical change.

此法免除了其他挥发物或有机物的干扰。

This method is free from interference by other volatile material or organic matter.

这些钢质部件在冻结温度下摸起来冰冷。

The steel parts feel icy cold at freezing temperatures.

原子能将会广泛而有效地加以利用。

Atomic energy will be widely and effectively used.

他发明了一种全新的工作方法。

He invented a completely new method of work.

所有放射性元素都在不断地蜕变。

All radioactive elements are constantly disintegrating.

没有催化剂能在本研究所采用的条件下保持稳定。

No catalyst is stable under the conditions employed in this work.

可以利用激光束在金刚石上打孔。

Use can be made of laser beams to burn a hole in a diamond.

相对论预言，在引力场作用下，光不仅会弯曲，而且要减速。

Relativity predicts that light should be not only slowed but bent in a gravitation field.

铝直到19世纪才为人们所知，因为铝总是和其他元素—最常见的是氧（因为铝对氧的亲和力很强）—化合在一起，所以在自然界任何地方都找不到处于游离状态的铝。

Aluminum remained unknown until the 19th century, because nowhere in nature is it found free, owing to its being always combined with other elements, most commonly with oxygen, for which it has a strong affinity.

绝缘材料因为过热而烧毁了。

The insulation was burnt for overheating.

与铁不同，水银在常温下是液态。

Adverse to iron, mercury is in a liquid state at ordinary temperature.

液体和蒸汽的混合物进入第一分离器。

The mixture of liquid and vapor passes into the first separator.

拉长了的弹簧能在收缩到它的正常长度的过程中做功。

A stretched spring can do work in contracting to its normal length.

假如便携式电器的挠性引线磨损而裸露其中的金属线，并且后者随后碰巧与该电器的金属部件相接触，那么谁碰到这些部件，谁就会触电。

If the flexible leads of a portable electric appliance fray and break and the wires then happen to touch the metal parts of the appliance, these parts can give a severe electric shock to anyone who touches them.

如果我们接入一个安培计来测量流入手电筒电珠里的电流，并接入另一个安培计去测量流出的电流，那么它们各自哦读数就会相同。

If we connect one ammeter to measure the electric current flowing into a torch bulb and another one to measure the current flowing out, they each read the same.

将石墨颗粒均匀地悬浮在整个盐浴中

to suspend graphite particles homogeneously throughout the salt both

围绕空间网格各个格点分布的对称要素的延伸网络

an extended network of symmetry elements distributed about the points of a space lattice

春潮每间隔1周出现一次，通常出现在距离新月和满月几天之内。

Spring tides occur every two weeks, usually within a few days of the new and full moon.

此外，后门程序是多维的；因此，建议使用多种检测方法来最大限度地防范后门程序BO2000在网络上的一台或多台电脑内安装，并且一旦有该程序装入，就可及其详尽地获知其相关情况。

In addition, backdoor programs are multi-dimensional, so several detection methods are recommended to achieve maximum protection against and awareness of the installation of BO 2000 on a machine or series of machines on a network.

各种不同形式的能都可用来做功。

Different forms of energy all can be used to do work.

麻省理工学院（MIT）的研究人员已经开发出一种硅晶片移植技术，它有望在将来用于长期的药物服用。

Researchers at Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) have developed a silicon wafer implant that may be used for long term drug administration in the future.

用闪速熔炼法炼铜时产生的炉渣要缓慢地加以冷却，而后破碎、研磨至大小为200目的颗粒，并进行浮选，以回收其所含的铜。

The slag produced during the flash smelting process would be slowly cooled, crushed, ground to 200-mesh, and floated for recovery of the contained copper.

气压低，沸点就低。

When the pressure gets low, the boiling point becomes low.

化学清洗明显优越，既适用于直管，也适用于弯管。

Chemical cleaning has the distinct advantage of being equally applicable to straight or bowed tubes.

雷达发射的是波长非常短的电磁波。

Radar involves transmitting electromagnetic waves of very short wave length.

当达到露点温度时，水汽将从其看不见的状态凝结成可见的水分。

The water vapor will change from its invisible state to condense into invisible moisture when the dew point temperature is reached.

充了电的电容器就像一个蓄电池一样。

The charges capacitor behaves as a secondary battery.

然而，这个小组还建议及早确定几个精心设计的随机化的撒播试验，以便可对各种风暴类型的可撒播性进行评估。

But the panel also recommended the early establishment of several carefully designed, randomized seeding experiments, planned in such a way as to permit assessment of the seedability of a variety of storm types.

图3中的流程图阐明了计算机的工作原理。

The flow sheet shown in Fig.3 is intended to illustrate how the computer works.

那批易碎的瓷器经历了颠簸的旅途而完好无损。

The fragile china survived the bumpy journey safe and sound.

气体分子运动起来比液体和固体分子更为自由。

The molecules in gases move more freely than do those of liquids and solids.

原子是元素的最小粒子。

The atom is the smallest particle of an element.

太阳从东方升起，至西方落下。

The sun rises in the east and sets in the west.

如果能知道频率，就能求出波长。

If you know the frequency, you can find the wave length.

氢是最轻的元素，原子量为1.008。

Hydrogen is the lightest element, with an atomic weight of 1.008.

重力是向下的力，任何物体都会向下运动。

Weight is a down force, and therefore any object will move downward.

太阳晒热地球，从而使植物得以生长。

The sun heats the earth, which makes it possible for plants to grow.

要说明汽车的速度，就必须获知它的行驶方向。

To state the velocity of a car we must find in which direction it is travelling.

压力不变，一定重量的气体的体积与绝对温度成正比。

If the pressure does not change, the volume of a given weight of gas will be in direct proportion to the absolute temperature.

半导体设备没有灯丝，因而不需要加热功率和加热时间。

Semiconductor devices have no filament or heaters; hence they require no heating power or warmed-up time.

有催化剂时反应速度的加速叫做催化作用。

Increased rate of reaction, in the presence of catalyzers, is called catalysis, or catalytic action.

激光而今正在很多领域得到广泛应用。

Light amplification by stimulated emission of radiation, or laser, is now widely used in a lot of fields.

当人们发现他们所曾接触过的人正患有艾滋病时，许多人会感觉恐慌。

Many may feel alarmed when people have found anybody they have contacted is ill with AIDS, or Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome.

绝缘体实际上也导电，但其电阻很高。

Insulators in reality conduct electricity but, nevertheless, their resistance is very high.

退化作用/降解作用

degradation

分布状况

distribution

观察结果

observation

准备工作/制备过程

preparation

还原反应/作用/过程

reduction

共振现象

resonance

在快速氧化过程中会产生火焰。

In rapid oxidation a flame is produced.

当能量以辐射能形式存在时，可以在传递很长距离后，才被吸收或转化为热。

While in the form of radiation, the energy may travel a tremendous distance before being absorbed or changed back into heat.

我们的标准化处理使得图3中的曲线可以被视为概率分布曲线。

Our normalization is such that the curves in Fig. can be regarded as probability distributions.

一到达对流层，温度就停止随着高度的降低而下降的过程。

As soon as the tropopause is reached, temperature stops decreasing with height.

综合自动控制系统能利用计算机监控整个操作过程。

The complex automatic control system monitors over the process by means of computers.

引线的箭头标记着材料类型。

The arrows in the leads identify the materials.

光波从光源扩散时，强度减弱。

Light waves weaken as they spread out from a source.

在20世纪60年代以前，人们关于30千米左右以上的高空大气知识主要是根据地基观测推断得到的。

Prior to the 1960s knowledge of the atmosphere above about 30km was based largely on inferences from ground-based observations.

这台新型电视机真是物美价廉。

This new type of TV set is really fine and inexpensive.

由于电子传导是借助空穴和电子两者进行的，因而结型晶体管是双极式的。

Since conduction is by both holes and electrons, the junction transistor is bipolar.

我们必须把这些现象弄清楚。

We must make the phenomena clear.

已经在人造卫星上对脉冲激光系统进行了试验。

A pulsed laser system has been tested on a satellite.

显然，较低的温度可以使细菌的活动减慢。

Clearly, cool temperature slows down the action of bacteria.

车间里有一排排的机器设备，他以往可从未见识过。

There are rows of machines or equipment in the workshop he has never seen before.

各传感器开关位于每条给料皮带末端附近。

Sensor switches are located near the end of each feed belt.

第一批电子计算机于1946年投入使用。

The first electronic computers went into operation in 1946.

“速度”和“速率”这两个词，如果不是用在技术书中，通常可认为是同义词。

The words “velocity” and “speed” are normally considered

电动机可/能将电能转换为机械能。

The electric motors covert electric energy into mechanical energy.

高空飞机过去是而且现在仍旧是一种了不起的飞行器。

The high-altitude plane was and still is a remarkable bird.

甚至在第二个五年计划之前，中国就已经在生产各种车床、机器、器械和仪表了。

Even before the Second Five-year Plan, China was already producing all kinds of lathes, machines, apparatus and instruments.

火箭的第一级在火箭起飞后仅仅几分钟就被扔掉。

The first stage of a rocket is thrown away only minutes after the rocket takes off.

那些半导体材料本来是应该保存在某个干燥地方的。

Those semiconductor materials should have been kept in some dry place.

普通玻璃必须先消除色差才能制成光学玻璃。

Ordinary glass must be first achromatized to become optical glass.

工艺流程中包括集水池，是为了消除来自五个来源的废水在流量和水质上的波动。

The collective reservoir is included in the flow scheme to iron out fluctuations in flows and qualities of the effluents from the five sources.

气体即使封闭在刚性容器中，在高温下也会膨胀。

Confined in a rigid container, gas will expand at some high temperature.

液体冻结时收缩，但水却是这一规律的一个重要例外。

Liquids contract in freezing; water is an important exception to this rule.

白色的或发亮的表面反射热量，而黑色的表面则吸收热量。

White or shining surfaces reflect heat; dark surfaces absorb it.

在顶吹转炉内，氧气经由一根叫做吹氧枪的水冷铜管喷吹到炉料的表面上。

Inside the L.D. converter oxygen is blown on to the surface of the charge through a water-cooled copper pipe, called a lance.

于是氧气便同铁中的杂质发生剧烈的反应。

The oxygen reacts vigorously with impurities in the iron.

第一类反应叫放热反应，第二类反应叫吸热反应。

Reactions of the first kind are called exothermic reactions and those of the second kind endothermic reactions.

当台风在陆地上移动时，其强度逐渐减弱。

When moving over land, a typhoon is gradually decreased in severity.

高温和高压把这些埋藏在地下的有机物变成了煤、石油和天然气。

High temperatures and pressures changed the underground organic materials into coal, petroleum and natural gas.

实验发现，碘化银产生撒播效果的临界温度比干冰略低（碘化银为-5℃到-10℃，而干冰为-3℃到-4℃）。

It was found that there is a slightly colder threshold for seeding effect to occur for silver iodide than for dry ice (-5℃ to -10℃for silver iodide versus -3℃ to -4℃ for dry ice）.

这正是这个实验意欲解决的问题。

This is what the experiment is intended to solve.

是太阳给我们提供了光明和温暖。

It is the sun that gives us light and warmth.

尽管载荷发生变化，施加在其上的电压却仍保持相当的恒定。

Despite changes in the load, the voltage applied to it remains fairly constant.

尽管面对国际的压力，和谈的进展仍已缓慢。

Despite international pressure, progress has slowed in the peace talks.

这辆小汽车的启动速度很快。

The speed at which the car starts is fast.

科研人员对这种材料进行了热处理。

The researchers heat-treated this kind of material.

这个国家在军事、政治和经济等方面都很强大。

This country is militarily, politically and economically strong.

这篇论文评述了在直接还原、氧气碱性转炉炼钢和连续浇铸这三个方面的发展情况。

The thesis reviewed the developments accomplished in direct reduction, BOF process and continuous casting.

在19世纪，潮汐振荡和声重力振荡的理论曾是受到极大关注的课题。

During the 19th century, the theories of tidal and acoustic gravity oscillations were subjects of great interest.

这磁场可以是条形磁铁的磁场，可以是马蹄形磁铁的磁场，也可以是电磁铁的磁场。

This magnetic field may be that of a bar magnet, a U-shaped magnet, or an electromagnet.

所有这些预报评分均比通过预报前期温度将持续不变而获得的评分要高。

All of these scores are higher than could be obtained by predicting temperatures of the previous to persist unchanged.

数字系统的基本要求之一就是要有某种类型的存储器，换言之，也就是要有一种通过脉冲或边沿能使其置于逻辑1，并能保持其电平直到施以复位脉冲为止的电路。

One of the basic requirements within digital systems is for some kind of memory, in other words, a circuit that can be set to logic 1 by a pulse or edge and which will hold this level until the circuit gets a reset pulse.

由于摩擦而产生的力称之为摩擦力。

The forces due to friction are called frictional forces.

通过这种途径，既可避免高纬地区越变越冷，也可防止低纬地区越变越热。

Thereby the higher latitudes are prevented from becoming increasingly colder and the low latitudes from becoming increasingly hotter.

山顶上升气流强度随速矢端迹曲率加大而稍有加强，在图上B点是29.0米/秒，C点是26.1米/秒。

Peak updraft strength is slightly enhanced with hodograph curvature, 29.0m/s in B versus 26.1m/s in C.

在这些波向外扩散的同时，它们也在按波长分开，这一过程叫频散。

At the same time the waves are fanning out, they are also separating by wavelength, a process known as dispersion.

过去三十年的研究已经产出了大量成果，揭示了昆虫害虫对杀虫剂所产生的抗药性的实质。

Research in the past thirty years has revealed a great deal about the nature of the resistance of insect pests to insecticides.

到冬季快要开始的时候，沿岸的海水已经彻底混合，表层水和底层水几乎没有什么温度差和盐度差了。

By the time winter begins, coastal waters are thoroughly mixed, with virtually no temperature or salinity differences between surface and bottom waters.

当今世界充满危险，因此就有了那个令人毛骨悚然的笑话，说我们尚未受到外星文明造访的原因在于：但凡文明发展到我们目前这个阶段，它们往往就自行毁灭了。

The world today is filled with danger, hence the sick joke that the reason we have not been contacted by an alien civilization is that civilizations tend to destroy themselves when they reach our stage.

如果给出了风速、刮风时间和吹程，就有可能预报由某一特定风暴所引起的海浪的高度。

Given wind speed, duration, and fetch, it is possible to predict the size of the waves generated by a given storm.

渗碳法在飞机制造中比其他方法更常使用。

Casehardening is used more often than the other methods in aircraft work.

工具和工件不直接接触。

There is no physical contact between tool and workpiece.

火箭已经用来探索宇宙。

Rocket has found application for the exploitation of the universe.

使用计算机可以大大提高劳动生产力。

The application of electronic computers

我认为，就数据库这门课而论，布朗先生比我教得好。

I think that, as far as the course of database is concerned, Mr. Brown is a better teacher than me.

计算机比人检查得更细心、更勤快。

The computer is a far more careful and industrious inspector than human beings.

石蕊试纸可用以指示溶液中是否含有酸。

Litmus paper can be used as an indicator of the presence of acid in a solution.

在美国，冷雾消散的实际操作自1963年以来一直是成功的。

Cold fog dispersal has been an operational success in the U.S. since 1963.

河流下游的情况是多种多样的。

The lower stretches of rivers show considerable variety.

政府发言人承认这位科学家关于在海洋沿岸建立核电站的想法是可行的。

The government spokesman admitted the feasibility of the scientist's idea about establishing a nuclear power station along the coast.

正在严密的安全保护下进行这项实验的技术人员感觉到，他们是极其安全的。

Safety was deeply felt by the technicians who were carrying out this experiment amidst tight security.

中国丰富石油资源的发现也是和石油工人的努力“争气”分不开的。

The discovery of rich petroleum resources in China is also inseparable from the oil-workers’ efforts to “win honors”.

大多数自然资源保护主义者认为，在良好的生态环境中，人类最易兴旺发达，而各种野生动物的持续生存是这种良好生态环境的标志。

Most of the conservationists believe that humans thrive best in ecological health and that the sign of this health is the survival of a diversity of wild animals.

尼龙的强度几乎是天然丝的两倍。

Nylon is nearly twice as strong as natural silk.

自由大气中的环流主要是纬向的，仅有微弱的经向性。

The circulation of the free atmosphere is largely zonal and only to a slight extent meridional.

日常生活经验告诉我们，重东西的稳定性比轻东西要好些。

Everyday experience shows us that heavy objects are more stable than light ones.

很长时间以来，科学家们深信物质是不灭的。

For a long time, scientists are confident that all matter is indestructible.

他们十分熟悉这类晶体管放大器的性能。

They are very familiar with the performance of this type of transistor amplifier.

尽在几年以前，废汽车切碎后的非磁性部分只用手选法回收一些铜、锌和铝，然后就大部分弃置到填埋场了。

Only a few years ago, most of the nonmagnetic fraction of a shredded car was disposed of in landfill areas after hand-picking to recover some of the copper, inc and aluminum.

水在4℃以下是不断地膨胀，而不是不断地收缩。

When blow 4℃, water is in continuous expansion instead of continuous contraction.

等离子平板电视技术是今年才发展起来的。

The Plasma Display Panel Television technology is fairly recent development.

他们特别重视提高电子设备的质量。

They laid special emphasis on raising the quality of electronic devices.

图形的尺寸必须正确。

The image must be dimensionally correct.

氯的化学性质和活泼。

Chlorine is very active chemically.

这项发现有多大的历史意义？

How historically significant is this discovery?

他们的科研任务完成得很漂亮，硕果累累。

Their tasks in research have been beautifully fulfilled with a lot of good results.

从涤气器里出来的洗涤水夹带有大量的固体颗粒。

The wash water from the gas washer was heavily laden with solid particles.

大家知道，气体是完美的弹性体。

It is a matter of common observation that gases are perfectly elastic.

此地的电是由附近的一家核电站供给的。

The electricity here is supplied by a nuclear power station nearby.

美国绝大多数间谍卫星，按其设计（构想），是在完成其使命之后，在大气层中焚毁。

Most US spy satellites are designed to burn up in the earth’s atmosphere after completing their missions.

涂层的厚度范围为0.1～0.2 毫米。

Coating thickness range from one tenth mm to 2 mm.

色彩亮丽是他的绘画的典型特征。

Bright colors characterize his paintings.

电子和原子的行为方式，多少有点像一组波。

An electron or an atom behaves in some ways as thought it were a group of waves.

通常用字母I来表示电流，用E来表示电动势，用R来表示电阻。

The letter I is commonly used for current, E for electromotive force, R for resistance.

在临界温度以上和高压下，蒸汽可能会变得像处于低温下的液体那样密度高且不可压缩。

Above the critical temperature and under high pressure the vapor may become as dense and as incompressible as the liquid at lower temperature.

生铁是一种铁碳合金，其碳含量在百分之二以上。

Pig iron is an alloy of iron and carbon wih carbon content more than 2 per cent.

原子内的大部分空间是空的，其全部物质几乎都集中到称之为原子核的一个极小的核内。

An atom is mostly empty space with almost all its substance concentrated into a tiny kernel called the nucleus.

在对流层，气温随高度增加而降低，其递减率通常为每上升100米下降0.6℃。

The temperature decreases with elevation through the troposphere at a rate, normally, of about 0.6℃ for 100m.

从世界各地送展的新型高技术设备中有许多是中国制造的。

There are new types of high-tech equipment here from all over the world and many of them are made in China.

信号表明，计算机没有毛病。

The signal was shown about the computer’s being in order.

地球绕轴自转，引起昼夜的变化。

The rotation of the earth on its own axis causes the change from day to night.

这种金属的电阻太高，所以我们不能用它做导电线材。

The resistance of this metal is too high for us to use it as a conductor of electricity.

这些马达作为泵工作时，（它们）就会给储能箱增压使车减速。

The motors are engaged as pumps, building pressure in an accumulator tank to slow the car.

地球大气随地球的自传和在其中的热输送状况导致具有上述特征的不规则波的形成。

Conditions of rotation and heat transfer in the atmosphere of the earth are such that irregular waves of the characteristics described above will form.

过了几年在这一领域才有了突破。

It was a few years before a breakthrough was made in this field.

这就是此方程的含义。

This is what the equation means.

这就是这台设备的工作原理。

This is how this device works.

虽然华氏温标很不方便，但英国和美国仍在使用。

The Fahrenheit is quite inconvenient, yet it is still used in England and U.S.A.

水汽较轻，否则它不会升到空中。

Water vapor is lighter, which would otherwise not rise into air.

设上图中AB代表一个倾斜平面，其表面光滑且非曲面。

Let AB in the figure above represent an inclined plane the surface of which is smooth and unbending.

这样的缓慢压缩能使这种气体经历一系列状态，但各种状态都很接近于平衡状态，所以这一过程被叫做准静态过程，或“近似静态”过程。

Such a slow compression carries the gas through a series of states, each of which is very nearly an equilibrium state and it is called a quasi-static or a “nearly static” process.

在理解了温度的概念以后，又经过多年的科学研究，人们才确定了热的真正性质。

After the concept of temperature became understood, there were many years of scientific development before the real nature of heat was established.

1752年，电学的研究还几乎没有开始，富兰克林就已在雷暴云中进行了危险的风筝实验，从而奠定了大气电学的基础。

The study of electricity had hardly begun when Franklin, in 1752, conducted his dangerous kite experiment in a thunderstorm, founding the science of atmospheric electricity.

而今，关于原子的真实性已无争议，它们在分子和晶体中的结合方式已被很好地了解，因此化学计算的三定律可被看作是原子的存在及其性质所引发的简单结果。

Now, when there is no question as to the reality of atoms and when their mode of combination in molecules and crystals is well understood, the three laws of stoichiometry are seen to be simple consequences of the existence and properties of atoms.

随着风力明显增大，蒸发也显著增强。

Wind increased sharply with the result that evaporation went up remarkably.

我们现金所知道的这个宇宙当初可能起始于一场巨大的爆炸。

The universe as we know it might have begun with a great explosion.

如果植物处于缺水状态，它们就无法良好生长。

Plants which were in the absence of water would not grow well.

要制造原子弹，我们必须用铀235，因为铀的所有原子都会裂变。

To make an atomic bomb we have to use uranium 235, in which all the atoms are available for fission.

这种事件是在经过短时间中断生产之后，在反应器仍然是热的情况下重新操作时偶然发生的。

When operation was resumed after a short interruption, when the reactors were still hot, such event occurred momentarily.

信息必须先从声音转变成电，才能由无线电传播。

Messages have to be changed from sound into electricity before they can be sent by radio.

风可以把沙子带到许多英里以外的地方。

Sand may be carried many miles by the wind.

水是由氧和氢构成的。

Water consists of oxygen and hydrogen.

船只可能不得不等待多日才能等到合适的海波和潮流，从而使得它们能安全地进港。

Ships may have to wait for days before finding a time when incoming waves and tidal currents are right, permitting them to enter the harbor with safety.

计算机发明于1946年，而今已取得惊人的进展，发生了振奋人心的变化。

Invented in 1946, the computer has now made surprising advances and exciting changes.

中国人似乎为他们在经济上的成就而自豪，这是合乎情理的。

The Chinese seemed justifiably proud of their own economic achievements.

因为他没有遵守安全规章，所以机器出了故障。

His failure to observe the safety regulations resulted in an accident to the machinery.

鱼能发电，其强度足以点亮小灯泡，甚至能驱动马达。

The idea of a fish being able to generate electricity strong enough to light small bulbs, even to run an electric motor, is almost unbelievable.

改进的表格灵活性很大，你可以利用这一特点快捷地绘制和设计表格，并可以自动地在表格周围进行文字环绕，还可创建含有浮动表格的文件。

You can draw and format tables quickly to take advantage of improved table flexibility, automatically wrap text around your tables, and create documents that contain floating tables.

数据被传送到总线上并被正在接受的小型计算机所接收；或者当通信线路是菊花链时，每个相连的小型机可以把信息传给总线的下一分支，直到预期的接收机从链路上获得信息为止。

Data may be broadcast onto the bus and intercepted by the receiving mini, or, where the communication link is a daisy chain, each connecting mini may pass information on to the next leg of the bus until the intended recipient finally takes the message off the link, each of these interconnect schemes have their merits, depending on the application.

波浪除非被海洋边界以某种方式消除或施加影响，否则它就会沿着其形成之时的风向继续移动很长距离。

Unless destroyed or influenced in some way or other by ocean boundaries, waves continue to travel for long distances in the direction that the wind was blowing when they formed.

撇开原来与磨光有关的主要问题不谈，技术问题并不是最难解决的问题。

Despite initial major problem with grinding the technical problem were not the most difficult ones to solve.

中子和质子组成原子核，而电子则围绕原子核旋转。

The neutrons and protons form the nucleus of the atom, around which the electrons moves.

图中示出了连续加料对耗电量和电极消耗的影响，连续加料工艺不仅不再需要补充装料，而且也能在连续装料期间完成精炼操作。

The figure shows the effect of continuous charging on energy and electrode consumption, which not only eliminates the need for back charging, but also accomplishes refining during the continuous feed period.

因为沥青或焦油是厂内生产的，其使用已经增加。

Because it is generated internally, the use of pitch or tar has increased.

当两种元素化合成两种以上化合物时，可和同样重量的一种元素的各个重量是成小整数比率的。

When two elements combine into more than one compound, the different weights of one element which combines with the same weight of the other are in the radio of small integers.

浓差电池

concentration cell

湿敏元件

dew cell

离子交换槽

exchanger cell

晶格晶胞

lattice cell

金相研究室

metallurgy cell

光电管

photoelectric cell

多单元法

poly cell approach

初基胞，原细胞

primitive cell

温差电偶

thermoelectric cell

载频放大器

carrier amplifier

载波信道

carrier channel

（汽车的）底盘框架

carrier frame

运载火箭

carrier rocket

移动齿轮

carrier wheel

电荷载流子

charge carrier

我们要完全掌握集成电路工艺，必须采取三项措施。

There are three steps which must be taken before we graduate from the integrated circuit technology.

此方法的发明者所表现的远大目光和广阔知识，给人以十分良好的印象。

The foresight and coverage shown by the inventor of the process are most commendable.

居里夫妇也成功地分离出第二个放射性元素—钋。

The Curies had also succeeded in isolating a second rayshooting element—polonium.

当把一根铜丝的两端连接到一个叫做电池的器件上时，就会有稳定的电流通过该铜丝。

When the ends of a copper wire are joined to a device called an electric cell a steady stream of electricity flows through the wire.

小型发电机常常采用旋转电枢，而大型发电机通常采用固定电枢和旋转磁场。

While small generations frequently have revolving armatures, large machines usually have stationary armatures and revolving fields.

浓盐酸在电解时分解成氢和氯：氢沉积在阴极上，氯沉浸在阳极上，这样就使浓盐酸变稀了。

Concentrated hydrochloric acid is decomposed by electrolysis into hydrogen deposited at the cathode and chlorine deposited at the anode, and so the acid becomes dilute.

蓝牙

blue tooth

网络资源

cyber source

数据限制条件

data qualification

对话框

dialog box

高清晰度画面

high-definition pictures

最佳性价比系统

optimum price-to-performance system

数据送话机

dataphone

信息高速公路

information superhighway

线性感应马达

linear-induction motor

微波

microwave

纳米技术

nano-technology

路由器

router

软件

software

超导体

superconductor

试管婴儿

test-tube baby

汽轮机列车

turbotrain

吊锚，履带拖拉机

cat

旋塞，吊车

cock

挡块，止动爪

dog

接合板，夹板

fish

绳索

fox

支架，铁杆

horse

金属垫块

pig

斑点

snake

底座，机床身

bed

拉床，钳工台

bench

轴承盖，罩壳

cap

镀层

coat

皮碗，轴套

cup

控制屏

desk

闸瓦，履带片

shoe

箱体，罩

house

放料盘

table

机身

body

吊钩

ear

孔环

eye

厚薄规

finger

支座

foot

游丝

hair

手柄，指针

hand

冒口，刀架

head

开度

mouth

座

neck

喷嘴

nose

粗糙面

tooth

工字梁

H-beam

工字杆

H-post

工字钢

I-bar

O型环

O-ring

T字刀架

T-rest

T恤衫

T-shirt

槽钢，U型钢

U-steel

马蹄形磁铁

U-shaped magnet

三角皮带

V-belt

V型切口

V-notch

交叉支撑

X-brace

十字钻头

Cross-bit

麻花钻

Twist drill

气压温度计

barothermograph

集成电路

IC, integrated circuit

音乐电视

MTV, music television

串联电路确实有这样的优点：在需要时用以增大电阻来减少电流。

Series circuits do have the advantage of increasing resistance to reduce current when this is desirable.

这些实验研究即使没有给出其他结果，但却对相似法描述这类气流的能力和局限性给予了较高的评价。

These experimental studies gave, if nothing else, a greater appreciation of the power and limitations of similarity methods in describing such flows.

这些过程和环流有助于形成与图1所示向类似的中尺度气压系统（即直径约为几百千米的系统）。

The processes and circulations are instrumental in the formation of mesoscale pressure similar to those shown in Fig.1 (i.e., with diameters on the order of several hundred kilometers).

激光是近年来最轰动的科学成就之一，因为它可以应用于许多科学领域，也适合各种实际用途。

Laser is one of the most sensational developments in recent years, because of its applicability to many fields of science and its adaptability to practical uses.

像触屏式控制面板、大型电视终端、广角背景摄像机和文本摄像机这些功能。

Features like a touch-screen control panel, a large TV terminal, a wide-angled background camera, and a text camera are optional with some models of videoconferencing systems.

在电话上统某人交谈时可以看着对方的视频画面，这听上去是一个很不错的想法，但结果证明它在实践中一直未能普及。

Looking at a video picture of someone while talking to him or her on the phone sounds like a great idea, but in practice it’s never proved popular.

万维网是一个基于超文本的因特网资源查询和访问系统；它是控制多媒体文件在因特网上创立及展示方式的一套程序、标准和协议。

The World Wide Web is a hypertext-based system for finding and accessing Internet resources; it is a set of programs, standards, and protocols governing the way in which multimedia files are created and displayed on the Internet.

该产品的物理形态在某种程度上取决于干燥或焙烧的温度。

The physical form of the product is dependent to a degree on the drying /calcination temperature.

传统计算机中，1比特由一个其状态编码不是1就是0的电路表示，该电路不存在任何中间值。

In a conventional computer, a bit is represented by a circuit whose state encodes either a 0 or a 1—there is no in-between.

量子计算机的超强能力源于这个事实：如果你有一组量子比特组合，称为一个量子簇，其中每个量子比特都处于一种不确定状态，那么该量子簇便可同时表示其所有可能的数。

The amazing power of the quantum computer stems from the fact that is you have a collection of qubits—a register—in which each qubit is in an indeterminate state, then the register effectively represents all its possible numbers at once.

我知道他的父亲正在为美国的一所大学全力投身于这项研究工作。

I know his father is dedicating himself to the research work at a university in America.

因此，假设一台录像机被拔掉插头，网络就会尝试寻找另一台录像机，并指令其完成预设的节目录制任务，否则它便会告知用户它无法找到另外的录像机来完成录制。

So if a VCR is unplugged, the network will try to find another VCR on the network and order it to take over the present recording of programmes, or it will tell the user it cannot find a VCR to carry out the taping.

个人电脑可以像其他HAVi设备一样在网络上使用，执行AV功能时，电脑既可用来控制其他设备，亦可为其他设备所控制。

Your PC could also be used like any other HAVi device on the network, controlling other devices and being controlled by them when carrying out AV functions.

假如给计算机提供可靠信息使之开始工作的话，它们便可给出准确结果。

Computers can yield accurate results providing that they are fed with reliable information to start with.

两个十分有害的因素是温室效应和污染：前者使其后恶化，后者则破坏环境。

The two factors that are harmful are greenhouse effect and pollution:this destroys natural environmental and that worsens weather.

在现阶段，通过硬件通用协议和软件通用中介，HAVi（家庭音频/视频公用）功能可将不同的电子消费产品连接起来。

In its present form, HAVi (home audio/visual interoperability) allows you to connect a variety of consumer electronic devices using a common hardware protocol and common software middleware.

当您发现出现故障时，请立即停止操作。

Stop immediately when you recognize a problem exists.

进一步操作可能会导致数据的丢失或损坏。

Further action may result in data loss or damage.

您可能会损坏一些与故障相关的有价值的信息，而这些信息往往可以帮助排除故障。

You may destroy valuable problem-related information that can help solve the problem.

应养成经常保存文件的习惯。

You should also get used to saving your work as often as possible.

个人电脑一般不太稳定，所以进行视频编辑时就须加倍小心。

PCs in general are not the most stable, and with video editing you have to be extra careful.

当今世界现存的个人电脑估计有1.5亿台，而手表却又超过10亿块之多。

While there are an estimated 150m PCs in the world today, there are more than one billion watches.

这种普及的状况说明，手表可能是未来便携式通讯的至关重要的平台。

This ubiquity could mark them as the key platform for future portable communications.

这样一来，每一种元素的原子的外层都具有两个易于失去的电子。

Each has, then, two electrons in the outer shell which it can readily lose.

这些公司在互联网上都有自己的网站。

The companies have their web sites on the internet.

“World 2000” 通过最新的通讯方式和协作途径增强了自身共享信息的能力。

World 2000 has improved its ability to share information through the latest communication and new avenues for collaboration.

这种纯平面屏幕技术可以消除屏幕表面的弯曲，从而达到高水平的聚焦效果，甚至令应用各种绘图软件的专业人士感到满意。

This flat screen technology eliminates curvature on the screen surface and so it achieves a high level of focus to please even professional users using graphic intensive applications.

它只是在屏幕的边、角处有极小的闪烁和变形。

It has only minimal glare and distortion on edges and corners.

而且，这种技术把单枪三色技术与纯平面技术结合起来，实现了真实、精确、清晰的效果。

Furthermore it combines “Trintron” technology with an absolute flat screen for realistic, precise and crystal-clear images.

该结构式是从右写到左，还是从左写到右，或者各种原子以什么角度相互连接，是无关紧要的。

It is immaterial whether the formula be written from right to left, or left to right, or at what angle the various atoms are connected.

在分时系统，重要的是每隔一段时间便可分享使用中央处理器。

In a time-sharing system, it is very important for each user to get a share of the CPU at regular intervals.

人们认为镭的射线可以用来治疗各种疾病。

It has been thought that radium radiations might be useful in curing various diseases.

业已证明，感应电压使电流的方向与产生电流的磁场力方向相反。

It has been proved that induced voltage causes a current to flow in opposition to the force producing it.

它也使人们更容易参与其开发过程，也就是说，一个人即使不是专业编程人员，也可通过向开发小组提出改进建议而对某一软件施加极大的影响。

It also makes it easier for people to get involved in the development process, which means that even if some one is not a programme, he can have a great impact on a piece of software by suggesting how to improve it to the development team.

约12立方厘米的蒸汽是1立方厘米的水加热后产生的。

It is about twelve cubic centimeters of steam that one cubic centimeter of water produces when heated.

当时我们所满意的是他们的优良服务。

It was their good service that I was satisfied with.

决定猞猁繁衍旺盛与否的是猞猁栖息地的承受量而不是猞猁的胃部容量。

It is the carrying capacity of the lynx’s habit, not the carrying capacity of the lynx’s stomach that determines the prosperity of lynxes.

正是因为另一个星系距离我们数十亿千米，所以光从那个星系到达我们这里需要200万年左右的时间。

It is because the other galaxy is thousands of millions of kilometers from us that light from it reaches us after about 2 million years.

看来这两个科学分支是相互依存、相互作用的。

It seems that these two branches of science are mutually dependent and interacting.

这意味着所有的专业编程人员和用户不仅有权修改它，而且也可以访问源代码。

This means that all programmes and users can have access to the source code as well as the right to modify it.

这是一篇综述，是与氧化反应、还原反应以及在酸碱中和时引起配位状态变化的那些反应的用途有关系的。

This is a review of the use of oxidation and reduction reactions and those involving changes in co-ordination states in neutralization between acids and bases.

电学上最常用的两个单位是安培和伏特：前者是电流单位，后者是电压单位。

The two units used most frequently in electricity are ampere and volt:this is the unit of voltage and that of current flow.

这个工作借助于我们的新技术就能很容易做到/完成。

Such can be easily done with the aid of our new technology.

另一种方法可以说是具有同样的效果。

The same can be said of the other method.

次氯酸盐和次氯酸都是优良的漂白剂，并在工业上作为漂白剂加以使用。

The hypochlorite and hypochlorous acid are both excellent bleaching agents and are used as such in the industries.

此闭路系统能保护操作工，使之不与液体接触，免受液体伤害。

The closed loop system protects the operator from liquid contact and hazard from the same.

有些原子核会自发裂变，而另外一些则不会。

Some atomic nuclei undergo spontaneous disintegration while others do not.

常数K值不随某些因数而变。

The value of constant K does not change with some of the factors.

所有物质都有不同的热容量，而水的热容量在所有物质中最大。

All substances have different heat capacities, but water has one of the greatest of all.

这种铁水罐的形状有点像鱼雷。

The iron ladle was shaped something like a torpedo.

你的文件、日程表、通讯录以及你所需要的任何资料都会自动地复制到这些设备中，因为你所能想到的任何东西都能通连。

Your files, schedule, address book, and everything else you need will automatically be replicated onto each of these devices, because everything that you can think of will link.

强度和韧性都比通过常规热处理获得的高得多。

Both strength and toughness were considerably improved over that obtained by conventional heat treatment.

由于当代文化对电视的关注，视频作为一种艺术形式十分引人注目。

Video as an art form is something that catches the eye because of our culture’s absorption with television.

这钢的质量似乎不像上个月炼的钢那样好。

The steel doesn’t seem as god in quality as that made last month.

当前桥的速度大于后桥时，前轮的马达就把液压油泵向后轮上的马达。

The motors on the front wheels pump fluid to the rear-wheel motors when the speed of the front axle exceeds that of the rear.

我们的新产品的市场竞争力将会大大强于那些过时产品。

The competitiveness of our new products in the markets will be much stronger than that of those out-of-date ones.

管理工厂的工人通常比管理工厂的设备更难。

The management of the workers of a factory is usually more difficult than that of its equipment.

他们厂里的设备似乎要比我们公司的设备更先进。

The equipment in their factory seems more advanced than that in our company.

当执行SWI程序指令时，CPU所要完成的中断过程与普通硬件中断所激发的过程相似，并且该程序会转移到中断服务程序。

When SWI is executed, the CPU goes through a similar interrupt sequence to that initiated by a normal hardware interrupt, and the program branches to an interrupt service routine.Conductors of electricity are of two kinds:

导电体可分为两类：（1）传导电流而无须通过化学变化、只被电流加热的，例如金属和石墨就属于这类金属导体；（2）为电流所分解而成为电解质的，如酸化水、盐溶液。

(1) those which conduct the current without undergoing chemical change, and are simply heated by the current; metals and graphite belong to this class of metallic conductors; (2) those which are decomposed by the current, such as acidulated water, and solutions of salts, called electrolysis.

这些机器在功能和效率上都要大大超过去年进口的机器。

These machines are far more powerful and efficient than those imported last year.

由于离子只出现在二电极上，最简单的方法是假设它们带有原子或根，离子的电荷符号与它被引向的电极的电荷符号相反。

Since the ions appear only at the electrodes it is simplest to assume that they are charged atoms or radicals, the sign of the charge of an ion being opposite to that of the electrode towards which it moves by attraction.

这条指令的作用与子程序的返回指令相同，它把主程序的状态恢复到CPU中去，以便继续执行主程序。

This has an action similar to that of the return instruction of a subroutine, and causes the main program status to be restored to the CPU so that the main program continues execution.

这种期刊的封面通常要比普通书籍的封面更加五彩缤纷。

The cover of the pictorial is usually more colorful than that of the ordinary book.

互联技术的应用范围将从局部的光纤回路到卫星连接，提供了超过当今直接存储器存取通道的宽带。

Interconnect technology will range from local, fiber optics loops to satellite links providing bandwidths exceeding those of today’s direct memory access channels.

麦制糕点的成本要低于米制糕点。

A cake made of wheat costs less than one made of rice.

这是具有极端重要性的职务。

The position is one of vital importance.

而且，在多微机或多小型机环境中，为用户提供服务的复杂系统中部件的数量大于单台计算机系统部件的数量，甚至比具有大量使用更基础器件或部件的系统的部件的数量还要大。

Also, in a multimicro-or minicomputer environment, the number of complex system components involved in providing user service is larger than for a single computer system, even one having a large number of more elementary devices or components.

只有一个能中断微机正常工作的装置的系统，是很简单的系统；该特定中断往往很容易得到服务。

A system with only one device which can interrupt the normal work of the microcomputer is a very simple one and the particular interrupt can be readily serviced.

这本书是每一位学英语的学生都需要的。

This book is such a one as is needed by every student of English.

这机会太好了，不能错过。

The chance was too good a one to let pass.

这台装置显然要比那台装置更有效率。

This device is obviously more efficient than that one.

在这六种工序中，最基本的两道工序是澄清和过滤。

Of the half dozen processes, the two most basic ones are clarification and filtration.

这座新电站耗费的建设成本比早先建造的那座电站减少了80%。

The new power station cost 80% less than the one built earlier.

光速每秒186 300英里。

Light travels 186,300 miles in a second.

A4型打印纸大小为297×210毫米。

A4 paper is 297×210mm.

纽约至洛杉矶走公路距离为22 915英里。

New York is 22,915 miles from Los Angeles by road.

当由阿留申群岛地震引起的波浪到达夏威夷群岛时，这些波浪在几处地方形成了高达6米的快速移动的水墙冲上海岸。

As the waves from the Aleutian earthquake hit the Hawaiian Islands, they were driven ashore in a few places as a rapidly moving wall of water up to 6 meters high.

该报道称，外资企业出口了价值6.65亿美元的商品，比1994年上升了33%。

Foreign-funded enterprises exported $665,000,000 worth of goods, up 33% over 1994, the report said.

在进行这种处理后，在1983年6月第三周把棉花种子用手种上，行距为75厘米，每块地种三行。

Following the treatment, cotton seeds were planted by hand in the third week of June 1983, at 75-cm row spacing with three rows of plants per plot.

毛发的长度在0%～100%的相对湿度范围内发生约2.5%左右的变化。

The length of hair changes by about 2.5% between 0% and 100% relative humidity.

所分析的地面低压中心位于中气旋之东约8千米处。

The analyzed low-pressure center at the surface was located some 8 km east of the mesocyclone.

虽然地球离太阳约为93 000 000英里，截获的能量不到太阳总辐射能量的二十亿分之一，但这一小部分能量总计起来却始终达到23万亿马力。

Although the earth, approximately 93, 000, 000 miles distant, intercepts less than 1/2,000,000,000 part of the solar output, this fraction amounts continuously to 23, 000, 000, 000, 000 horsepower.

中国是世界上最大的国家之一，拥有960多万平方千米的国土面积。

China is one of the largest countries in the world with a territory of more than 9,600,000 square kilometers.

地球完成一次自传需要23小时56分钟4秒多。

It takes 23 hours, 56 minutes and 4 and a fraction of a second for the earth to complete one rotation.

去年中国的汽车产量增加了30万辆。

The production of cars in China went up 300 thousand last year.

米尔建立的模型预测，在下个世纪，即使温室气体保持在2000年的水平，单单热膨胀就足以使海平面上升约11厘米。

Meehl’s models predict that thermal expansion alone would make sea levels rise by about by about 11 centimeters over the next century.

中国出口到美国的商品总值比去年上升了三分之二。

The total value of China's exports to the US rose by two thirds last year.

与去年同期相比，国家第一季度的总采购量提高了5.2 个百分点。

The total volume of state purchase in the first quarter has been raised by 5.2 percent, compared with the same period of last year.

计算机模拟表明，在多烟雾的夏季，下午交通高峰期间每一辆汽车上的PremAir 会降低臭氧量十亿分之六至十亿分之八。

Computer models suggest that at rush hour on a smoggy summer afternoon, PremAir on every car could lower ozone levels by six to eight parts per billion.

钢产量比去年增加了450万吨。

There is an increase of 4.5 million tons of steel as compared with last year.

型焦阶段的总碳比减少3%，是由于型焦中氢含量较高，约为基准界段焦炭含氢量的三倍。

The decrease of 3% in the gross carbon rate during the formed coke period was attributable to the relatively high hydrogen content of the formed material, being about three times as great as that of the base period coke.

这种新款手机拥有的功能比其旧型号多出了五种。

The new type of mobile phone has five more functions than its old model.

这所大学2004年的科研经费预算比北京大学低了2000万元。

The budget for research work expenditure of the university in 2004 is 20 million yuan lower than that of Beijing University.

去年欧洲汽车的产量比1996年下降了24%。

The output of cars in Europe last year was 24 per cent less than in 1996.

新的天线系统采用了延迟波原理，使天线高度降低到40%。

The new antenna system uses a retarded wave principle that cuts antenna height to 40%.

这家钢厂的年钢产量已增加到1000万吨。

The output of steel has increased to 10 million tons annually in this steel works.

各种MP3播放机的产量比2005年增加了三倍。

The production of various MP3 players has been multiplied four times as against 2005.

到1980年，用浸出法生产的原铜产量预料会增长四倍。

By 1980 the production of primary copper by leaching would be expected to increased fivefold.

这些复合材料的弹性模数比单纯基体材料增大了一倍，而抗拉强度则增大了四倍。

The composites showed a two-fold increase in modulus of elasticity and a five-fold increase in tensile strength over that of the plain matrix.

1974年中国的煤产量比1949年增加了9倍。

In 1974, there was a ten times increase of China’s coal output as compared with 1949.

如果两个不同电荷之间的距离缩短一半，则它们之间的吸引力的强度增加到原来的2×2=4倍。

The strength of the attraction between two unlike charges increases by 2×2=4times if the distance between the original charges is halved.

这家公司将其数控机床的产量增加了两倍，由两万台增加到六万台。

The corporation has increased its production of the digital machine tools by two times, from previous 200,000 to present 600,000.

该速度超过平均速度2.2倍。

The speed exceeded the average speed by a factor of 3.2.

这种舰船的体积相当于Ticonderoga级巡洋舰的4倍，舰身长825英尺，可携带512个导弹发射筒。

This ship would be four times the size of a Ticonderoga-class cruiser and would carry 512 missile launch tubes in its 825-foot-long hull.

各排积云的云间间距通常是其自身高度的大约两倍。

Often the distance between the rows is about twice their height.

这些炸弹中的每一枚，其破坏威力都相当于当年投放在广岛的那枚炸弹的十倍。

Each of these bombs has ten times the destructive power of the bomb that was used on Hiroshima.

这个女婴的体重一年中增加了一倍。

The baby girl doubled its weight in a year.

牲畜的数量今年增加了三倍。

The number of livestock has quadrupled this year.

操作费用减少了三分之二。

The operation cost decreased three times.

与双滤波器相干检波相比的主要优点是其宽带减少了五分之四。

The principal advantage over the dual filter coherent detection is a five-fold reduction in bandwidth.

图2的数据表明，各最大值中间最大的和最小的几乎成三与一之比。

The data in Fig.3 show a nearly three times difference in the highest values.

这条新设计的自动装配线能够缩短装配期十分之九。

This newly-designed automatic assembly line can shorten the assembling period by ten times.

正在研制的设备很有可能会使误差概率减少到七分之一。

The equipment under development is more likely to reduce the error probability by a factor of 7.

密歇根大学的化学家拉乌尔发明了一种只有一根头发丝的千分之一粗细的光纤探针。

Raoul Kopelman, a chemist at the University of Michigan, has invented a fiber-optic probe that is just one-thousandth the width of a human hair.

由于这种天然气发电机不间断地燃烧，所以一氧化碳和碳氢化合物的排放量只相当于使用内燃发动机车辆的五十分之一。

Because the natural-gas generator burns fuel continuously, carbon monoxide and hydrocarbon emissions would be one-fiftieth those of vehicles with internal-combustion engines.

这个热电站比那个热电站大三倍。

This thermal power plant is four times larger than that one.

一公斤铀所能产生的热能相当于燃烧一公斤煤所能产生的热能的近三百万倍。

One kilogram of uranium gives nearly three million times as much heat as can be obtained by burning an equivalent amount of coal.

待冷却气体的总热函也会减小到原来的五分之一到四分之一。

The total enthalpy of the gas to be cooled would be three to four times smaller.

这种薄膜的厚度只及普通纸的三分之一。

This kind of film is twice thinner than ordinary paper.

这种金属比那种金属轻三分之二。

This metal is three times as light as that one.

汽车将采用陶瓷发动机，重量仅为钢制发动机的一半。

The cars will be driven by the ceramic engine twice as light as that of their steel counterparts.

在电子扫描时，波束宽度展宽一倍。

In case of electronic scanning the beamwidth is broader by a factor of two.

总之，在免耕地条件下，春季作物对土壤含氮量的反应大约是常规耕作的两倍。

In summary, under zero till crop response to nitrogen levels in the spring was approximately twice as large compared to conventional till.

声音在水中的传播速度几乎是在空气中传播速度的五倍。

In water sound travels nearly five times as fast as in air.

这大约是其实际约2.5万英里周长的七分之二。

This is about two and one-half times less than the actual circumference of about 25,000 miles.

人们发现，从播撒过的单体云中降落到地面的雨量，是从未经播撒云中降落下来的三倍。

It was found that three times as much rain fell to the ground from seeded single clouds as from unseeded clouds.

通过海底电缆以相当于当今通讯电缆四倍的速度传送信息，这家美国最大的电信公司超越了它的所有竞争对手，保持了它在信息高速公路上的领先地位。

The US’s largest telecommunications company has overtaken its rivals in the battle to keep ahead on the information superhighway by sending data down a sub-sea fiber optic cable four times faster than is usual on today’s commercial cables.

他对这一天气事件的预报是完全成功的。

His forecast of the event is found entirely successful.

根据《科学》杂志最近的报导，诺查丹玛大学的研究人员正在开发一种电路设计方法，它只需微量的初始电荷便可传输信息。

As reported recently in Science, researchers at the University of Notre Dame are working on a method of building circuits that need only a tiny initial electrical charge to transfer information.

但是，随着CPU、随机存取存储器、特别是硬驱成本的降低，在家用电脑上制作高品质视频的梦想终于成为现实。

But, finally, the lower costs of CPUs, RAM, and especially hard drives, have made the dream of good quality video on the home PC a reality.

为了有效、安全而无烟地操作，二次空气的分布、数量、温度和速度必须足以确保适当的混合和温度。

For efficient, safe and smoke-free operation, the distribution, quantity, temperature and velocity of the secondary air must be adequate to insure proper mixing and temperature.

用电解法生产氢的效率不像热化学法那样高。

The electrolytic process for producing hydrogen is not so efficient as the thermochemical process.

淋巴，一种乳白色的流体，把人体各组织内的杂质和代谢废物带走，并穿越腺状结构；后者遍布在全身的淋巴系统内，起着过滤阀的作用。

A milky white fluid called lymph carries impurities and waste away from the tissues and passes through gland-like structures spaced throughout the lymphatic system that act as filtering valves.

钛是一种轻量、坚固而耐蚀的金属。

Titanium is a light, strong and corrosion-resistant metal.

自动数字程序控制

programmed digital automatic control

最大理论密度

theoretical maximum density

低黏度润滑剂也表明其黏度对温度的依赖性不大。

Lubricants of low viscosity also exhibit a low temperature dependence of viscosity.

不导电的橡胶、陶瓷和玻璃通常用来隔绝电流。

Non-conducting rubber, porcelain and glass are commonly used to resist electric current.

便携式电器—例如电炉、电熨斗、或电热水器的布线，需要特别小心。

The wiring of portable appliances, such as electric fires, irons, or kettles, needs particular care.

这种技术可用于开发体积微小、功能强大，依靠极少的电能就可以长时间工作的计算机。

This could result in the development of tiny, powerful computers that run for extended periods of time on little power.

热能在辐射时，会转换成性质与光相似的辐射能。

In radiation, thermal energy is transformed into radiant energy, similar in nature to light.

铝可以轧制成薄到几乎透明的箔片。

Aluminum may be rolled into foils so thin that they are almost transparent.

你多半会随身携带某种出入卡，电子的或别的什么的。

You probably carry some kind of access card, electric or otherwise, that allows you in and out of your place of work.

1997年，Rezulin（一种糖尿病治疗药物）获首次认可，各方官员及医务人员视其为“神奇炸弹”，其重要性足以使它能在美国食品与药物管理局新近制定的“快速治愈”条例下获得批准。

When initially approved in 1997, Rezulin was viewed by officials and physicians alike as a blockbuster drug important enough to be approved under the FDA’s newly instituted “fast-track” protocol.

进行桌面视频编辑时，要确保关闭所有与计算机运行无关的程序。

When you’re working with your desktop video, make sure that you have disabled any programs that aren’t essential to the operation of your computer.

大多数家用电脑用户均可进行基于计算机的非线性视频编辑，而且编辑出的效果有时会让周围的人吃惊。

Non-linear computer-based video editing is now feasible for most home computer users, and the results it produces can sometimes astonish those around you.

这些马达功率大而且结构紧凑，但经过短时间试用发现，其噪音也相当大，这是液压传动系统过去一直普遍存在的问题。

The motors are both powerful and compact, but a short test drive reveals that they also are quite noisy, which has been a common problem with hydraulic drive systems in the past.

每一个企业，无论其规模大小，技术含量高低，国有还是私营，都面临着如何在激烈的竞争中继续生存的问题。

Whether large or small, high-tech or low, public or private, every business will be faced with the issue of how to survive in the fierce competition.

更新后的表格工具使绘制和编辑表格比以往更容易。

The updated table tool makes drawing and editing tables easier than before.

植物和动物生活的平衡可保持空气中氧与二氧化碳的含量的恒定。

The balance of plant and animal life keeps the amounts of oxygen and carbon dioxide constant.

家用电脑要有效处理高品质视频所要求的大量数据，唯一途径就是压缩。

The only way a home computer can effectively deal with the huge amounts of data required for good quality video is to compress it.

该系统目前仍减少必要的电子控制装置，特别是用以平稳地控制制动力的装置。

The system still lacks the necessary electronic controls, particularly to control the braking force smoothly.

资本主义从经济方面改造了社会。

Economically, capitalism has transformed societies.

许多人可能会争辩道：与客户之间如此精确水准的沟通交流无论在商业上还是在技术层面上都是不可行的。

Many people may argue that such a precise level of customer communication is not commercially viable or technically feasible.

389VP型传感器安装在带有氟化橡胶圆环的模压Tefzel（r）体内，从而使传感器既可免遭毁坏，又可耐受化学腐蚀。

Model 389VP is housed in a molded Tefzel(r) body with Viton O-rings, making each sensor virtually indestructible and chemically resistant.

之所以能提高传输速度是由于采用了光学的而不是电子学的方法将信号加以放大。

The increased transmission speed was made possible by amplifying the signals optically rather than electronically.

非常遗憾的是，光纤通讯系统在红外区内的工作波长通常都很长，长达1300毫微米，而且发射这种波长的垂直腔激光器很难制造。

Very unfortunately, communications systems usually operate further into the infrared, at 1,300 nanometers, and vertical-cavity lasers that emit at this wavelength are hard to make.

“连通性”这一词进入高科技词汇已有20多年之久，这是十分惊人的。

Amazingly, it has been more than 20 years since the concept of “convergence” entered the high-tech lexicon.

在标准情况下/通常，头脑清醒的司机大约需400毫秒就能做出反应；不过，一旦反应时间拖长到500毫秒左右，就表明司机正在犯困。

Typically, a normally alert driver would take about 400 milliseconds to respond, but once that falls to about 500 milliseconds it suggests that the driver is getting sleepy.

一般说来，做兼职工作的人从事的都是地位低下、工资微薄的职业。

Generally, the part-timers work in low-status, low-wage occupations.

简而言之，这些物质可以用分析方法加以鉴定。

Briefly, these substances can be identified analytically.

大多数计算机使用者从未接受过正规的键盘技能训练。

Most computer users have never received any formal keyboard training.

因而他们的键盘技术达不到要求。

Consequently, their keyboard skills are inefficient.

相反，若别的什么人使用你的浏览器，它也不会有什么差异。

Conversely, if someone else were to use your browser, it couldn’t tell the difference.

然而，这种发动机可能很快就可以经济合算地用于房车和船上。

The generator could soon be cost-effective enough to be used in motor homes, and boats, however.

看来，某些洋区（如南印度洋）很少产生远高于13米的波浪。

It appears that some ocean regions (e.g. the southern Indian Ocean) rarely produce waves much higher than 13 times.

显然，润滑好的轴承，比未作润滑的轴承更容易转动。

It is evident that a well lubricated bearing turns more easily than a dry one.

异常温暖的海水所在海域可沿赤道向西长距离延伸，至少可远及坎顿岛。

The anomalously warm water can exist for a long distance along the equator at least as far west as Canton Island.

水面的空气越接近饱和，水面上水的净损失速率就越缓慢。

The nearer the air above the water approaches saturation, the less rapid will be the net loss from water.

电磁波的传播速度和光速相同。

Electromagnetic waves travel at the same speed as light.

垂直面发射型的激光器对于某些用途尤其具有吸引力，因为它们的光束比边缘发射型激光器的光束更为对称，聚焦也好。

These surface-emitting lasers are particularly attractive for some applications because their beams are more symmetrical and more tightly focused than those from edge-emitting lasers.

与氢相比较，氧的重量大约是它的十六倍。

Compared with hydrogen, oxygen is nearly 16 times as heavy.

加拿大研究人员提出报告说，事实上，一套普通公寓尽管外墙少于普通住房，但其所耗能量与面积相似的单户人家住房所耗能量相等。

In fact, Canadian researchers report that an average apartment uses as much energy as a comparable-size single-family house, even though the apartment has fewer walls exposed to the outside.

KH4系列是最先送入轨道拍摄立体照片的照相机，这种立体照片比单个相机拍得图像所蕴含的有用信息要多得多。

The KH-4s were the first orbiting cameras to take stereoscopic photos, which contain far more useful information than single-camera images.

电磁波以广播传播。

Electromagnetic waves travel at the same speed as light.

那辆新型小汽车一直在以最高车速飞驰，因而现在也不可能跑得更快了。

The new type of car would run faster, if it could run faster than it has been running at its highest speed all the time.

月亮从赤道以北28.5°的位置运行到赤道南28.5°的位置。

The moon moves from a position 28.5°north of the equator to as much south of it.

它越快达到这个温度，它就越早开始最有效地运行。

The quicker it reaches that temperature the sooner it begins operating at its most efficient.

电解槽废气可用苛性溶液加以清洗。

The cell offgases may be scrubbed with caustic solution.

这时氯和氢氧化物起反应，产生次氯酸盐离子和氯离子。

The chlorine then reacts with the caustic to produce hypochloride ions and chloride ion.

这种仪器很贵，使其应用受到了限制。

The expense of such an instrument has discouraged its use.

这种车上配置了热能转换器来取代普通汽车上的散热器；而研究人员必须要解决的一个难题是，如何防止热能转换器结霜。

One problem the researchers had to overcome was how to keep the heat exchanger, which resembles a car radiator, from frosting up.

计算机能排定整套设备的操作时间表。

The computer schedules the operations of the whole plant.

此余隙可将形成“桥凝”的可能性减少到最低限度。

This clearance minimizes the possibility of “bridging".

细粒氧化钍弥散体不仅由于奥洛万机理、而且由于亚结构能在较高温度下保持稳定而使钨得到强化。

A fine thria dispersion strengthens tungsten not only by the Orowan mechanism but also by stabilization of the substructure to higher temperature.

它们在拉伸矫正机上对薄钢板进行矫直和应力消除。

They strengthen and stress-relieve the steel sheets on the stretching machine.

东芝公司设计的Tecra780型电脑经久耐用。

Toshiba designed the computer Tecra 780 for durability.

液氮汽车的动力来自液氮温度在外部空气的作用下升高，超过其零下320华氏度的沸点而气化时向外界释放的压力。

The vehicle is driven by pressure released when cold liquid nitrogen is heated past its -320°F boiling point by outside air and becomes a gas.

也可使两台以上的计算机一同运行，以改善其性能或提高系统的可靠性。

Two or more computers can also be operated together so that they can improve performance or system reliability.

首先，应当选择能延长刀具寿命和获得良好表面光洁度的机械加工条件。

First, machining condition should be selected which will give long tool life and good surface finish.

这只二极管的辐射功率约为那只的九倍。

This diode produces about nine times more radiant power than that one.

噪声控制工程师现在可以使用的升学设备和振动测量设备种类繁多，令人眼花缭乱。

There is a bewildering variety of acoustics and vibration measurement equipment now available to the noise control engineer.

这种新型的机器人能为人类干很多家务活，它们甚至能像人一样灵巧地扫地、擦洗地板。

This new type of robot can do a lot of housework for humans-they even can sweep and scrub as skillfully as humans.

如果地轴不倾斜，地球上就不会有季节变化。

If the earth’s axis did not tilt, there would be no seasonal change on it.

假如你能把铜原子一个挨一个地排列起来的话，也许要一亿个才能排满一英寸的长度。

If you could make a row of copper atoms by placing one next to the other, you might need 100 million to cover an inch.

如果当时不采取必要预防措施，这场台风就会造成更加严重的损害。

If we had not taken necessary precautions, the typhoon would have inflicted more serious damage.

而且汽车散热器部分地受到防护罩保护，使之免受这类气候要素的影响；假如将催化剂涂料涂敷在较为暴露的部位，如保险杠上，那么这些涂料就可能受到风雨的侵蚀。

And the radiator is partially shielded from the elements, which might damage the catalyst were it more exposed, such as on a bumper.

要是没有这些颠扑不破的定律，物理学就肯定不可能在任何漫长的岁月里作为一门精确的科学而存在。

Were there no such superior laws, physics would surely be impossible as an exact science over any sufficiently long period.

假如电流切断，线圈就会返回到原来位置。

Should the current be cut, the coil would return to its original position.

假如当时富兰克林关于闪电的知识与我们今天的认识一样，他可能就不会进行那种危险的风筝试验了。

Had Franklin known what we know about lightning in those days, he probably would not have undertaken such a dangerous experiment.

要不是由于他们共同的努力，他们本来是不可能在他们的科研工作中取得这样大的成就的。

But for their common effort, they could not have made such a great achievement in their scientific research.

这种手表可以让使用者进入计算机系统并编辑数据资料，在屏幕上选择信息之后，间隔6～12英寸将表盘对着监视器就可将信息下载到手表内。

The wristwatch will allow users to enter and edit data on their PC and select information on the screen to download into the watch by holding its face 6 to 12 inches from the monitor.

人们希望温度的时间序列尽可能地长，以便能研究各种波的振荡周期。

The times series of temperature are expected to be the longest possible so as to examine various modes of oscillation periods.

有些空气微粒，特别是较轻气体的原子，运动足够快，以致能从空气海洋中逃逸出来。

Some of the air particles, particularly the atoms of the lighter gases, travel fast enough to escape from the air ocean.

当信号作用到IRQ（中断请求）引脚时，便时处理器进入一系列的中断操作。

When a signal is applied to IRQ, this causes the processor to go into an interrupt sequence of operations.

这使得CPU能够跳出主程序并转入中断服务程序,该程序或许会向打印机输出数据。

This enables CPU to jump out of the main program and go to an interrupt service routine, which perhaps outputs data to a printer.

早春季节气温太低，不利于这些植物的生长发育，因此它们还必须留在温室中。

In early spring temperature is too slow to favor the growth and development of the plants so that they have to remain in the greenhouse.

下大力气解决仍在困扰着肥料生产的经济问题和技术问题的时机已经到来。

The time has come to make great efforts to solve economic and technical problems still besetting fertilizer production.

不用电缆或任何形式的连接，个人计算机竟能通过监视器传送信息。

People find it hard to believe that there are no cables or connections of any kind and that a PC can transmit data through the monitor.

尽管现在谈论这门强大的新型科技的出现最终将会产生何种影响可能还为时过早，但人们对于纳米技术及其影响所具有的兴趣却有增无减，因而对之倍加关注。

While it may be too early to tell the ultimate impact of the emergence of the new and powerful technology, nanotechnology has clearly raised the interest and greater attention on both the technology and its consequences.

对这一加热不平衡的动力学响应结果导致热在这沙漠地带的对流层上部汇聚。

The dynamic response to the heating imbalance is such as to converge heat into the upper troposphere of the desert regions.

结构材料的选择应使其在外界条件中保持其弹性。

Materials to be used for structural purposes are chosen so as to behave elastically in the environmental conditions.

为了确保反应进行得相当快，要求在少量液相和多得多的固相之间有最密切的接触。

To ensure that the reaction progresses reasonably fast involves the closest contact between the small amount of liquid phase and the much larger bulk of solid phase.

按照英国铜业发展协会（CDA）的意思，铜合金的压力模铸费用迄今一直是高于铝和锌的，而在采用这项新技术后预期会降低25%。

Up to now, copper alloys, according to CDA, have been more expensive to pressure diecast than aluminum and zinc, and a 25% reduction in the cost of pressure diecasting of copper alloys is expected with the new technique.

静电发生器由两片将会逆向转动的玻璃组成。

An electrostatic generator consists of two glass plates which are to revolve in opposite directions.

上述操作规程必须严格遵守。

The operating instructions mentioned above are to be strictly observed.

这种照相机胶卷不可在阳光下曝光。

The photographic film is not to be exposed to the sunlight.

为了最大限度地利用热，有必要弄懂支配热传输的几条定律。

In order to utilize heat to the best advantage, it is necessary to know the laws that govern heat transfer.

例如，糖尿病患者可以用这种小得令他们感觉不到的光纤探针来检测自己的血糖水平。

Diabetics, for example, could measure their blood-sugar levels with a fiber-optic “needle” that would be far too small for them to feel.

聚合物链间有更多的横耦合链形成，从而使它更难被电子穿透。

More cross-links are formed between the polymer chains, making it more difficult for electrons to penetrate.

在通讯系统中，电子学要解决的问题是如何把信息从一个地方传递到另一个地方。

In communications, the problem of electrons is how to convey information from one place to another.

编程语言是以人为本的语言，用来指令计算机做什么以及怎样做。

Programming language is a human-oriented language used to tell a computer what to do and how to do.

如果有关如何激励员工的培训能有效地实施，它就能导致某些显著的改进，这正是公司的目标的一部分。

If the training on how to motivate employees is effectively done, it should lead to measurable improvements, part of company goal.

西斯科公司的理念是听取客户的要求，考察所有技术方案，向客户提供广泛的选择范围。

Cisco’s philosophy is to listen to customer requests, monitor all technological alternatives, and provide customers with a range of options from which to choose.

专家们必须要计算出卫星围绕月球运转的速度。

The experts had to calculate at which speed for the satellite to travel around the moon.

因为没有一台机器可以无摩擦地运转，所以克服摩擦力只是白费功夫。

As no machine ever runs without some friction, overcoming the force wastes work.

常用培土或覆盖其他材料的方法来遮护这些植株幼苗以防止其大量死亡。

Shading by heaping soil or other materials over the young plant is often practiced to prevent major losses.

物质的冷却会导致其分子运动减慢。

Cooling matter causes the molecule to move more slowly.

调整压力是没有用的，除非更换损坏了的零件。

It is no use adjusting the pressure unless the damaged parts are replaced.

天文学家并不认为在其他行星上寻找生命的证据是浪费时间。

Astronomers do not deem it a waste of time searching for life evidence on other planets.

利用海水发电的可能性已经变为现实。

The possibility of sea water being used to generate electricity has come true.

这一新生技术涉及的结构制作，部分时间控制在纳米层面，而大多数时间则控制在原子层面。

This emerging technology involves structure elaboration with a control at nanometer level and most of the time at the atomic level.

透镜可以是发散透镜或会聚透镜。

Lenses are either diverging or converging.

在所有这些反应中，我们都是用金属取代酸中的氢，从而生成了盐。

In all such reactions we have the hydrogen in the acid replaced by the metal to form a salt.

基于零件数目和能源消耗的估计，分子大小的构件可以使将来的台式电脑功能远比现存所有的电脑功能的总和还要强大。

Based on estimates of parts count and power dissipation, components of molecular size could make desk-top computers of the future more powerful than computers in existence today combined.

分子设计在进军纳米技术的征程中所取得的进步，很可能使这一趋势得以继续或加强，最终达到延年益寿的目的。

Progress in molecular design on the path to nanotechnology is likely to continue and strengthen this trend, eventually allowing the retention of good health for a prolonged period.

有机酸的稀水溶液会使蓝色石蕊试纸变红，受金属的作用时会放出氢，且会被金属的氢氧化物中和而生成盐类。

Dilute water solutions of organic acids color blue litmus red, evolve hydrogen when acted on by metals, and are neutralized by metallic hydroxides forming salts.

洗涤以后的气流进入吸附反应器，在里面从下向上流动。

After washing, the gas stream enters the adsorption reactors flowing from bottom to top.

在所有金属中，银是最好的导体，其次是铜和铝。

Of all metals, silver is the best conductor, followed by copper and aluminum.

由于光传递得很快，它从太阳到达地球只需要八分钟多一点。

Traveling very fast, light from the sun takes a little more than eight minutes to reach the earth.

燃料如果被燃烧，就放出热。

Burned, fuels give off heat.

朝向不同的山坡收到的直接太阳辐射量是不同的。

Slopes oriented differently receive direct solar radiation in different amounts.

1卡路里定义为在一个大气压力条件下使1克水温度增加1℃（通常指从14.5℃提高到15.5℃）所需要的热量。

A calorie is defined as the quantity of heat required at one atmosphere to raise the temperature of 1 gram of water through 1℃, usually from 14.5 ℃ to 15.5℃.

从对流单体降落的冷凝物的水平宽度比观测到的中尺度下沉气流的宽度小得多（前者60千米而后者150千米）。

The horizontal width of the condensate falling from the convective cells was much less than the width of the observed mesoscale downdraft (60km compared to 150km).

尽管如此，该展示在探索未来汽车燃料的高效率方面，为现在正处于研发阶段的电驱动系统提供了引人关注的选择。

Still, the demonstration offers an interesting alternating to the electric drive system being explored in the quest for high fuel efficiency in future vehicles.

1瓦的功率可以让1安培的电流在电压为1伏的回路中流动。

A current of one ampere will be kept flowing in a circuit by a watt of power under a pressure of one volt.

从气流中分离其中所含酸性气体的方法，是使该气流与吸收酸的固体微粒接触，即让它同预先经过水处理并干燥了的霞石正常岩相接触。

An acid gas component is separated from a stream of gas, through contact with acid absorbing solid particles, by contacting it with previously water-treated and dried nepheline-syenite.

这些台站可以每隔1小时或不到1小时报告1此天气以警告人们危险天气的临近。

These stations may report weather at intervals of an hour or even less to warn of approaching weather dangers.

由于电阻很大，电路中通过的电流很小。

The resistance being very high, the current in the circuit was low.

振动着的物体产生声波，每一次振动产生一个声波。

Vibrating objects produce sound waves, each vibration producing one sound wave.

在其他条件相同时，海水的蒸发比淡水蒸发小大约5%。

Evaporation from sea water is about 5% less than from fresh water, other conditions being the same.

若多个装置连接至给定的中断线，而每个装置均有自己的中断服务程序。

When a number of devices are attached to a given interrupt line, each with its own servicing routine, then the peripheral responsible for the interrupt has to be identified.

芯片上具有成千上万个相同的电路，每个电路能存储一个二进制位。

Chips have thousands of identical circuits, each one capable of storing one bit.

这儿是头两项检测的结果，第三项体检结果将在下周出来。

Here are the results of first two medical examinations, the third (being) to come out next week.

若物体受到每个恒力的作用，则该物体就会做等加速运动。

The body with a constant force acting on it moves at constant acceleration.

不过，由于肥胖症与心脏病以及其他严重疾病也有关联，与肥胖作斗争已成为生死攸关的问题。

But with obesity also linked to heart disease and other serious ailments, fighting fat has become a matter of life or death.

一种物体即使无法看见其内部的运动也有可能是热的。

An object may be hot without the motion in it being visible.

这种电缆在芯线外面包着两层绝缘材料。

In this cable there is two-layer insulation around the core wire.

因此，同线性回归相比，这种对多元回归的需要看来是颇有道理的。

Accordingly, the need for multiple regression as against linear regression appeared quite reasonable.

这种技术具有足够的精密度和准确性，足以应用于动力工业领域。

The technique is of adequate precision and accuracy for use in the power industry.

他们总是保持备用发电机组的完好状态。

They always keep the emergency generating set in order.

这种汽车的专业化部件现在仍处在研发阶段，其设计方案是，它可在气流穿过一个长如车体的圆锥形风“洞”之时获得能量。

With its specialized components now at the development stage, the car is designed to gain power as its airflow passes through a wind cone “hole” which stretches the length of its body.

阵风可以以超过每小时75英里的速度从雷暴中吹出。

Gusty winds may blow out of a thunderstorm at speed in excess of 75 miles an hour.

鉴于该高原对于广大地区的天气和气候的重要性，在数年前曾对之进行过一次科学考察。

In view of the importance of the plateau to the weather and climate over broad areas, a scientific investigation was carried out a few years ago.

物体由于运动而具有的能量叫动能。

The energy possessed by an object by virtue of its motion is called kinetic energy, or energy of motion.

在海平面以上几千尺高度的范围内，气压递减率大约是每900到1000英尺高度下降1英寸汞柱左右。

For the first few thousand feet above sea level the rate of pressure decrease is in the neighborhood of 1 inch of pressure for each 900 to 1000 ft.

这些优先权终端电路借助于可用处理器检查的3位码，就可鉴别高达8级的中断。

These priority interrupt circuits identify up to 8 interrupt levels by means of a 3-bit code which can be inspected by the microprocessor.

多级流床焙烧炉也很有可能将会很好地处理以浓缩矿浆或半干粉末形态给人反应器的某些精矿。

There is also a good possibility that multistage fluid bed roasters would work well on certain concentrates fed to the reactor as a thickened slurry or as a partially dried powder.

失去控制的气压增长是这一爆炸的根本原因。

The pressure increase out of control was at the bottom of the explosion.

这种机器据说能告知生意人他的朋友或客户是否在说谎。

The machines are supposed to tell the businessman, with a small margin of error, whether his friend or client is telling lies.

英吉尔哈特公司的化学家们自然不会愿意谈论这种催化剂的确切成分。

Engelhard chemists are naturally reluctant to discuss the precise chemistry of their catalyst, beyond hinting that it uses platinum or platinum group elements such as palladium.

银是已知的最好的导电体和导热体，并且其展性和延性仅次于金。

Silver is the best conductor of heat and electricity known and is next to gold in malleability and ductility.

这个系统由两个俯视的全景远程照相机组成，相机之间互相倾斜30度。

The system consisted of two downward-looking panoramic telephoto cameras tilted 30 degrees with respect to each other.

矿物初始粒度的减小导致浸出表面积的增大和铜浸出率的相应提高。

Decreasing the initial mineral particle size gives rise to an increase in the surface area for leaching with a corresponding increase in the copper leached.

而后，当光通过开口的一端浸入光纤时，融合的顶端就会发光，其亮度和色彩依据目标化学物质的浓度的不同而变化。

Afterward, when light is pumped through the open end of the fiber, the fused tip glows, its brightness and color varying according to the concentration of the target chemical.

在无云夜间，地面温度由于其热量散失到空间而下降。

In the cloudless night the ground temperature decreases on account of the heat lost to the space.

由于被吸收而引起的强度减弱叫做阻尼，而由于这一原因其强度减小的波叫做阻尼波。

The decrease in intensity due to absorption is called damping and a wave whose intensity decreases for this reason is called a damped wave.

随着机器缓慢升温，绝缘电阻通常会降低。

With the machine warmed up slowly, the insulation resistance will normally be lower.

所得结果仍然是无可争议的，因为用以测量从这些自爆裂原子核中射出的电子及α粒子的特性的物理方法是精确的。

The results are nevertheless beyond dispute, thanks to the accuracy of the physical methods of measuring the characteristics of the electrons and alpha particles shot off from these spontaneously exploding nuclei.

发电机是输入机械能，输出电能；而电动机是输入电能，输出机械能。

In a generator mechanical power is put in and electrical power is taken out, instead of electrical power going in and mechanical power coming out as in a motor.

在模型中，浮冰用一些塑料块来代表，这些塑料块具有与河流中浮冰快大致相同的密度和平均尺寸。

In the model, the floating ice was represented by pieces of plastic material, about the correct density and average size of floating blocks of ice in the river.

由于芯片很小，故而蚀刻在芯片上的电路也很小，这样电信号就无需传送很远，因此它们传输得较快。

Because of the very small size of the chip, and consequently of the circuits etched on it, electrical signals do not have to travel far; hence, they are transmitted faster.

由于在所有卫生保健服务方面在一定程度上较为明显地存在着一系列的问题，因而，作为结构系统对此类问题的响应，疾病管理的出现受到了欢迎。

Disease management is welcomed as a structured systems response to a set of problems that are evident to some degree in all health services.

世界卫生组织的目标是经过各族人民的共同努力达到尽可能高的健康水平。

The objective of WHO is the attainment by all peoples of the highest possible level of health.

于是，阀盒下面的压缩空气就会克服阀弹簧的拉力而打开阀盒。

The compressed air below the valve cage will then open it against the tension of valve spring.

这两项费用节省的优点都必须根据/参照筛式废液分离机所需的额外投资来加以权衡。

Both these cost advantages must be weighted against the additional investment required for the screen effluent splitter.

最近，自然资源加拿大组织和加拿大住房抵押建筑公司共同赞助高层公寓楼设计竞赛，要求新设计方案除具备其他一些特点外，还必须能提高能量效率以及楼内空气质量。

Recently, Natural Resources Canada and the Canada Mortgage and Housing Corporation jointly sponsored a contest that sough out high-rise department designs that promote energy efficiency and indoor air quality, among other attributes.

根据功的原理，阻力与距离的乘积等于作用力与距离的乘积。

From the principle of work, the product of the resistance times its distance equals the product of the effort times its distance.

当用氢氧化钠小心地使酯水解时，就形成乙酰乙酯。

On careful hydrolysis of an ester with barium hydroxide the salt of acetoacetic acid is formed.

上个月，AT&T公司用光脉冲的形式以每秒一百亿比特的速度，通过加勒比海海底长2000千米的光纤电缆传输信息。

Last month At&T sent the information as pulse of light at a rate of 10 billion bits per second over 2,000-kilometer stretch of cable under the Caribbean Sea.

就大多数这类新型的网络电话而论，那意味着能够直接阅读和回复通过这种电话发来的电子邮件，而无须启动（甚至不必拥有）个人电脑。

With most of these e-mail phones, that means being able to read and reply to electronic mail directly from the phone, without booting up (or even owning) a PC.

尽管有了各种机械，干农活还是很累，耗时也很长。

With all the help from the machines farming still requires hard work and long hours.

在50万伏位差的情况下，芯线中一些带负电荷的电子被迫进入聚乙烯绝缘层并在那里滞留。

With a difference of 500,000 volts, some of the negatively charged electrons in the core are forced into the polyethylene insulation, where they become trapped.

多莉可能在它自己的时代来临之前就衰老了，但是又有一种新的克隆动物正将年轻不老延伸到极限。

Dolly may grow old before her time, but a new breed of clones are taking youth to extremes.

垂直腔激光器不仅能提供聚焦更好的光束，而且其造价也应该比边缘发射型激光器更便宜。

As well as providing more tightly focused beams, vertical cavity lasers should be cheaper to produce than edge-emitting devices.

不仅克隆体细胞有较长的染色体端粒，而且在实验室里培育时，这些细胞分裂的次数要比非克隆体细胞多。

Not only do cells from the clones have long telomeres, but when grown in the lab they are able to divide more than non-cloned cells.

钢在工业上得到广泛应用，因为它具有许多有用的性能。

Steel is widely used in industry because it possesses a great number of useful properties.

其工作原理与照相机镜头在胶片上聚光而形成影像的原理完全相同。

It works in the same way that lens of a camera focuses light to create an image on film..

在那种场合，除了汽车不能发动以外，还会发生什么事情呢？

At that point, what should happen except that the car wouldn’t start?

虽然关节炎症状在患者节食期间会得到改善，但一但恢复饮食，这些症状通常就会复归。

Although the symptoms of arthritis often improve while a patient is fasting, they usually return as soon as eating resumes.

这可通过屏蔽中断请求来实现；因此，尽管有中断请求，处理器可不予理睬。

This can be achieved by masking the interrupt so that, although an interrupt may arrive, the processor simply ignores it.

需要高得多的温度，以便我们能把铁从固态变成液态。

A much higher temperature is required so that we could change iron from a solid state into liquid.

铁制品常常涂以保护层以防生锈。

Iron products are often coated in case they should rust.

万一全局处理机出了故障，其中一台本地处理机常可承担起全局处理机的功能。

Often, in case the global processor fails, one of the local processors may assume the function of the global processor.

自从回旋加速器发明以来，已设计了许多其他类似的仪器。

Since the cyclotron was invented, many other similar instruments have been devised.

当它们在就绪队列中等待时，输入/输出装置则空闲着。

While they are waiting in the ready queue, the I/O devices are idle.

所以，尽管低温动力汽车（以及电动汽车）属于零排放车型，但它们还是要依赖远在某处的发电厂提供能源支持，而发电厂往往是要排放污染物的。

So while cryogenic cars (and electric vehicles) have zero emissions, they rely on energy produced far away at emissions-generating power plants.

一些胎儿是经体外受精并进过培育后移植的，而另一些则是经由人工授精获得的。

Some are produced by IVF and cultured before being implanted, while others were conceived by artificial insemination.

随着台风的临近，气压开始下降。

The air pressure begins falling accordingly as a typhoon comes near.

不久铝箔本身就开始受到了更加大得多的关注，因为用户对其质量要求逐年提高了。

Soon aluminum foil itself started to receive much more attention as customers’ demand on quality increased year by year.

淋巴不能像许也那样循环，因此其运动很大程度上依赖肌肉收缩的挤压作用。

The lymph does not circulate as the blood does, so its movement depends largely on the squeezing effect of muscle contractions.

的确，在多次旨在对实际的针灸疗法和模拟的针灸疗法进行比较的测试中，接受模拟治疗者通常可获得与接受实际治疗者相同的止痛效果。

Indeed, in tests comparing genuine acupuncture with an imitation, patients receiving the fake treatment usually enjoy about as much relief (50 percent) as those given the real thing.

该风场的扰动虽然很弱，但还是可以看得出来。

Weak as it is, the disturbance in the wind field is discernible.

如果这一信息没有送到那么天然的食欲抑制素就不会产生，体重也不会停止增长。

When the message isn’t sent, there’s no natural appetite suppressant—and no end to weight gain.

其他人员推测，素食饮食可能改变了大肠内的菌群，以某种方式缓解了疾病。

Others speculate that a vegetarian diet may alter the bacterial population in the large intestine, somehow relieving the disease.

但是，医生们仍在争论该类疗法是否比安慰剂疗法（模拟治疗而非实际治疗）更有效。

However, doctors are still debating whether this type of therapy has nay effect beyond that of a placebo (a fake treatment with no real activity).

推拿以镇静或刺激的方式来保持神经系统平衡，采取哪种方式取决于在推拿之时个人需要达到哪种效果。

Massage balances the nervous system by soothing and stimulating it, depending on which effect is needed by the individual at the time of the massage.

每个人都知道，人类生活对石油依赖到什么程度：石油是那种神奇的液体—汽油—的来源，正是汽油使汽车能够开动行驶。

Everyone realizes to what extent the world is dependent on petroleum as the source of that magical fluid, gasoline, which has made the automobile possible to drive.

人们感到奇怪的是，为什么硬的金刚石会变成软的石墨，或者，为什么食盐溶于水而金刚石却不溶于水。

One wonders why a hard diamond can be converted into soft graphite or why table salt dissolves in water and diamonds do not.

进一步的试验有可能表明，湿法炼铜方法是否能够和何时才能变为在经济上对炼铜者有吸引力的替代方案。

Further tests may indicate whether and when hydro-metallurgical processes could become economically attractive alternatives for copper producers.

真正令人吃惊的是我们不仅能从处于生命末期的牛的细胞克隆出健康的牛犊，而且这些克隆动物的细胞明显比它们的实际年龄更年轻。

What is really surprising is not only were we able to clone healthy calves from cells at the end of their lifespan, but the “cloned” animals had cells that appear to be younger than their chronological age.

此外，神经键中那些分解多巴胺（MAO-B）的化学物质继续消耗所剩无几的多巴胺。

Also, the chemical in the synapse that breaks down the dopamine (MAO-B) continues to deplete what little dopamine is left.

要想了解推拿疗法的治病原理，有必要先简要探讨推拿的某些生理学作用。

To understand how massage therapy works, some of the physiological effects of massage need to be briefly examined.

因而一个由专家组成的小分队成立了，并时刻待命，随时准备在24小时之内奔赴疾病突发区。

This is why a team of experts has been formed and is on standby, ready to rush to the site of an outbreak within 24 hours.

然而，两种方法有着共同的缺陷：即反弹—一旦停止禁食，你禁食期间减掉的重量无论有多少通常都会恢复原状。

Both approaches, however, have one major drawback in common:whatever weight you shed during the fast usually returns once it ends.

发电机所产生的电流是通过粗铜线从发电厂输送到任何需要它的地方。

The electric current from the generations is taken through thick copper wires from the power station to wherever it is needed.

临界压力就是能在临界温度下使气体变为液体的最小压力。

Critical pressure is the smallest amount of pressure that can make a gas at critical temperature into a liquid.

但是这些研究结果应当给那些正在考虑培育胚胎以改善受孕机会的人类生育研究者们以警告。

But the result should serve as a warning to human fertility researchers who are considering culturing embryos to improve chances of achieving pregnancy.

镀铬的表面，诸如我们很熟悉的汽车部件和卫生设备的那种表面，具有很高的光洁度，而不易变色或产生痕迹。

A chrome-plated surface, such as that which we are familiar in automobile parts and plumbing fixtures, takes a high polish that is not easily tarnished or scratched.

聚丁烯也具有聚烯烃可能具有的高的耐强酸强健腐蚀性。

The polybutylene also has high resistance to corrosive attack by strong acids and bases as is expected for the polylefine.

同是臭氧，在平流层挡紫外线，对人是有益的；但在地面，被人吸入就会对人的呼吸系统产生严重伤害。

The same ozone that helpfully blocks ultraviolet light in the stratosphere can seriously damage your respiratory system when it is at ground level where it can be inhaled.

为什么长途输电时交流电优于直流电，还有一个理由。

There is another reason why A.C. is preferred to D.C. for long-distance transmission.

目前气体（还原）法正在飞速发展，并且取得了巨大成功。

At present the gaseous processes are rapidly developing and are most successful.

这与三年前所预料的相反,当时SL/RN固体燃料（还原）法似乎最可能迅速取得成功。

This is contrary to what was expected three years ago when the solid fuel process SL/RN seemed the most likely to take off quickly.

在熔化完毕后将钢水移到另一容器中进行精炼。

After melting is completed the steel is transferred to a separate vessel where refining is carried out.

营养不良一遇机会便会引发感染并造成非脂肪组织（统称为LBM）严重缺失。

Malnutrition invites opportunistic infections and contributes to wasting, severe loss of nonfatty tissues (collectively referred to as lean body mass, or LBM).

在阅读有关“帕金森氏病”及其治疗的内容之前，多了解一点人体运动的控制原理或许会有帮助。

Before reading about Parkinson’s disease and its treatment, it may probably be helpful to understand a little more about how the movement of your body is controlled.

从这个对比表格中可以很明显地看出，在硬件成本达到大型机成本之前，可以使用为数颇多的小型机。

It is quite obvious from this comparison chart that quite a few minis can be used before the hardware cost will equal that of a large computer.

就耐火材料的工作性能而言，旋转水口系统和直向滑动水口相比，其主要优点似乎是不言而喻的。

As far as refractory’s performance is concerned, the main advantages of the rotary nozzle system over the straight sliding gate would appear to be self-evident.

内轴承圈完全支撑在轴上，折旧要求轴的锥度与内圈镗口的锥度精确吻合。

Full inner ring support on the shaft requires exact coincidence of shaft taper and bore taper of inner ring.

关于紫外辐射使聚合物降解的精确路线或机理，这一领域的专家对它是有分歧的。

The exact route or mechanism of polymer degradation by ultraviolet radiations is not agreed upon by experts in the field.

概述了情报中心有关活动对计算设备的影响的预测，它表明计算设备的用量随着情报中心的迅速增多而急剧增大。

Projecting the impact of information center related activities on computing resources is outlined, showing that the consumption of computing resources grows rapidly with the proliferation in the number of computing centers.

对于生产钢铁用的贫矿石，我们必须在将其喂入高炉之前小心地加以处理。

We must carefully process the lean iron ores we use to produce iron and steel before they are fed to the blast furnace.

防止或至少延迟金属氧化的倾向这件事使全世界耗费了巨额金钱。

To prevent or, at least, to retard the tendency of metals to oxidize costs the world immense sum of money.

我们必须让现场工程师能够自由地运用他们个人的才智去追求自己的理想。

We must allow engineers on the spot freedom to apply their personal resources to pursue their ideals.

目前另外两个令人感兴趣的领域的研究也正在进行之中。

Two other intriguing areas are currently under research.

一个是利用针灸戒除毒瘾和酒瘾；针灸，特别是对外耳处的针灸，被应用于美国的许多戒毒所。

One is the use of acupuncture in easing withdrawal from the addiction to hard drugs and alcohol; acupuncture, especially of the outer ear, is available at many detoxification clinics in the United States.

另一个是针灸疗法有可能促进中风的康复及减少中风引起的损伤。

Another possibility is that acupuncture therapy may speed rehabilitation and limit damage after a paralyzing stroke.

硅酸钠的溶液可用来使木料和织物耐火，并可用作玻璃和陶器的黏合剂。

A solution of sodium silicate is used to render wood or cloth fireproof, and as a cement for glass and pottery.

他的目标是让这辆电动汽车能利用经过通宵充电的电池行驶300英里距离。

He aims to have the electric car running with a range of 300 miles on each overnight battery charge.

所介绍的优化技术考虑了操作要求、寿命成本、可靠性和可维护性、环境约束、性能要求等。

The optimization techniques presented take into account operational requirements, life-cycle cost, reliability and maintainability, environmental constraints, performance requirements, etc.

汞弧整流器中电流的这种流动成为电弧，并使汞蒸气发出强烈的紫光。

This flow of current in a mercury-vapor rectifier is called an electric arc, and causes the mercury vapor to glow with an intense purple light.

使用共享内存互连法的多微机或多小型机系统称为“紧耦合”系统。

Multimicro-and minicomputer systems, which employ the shared-memory interconnect approach, have been coined “tightly coupled”.

多莉看起来正常而健康，但去年的研究发现它的染色体端粒异乎寻常的短。

Dolly appears normal and healthy, but in last year’s study her telomeres were found to be unusually short.

在一个时期，表层和次表层的水流方向相反；表层水流向外海方向流动，靠近底层的水流则向陆地方向流动。

For a time, surface and subsurface current rate in opposite directions; flow is seaward at the surface and landward near the bottom.

实际上，即使太老的、无法在实验室里继续分裂的非克隆细胞也依旧能产生健康的、“年轻的”克隆体；显然，克隆有可能是一个返老还童的过程。

In fact, non-cloned cells that were too old to continue dividing in the lab were still able to produce healthy, “young” clones; apparently, cloning can be rejuvenating process.

显然，这与克隆技术以及所采用的供体细胞有关。

Clearly it has to do with the cloning technique and the donor cell used.

对620CC和800系列压缩泵说来，在整个泵送周期内，所泵送的产品始终保持在平滑的泵送管内，因此消除了稀释或交叉感染的风险。

In the 620CC and 800 Series of depressing pumps, pumped product remains within smooth pump tube throughout entire pumping cycle, thereby eliminating any risk of dilution or cross contamination.

Rezulin面市前的试验过程明显地检测出一些由它导致的肝异常症状，但发病率之低并不足以制止概要的批准与上市。

Some liver abnormalities were apparently detected during Rezulin’s pre-marketing testing, but not in sufficient frequency to halt its approval and release.

从反射表面弹回的光波称为反射射线。

The light wave that has bounced off the reflecting surface is called the reflected ray.

由于食品与药物管理局在两次不同的场合的督促，药物包装标签上增添了对医生的警告，建议他们对患者反复多次验血，并且仅限于采用其他药物无效的患者服用。

Warnings to physicians were added to the package label at the behest of the FDA on two occasions, advising physicians to utilize more frequent blood testing, and then restricting its use to those who did not benefit from other medications.

另外，对神经受体的刺激使得血管（通过反射作用）扩张，从而有利于血液流动。

Also, the stimulation of nerve receptors causes the blood vessels (by reflex action) to dilate, which also facilitate blood flow.

它们是强腐蚀流体（计量应用）的理想计量泵。

They are ideal for applications with aggressive fluids that require metering.

然而，已经有不少办法可有助于控制帕金森氏症患者脑神经细胞功能的逐步下降。

However, there are several methods that can help to manage the slow decline in function that occurs with Parkinson’s disease.

不饱和烃显然很高的烃却不能参与加成反应。

The failure of an apparently highly unsaturated hydrocarbon to enter into addition reactions is indeed surprising.

使轴转动（所需要的）力取决于臂长。

The force required to turn a shaft depends on the length of the lever used.

三合土是消石灰和砂的混合物，可用来在房屋、墙壁等的砌筑中把砖或石头年节在一起。

Mortar is a mixture of slaked lime and sand used for holding together bricks and stone in the construction of buildings, walls, etc.

人体对安全带的拉力传给了负载限制器，而该限制器是由一些设计成能被拉开的钢带组成的。

The strain of the body on the belt is transmitted to a load limiter comprising a block formed from strips of steel designed to tear apart.

本研究的目的是借助于适当的技术，定性和定量地测定铝合金中的金属间化合物，以确立在日常研究工作中快速鉴定这些化合物的方法。

The aim of the present work is to determine the intermetallic compounds in some aluminum alloys qualitatively and quantitatively and by means of a suitably chosen technique to establish ways for rapid identification of these compounds in routine investigations.

脱气器配置在电解槽外部靠近电解槽的地方。

The degasifier is disposed outside of, but close to the electrolytic cell.

他的想法是用两个电动马达来驱动一辆充电电池汽车，每个前轮安装一个，而位于车体下方的强力空气涡轮发电机则在汽车行驶中不断给蓄电池充电。

His idea is a battery car driven by two electric motors, one at each front wheel, with a powerful under-floor air-driven turbine alternator recharging batteries on the move.

伏打电池的电荷是以电子的形式存在于电池材料中。

The electrical charges of a voltaic cell are present in the materials of the cell in the form of electrons.

对氯化钠溶液而言，可以假定：通过第一次作用（即电解的直接作用）首先沉积在阴极的钠，会立即通过第二次作用（即与电解无关的作用）与水反应，形成氢氧化钠溶液而放出氢气。

With a solution of sodium chloride it may be supposed that the sodium first deposited on the cathode by a primary action (i.e. as a direct result of electrolysis) at once reacts with the water by secondary action (i.e. one not involving electrolysis), forming a solution of sodium hydroxide and liberating hydrogen gas.

通常，软件工程的生产率（每个人的产量）与参与项目的人员数量呈反比（参与人员越多，则单个程序员的软件产出率越低），这主要是由于为准确而可靠地交换与正在研发的软件系统有关的信息所要求的开销不断增大。

As a rule, productivity (production per person) in software engineering varies inversely with the size of a project work force (the larger the work force, the less productive is the individual programmer), due principally to the increasing overhead required to communicate information accurately and reliably concerning the system under development.

这种剧毒的化合物必须非常小心稳妥地加以存放。

This severely toxic chemical compound must be kept very carefully in a proper way.

此工艺过程所产生的压力为700磅/英寸2（50巴）的蒸汽可用以驱动空气压缩机。

Steam generated by the process at 700 psi (50 bars) is used to drive the air compressor.

针灸过程中的“针刺”指的是将多根极细的银针插入体表的某些特定穴位。

The “puncture” in acupuncture refers to the operation of inserting tiny needles at certain very specific points on the surface of the body.

它可以通过用水洗涤后再予以蒸馏的方法加以净化。

It is purified by washing with water and then distilling.

上面所写出的第二个反应的产物是碳酸的二乙基酯，即碳酸二乙酯。

Product of the second reaction written above is the diethyl ester of carbonic acid, ethyl carbonate.

能够启动或停止某一电路中的电流，例如，将手电筒电珠哦电流接通或断开，是很有用的。

It is useful to be able to start and stop the current in an electric circuit, for example, to turn a torch bulb on and off.

导电聚合物—能够导电的塑料—即将实现技术上的突破。

Conducting polymers—plastics that conduct electricity—are on the verge of a technological breakthrough.

触觉传感研究人员与视觉传感领域的同行们一样，正在着力解决相同的问题：如何立即分析所获取的数据。

Researchers in tactile sensing are now grappling with the same problem as are their colleagues in visual sensing:

铝工业和球墨铸铁工业（将镁用作合金成分的主要用户）的任何波动，都对镁生产厂家的命运具有直接影响。

analyzing the data once it is obtained.

用空气将乙烯这种易于获得而且比较便宜的材料氧化成各种产品，在工业上具有极其重要的意义。

Any fluctuations in the aluminum and nodular cast iron industries, the principal consumers of magnesium for alloying purposes, have a direct influence on the fortune of the magnesium products.

作为日益繁荣的21世纪新兴产业，IT产业在许多国家甚至像中国、印度这样的发展中国家一直在迅猛地发展中。

The oxidation of ethylene, a readily available and relatively cheap material, to various products by air is of great industrial significance.

世界卫生组织作为联合国一个拥有191个成员国的特殊机构，在各国之间增进卫生技术合作、执行控制和根除疾病的各种计划，为改善人类的生活质量而努力奋斗。

An increasingly prosperous new industry in 21st century, the IT industry has been rapidly developing in many countries, even in some developing countries like China and India.

能量既不能被创造也不能被消灭，这是一条普遍公认的法则。

A specialized agency of the United Nations with 191 member states, WHO promotes technical cooperation for health among nations, carries out programs to control and eradicate disease and strives to improve the quality of human life.

这些纳米管实际上是一些被拉长的分子。

Energy can neither be created nor destroyed, a universally accepted law.

在这样的高度上，台站地形所造成的局地影响预期可以大幅减小到最低限度；这种假设似乎主要在空气充分流通的相当开阔的地区证明有理。

At these levels the local influence of station exposure is expected to be greatly minimized, an assumption which seems justified mainly in cases of rather open locations that permit sufficient air circulation.

当他们设法让聚乙炔膜与碘蒸气起反应时，其导电性呈千万倍的增加；这一发现最终使他们获得了诺贝尔化学奖。

When they caused the polyacetylene films to react with iodine vapor, the conductivity increased by as much as ten million tines—a discovery that was eventually to give them a Nobel Prize in Chemistry.

碳酸盐能够通过往碳酸的水溶液中添加强碱的方法予以制备。

The salts of carbonic acid, the carbonates, can be prepared by adding alkali to such aqueous solutions.

据我看来，这台旧机器应当换一台新的了。

This old machine, as it appears to me, should be replaced by a new one.

但正如人们所料，这种酸是不可能通过将硅石溶解于水中形成的。

But this acid cannot be formed, as might be expected, by dissolving silica in water.

少量的铜化合物对于每一种植物或动物—当然也对于人类自身—的生存和健康是必不可少的。

Copper compounds are, in small quantities, essential for the life and health of every plant and animal and, of course, to man himself.

这种新系统价钱比较便宜，更为重要的是/况且，它的质量较好。

The new system is cheaper, and what’s more, it’s better.

当把少量水喷洒到一块生石灰时，就会有热量生成—这可由放出的蒸汽来证明—而石灰则碎裂成白粉即氢氧化钙。

When a piece of quicklime is sprinkled with a little water, heat is produced, as is shown by the steam given off, and the lime crumbled to a white powder, calcium hydroxide.

水泥、木料和钢材是最广泛使用的建筑材料。

Cement, wood and steel are the most widely used building materials.

不存在严重的温度控制问题。

There is no serious problem of controlling the temperature.

这样一些洋流流向的形成、消失或改变可以在大约几个小时或几天内发生。

Such currents may form, disappear, or change flow direction within a matter of hours or days.

潮流可引起各层海水之间发生混合，所以水体只能有一种适度的分层。

Tidal currents cause mixing between layers, so that the waters become only moderately stratified.

在施工过程中，常会出现需要改变设计的问题。

During construction, problems often arise which require design changes.

Twister VSB 型干螺旋真空泵用于溶剂回收和化学处理过程，具有低温、干燥和环境友好的特点。

Twister VSB dry screw vacuum pump is a cool, dry, environmentally friendly solution for solvent recovery and chemical processing applications.

即使在这样一个系统中，近乎相同的两初始状态有时也会于一周之后在总体统计上发生差异。

Even in such a system, gross statistical divergence of two nearly identical initial states will occur, sometimes in a week.

观测进行时期为一个月差两天。

The observation was carried out one month less two days.

此飞机的设计速度为800千米/小时。

The aircraft has been designed to fly at 800 kilometers per hour.

图1是阐明分馏法的流程图。

The flow sheet shown in Fig.1 is intended to illustrate the process of fractionation by distillation.

一片放在阳光下的金属，其温度要上升到它吸收热量和失去热量的速率相等时才停止。

A piece of metal left in the sun rises in temperature until it loses heat at he same rate at which it absorbs heat.

在第一阶段急流远在其北且一般为由由西向东的方向。

In the first stage the jet stream lies well to the north and it takes a general west-east direction.

在这一阶段，海平面上西风气流很强且属纬向性的，它们比正常位置偏向了极地。

At this stage sea-level westerlies are strong and zonal in character and they lie poleward of their normal position.

碳与氢之间的双键可防止自由转动，而能否生成两种立体异构体则取决于羟基和氢原子是否相互叠置。

The double linkage between carbon and hydrogen prevents free rotation and two stereoisomers are possible depending on whether or not the hydroxyl group and hydrogen atom are over each other.

喷洒在空气中产生小水滴，它们使热辐射减小，但是喷洒一停止，植物本身温度就立刻下降。

Sprinkling creates water particles in the air that reduce outgoing radiation, but plant temperature declines immediately on cessation of the operation.

部分原因是液体的表面张力所产生的破坏力，所以用超临界二氧化碳代替这种液体有助于防止这种问题出现。

The forces exerted by liquid surface tension are partly to blame, so replacing the liquid with supercritical carbon dioxide helps to prevent the problem.

输出功率绝不可能等于输入功率，因为总有损耗。

The output power can never equal the input power, for there are always losses.

我想可能存在某些维持染色体端粒的物质，但寿命的延长确实出乎我们的意料。

I thought it might be possible that there would be some maintenance of telomeres, but that we see extension is unexpected.

隔多久进行一次观测，这些观测的站点彼此相距多远，取决于想要获得其资料的大气事件的规模。

How often observations are made, and how widely they are spaced, depend on the scale of the atmospheric events about which information is desired.

据人们所知，当地天气在几天内可以受到几千英里以外的气象条件的影响。

It is known that local weather can be affected within a few days by meteorological conditions thousands of miles away.

当然，如果你仅仅关注疼痛是否减轻的话（相对于潜在疾病的治愈而言），那么只要感觉有好转，针灸的效果是来自物理方面还是仅仅来自于心理方面实际上都无关紧要。

Of course, if your only concern is pain relief (as opposed to a cure of the underlying problem), it doesn’t really matter whether acupuncture’s effects are physical or merely psychological, as long as you feel better.

艾滋病患者（又称PWAs）在饮食方面所遭遇的两难困境表现为：患者一方面必须进行大量进食，另一方面又不得不防范饮食可能导致的疾病，改变食谱和用药，还要克服因药物治疗以及艾滋病本身而引发的食欲不振和消化不良。

The nutritional dilemma of persons with AIDS, or PWAs, is that they must eat abundantly yet they must also avoid foodborne illness, juggle foods and medications, and surmount the poor appetite and indigestion caused by their medications and by AIDS itself.

似乎随着新千年的到来，微软的Word也改变了我们文字处理的方式。

It seems that with the coming of a new Millenium, working in Microsoft Word has also changed the way we do word processing.

法拉第所称的电化学当量就是现在所称的化学当量。

What Faraday called the “electrochemical equivalent” is what is now called the chemical equivalent.

此图表明最大降水出现在印尼以东。

The figure shows that the maximum precipitation occurred to the east of Indonesia.

一位想要进行世界首例头颅移植手术的美国医生承认，手术受体很可能会排斥新移植的头颅。

An American doctor who wants to perform the world’s first head transplant has conceded the host body would probably reject the new addition.

唯一能决定把什么编写进操作系统的人是专业编程人员。

The only people who make the decisions on what went into the system were programmers.

研究者们不清楚为何他们的牛犊显得与多莉如此迥异。

Researchers don’t know why their calves appear so different from Dolly.

这一发现引起了人们的担忧，即克隆动物或未来以克隆细胞为基础的医学治疗将会是短命的。

That finding raised fears that cloned animals or future medical treatments based on cloned cells would turn out to be short-lived.

植株高度范围内的温度在白天会极大地增加，这不仅是由于空气的垂直交换受到抑制，而且也是由于“风障”结构向南倾斜从而使地表所反射的相当大的一部分太阳辐射又重新返回地表和植物。

A large increase of temperatures at the plant levels is obtained in the daytime not only from the suppression of vertical air exchange, but also by the fact that the “brush” structures are slanted to the south so that a considerable amount of the solar radiation reflected by the surface is redirected towards ground and plants.

这包括如下设想：在一种盐里，碱和酸分别具有阳电和阴电，在电解时，它们被吸引到相反的电极上并且由于电荷的中和而被释放出类。

This involves the idea that in a salt the base and acid have positive and negative charges, respectively, and that on electrolysis they are drawn to the oppositely-charged electrodes and liberated by neutralization of their charges.

Vector系列蠕动泵的启动与停机便捷可靠，并能持续泵送具各种压力值和流量值的浆状、汁状、塑胶状或厚重状的液体。

Vector series peristaltic pumps can reliably start, stop and continuously pump fluids that are pasty, pulpy, plastic or just plain thick at a wide range of pressures and flows.

已经研究出一种取决于某些盐类的不溶性的金属定性分析法。

A system of qualitative analysis of the metals has been devised that depends on the insolubility of certain salts.

我们几乎没有注意的很神奇的物质变化每天都在眼前发生。

Very wonderful changes in matter take place before our eyes everyday to which we pay little attention.

这不是我所希望的那种仪器。

This instrument is not such as I expect.

酒精是易燃的，苯和汽油也是一样。

Alcohol is combustible, as are benzene and gasoline.

一种称为电子的小粒子绕原子核旋转。

The electrons, as one kind of the small particles is called, revolve round the nucleus.

经常提到的这类要点对于掌握尖端科学技术是不可或缺的。

Such points as are often mentioned are essential to the mastery of sophisticated science and technology.

这个实验需要多少仪器设备，你最好就预先准备好多少。

You’d better get ready beforehand as many instruments as are necessary for your experiment.

普通原子总是具有与电子数一样多的质子。

Ordinary atoms always have the same number of protons as they do of electrons.

磁场可用和电相同的方式加以表示。

A magnetic field may be represented in the same manner as an electronic field.

实验中的这些老鼠并没有遵循与处于并非过度拥挤的群体中的老鼠相同的行为模式。

The rats in the experiments did not follow the same patterns of behavior as rats would in a community without overcrowding.

如前所述，这座炉子已经停止操作了。

This furnace, as has been mentioned above, has been shut down.

生物钟使我们成为在上午九点时不同于下午三点时的人。

Biological rhythms make us a different person at 9 a.m. than we are at 3 p.m.

在力的作用下，没有一种材料不或多或少地变形。

There is no material but still deform more or less under the action of force.

这是一种用于不能有一点儿污染或者环境要求高的工艺过程的理想系统。

This is an ideal system for processes that cannot tolerate even a hint of contamination or where environmental issues are a concern.

γ射线不受电场影响；它们不过是β射线在通过一些固体物质时作用于它们而产生的极短的χ射线。

The gamma rays are not affected by an electric field and are nothing but a very short χ-rays which are produced by the action of he beta rays on some of the solid material through which they pass.

尚不会给计算机安装操作系统的人们可以前往求助的一个地方便是书店。

One place people who cannot yet manage to boot up their computers can turn to for help is bookstore.

通过将这只老鼠的DNA与人类DNA的基因进行比较，他们得以鉴别出一种他们认为可以在调整食欲方面发挥关键作用的基因。

By comparing the mouse DNA with genes in human DNA, they were able to identify one that believe could play a key role in regulating appetite.

当我们谈论某人的个性时，我们指的就是将这个人于其他人区分开来的其行为、言谈、思考和感觉的方式。

When we talk about someone’s personality, we mean the ways in which he or she acts, speaks, thinks and feels that make that individual different from others.

正在得到广泛而大量研究的癌症的病因不久就将查清。

The causes of cancer, large amounts of research on which is being widely done, will soon be found out.

所制造的大多数集成电路器件封装得很牢实。

Most devices of the integrated circuit, as are manufactured, are ruggedly packed.

纳米技术被认为是21世纪的一门重要的制作技术，它将能够以低成本制造出几乎任何化学成分稳定的结构。

Nanotechnology has been described as a key manufacturing technology of the 21st century, which will be able to manufacture almost any chemically stable structure at low cost.

已知有这样的一些元素，它们的原子通常只能和任何其他元素的一个原子化合。

Some elements are known the atoms of which usually do not combine with more than one atom of any other element.

不过，英国的科研人员现已研究出利用干冰（固体二氧化碳）来清除的方法，清除后干冰完全气化，除了剥离下来的油漆和尘垢外不会产生任何残留废物。

But British researchers have now developed a process using dry ice—solid carbon dioxide—which evaporates completely after doing the job and so generates no waste, apart from the material it dislodges.

基本上有三种信息交换的类型，其分类是以计算机和外设的时间基准点为依据的。

There are basically three types of information exchange, whose classification refers to the time references of the computer and the external devices.

网络技术已得到拓展，可用来召开网络会议和进行实时通信；其功能就像是一个组件，为人们在网上，特别是内联网上的合作提供了便利。

Web technology has been extended to handle conferencing and real-time communications, to enable it to act like groupware, which facilitates people collaborating over a network, especially over an intranet.

多巴胺对于人的运动机能至关重要，它就是一种神经传递素，可帮助将信息传递到纹状体。

Dopamine is crucial to human movement and is the neurotransmitter that helps transmit messages to the striatum that both initiates and controls your movement and balance.

而后者既引发又控制人体的运动和平衡。

The solution may be to replace the silicon-based devices used today with minuscule carbon molecules, which would have another advantage:

解决方法也许是用微型碳分子来替代今天使用的硅基电子装置。

they conduct heat much faster than silicon, and therefore would be more suitable for microelectronics.

到那时，战场上的一切通讯任务，譬如坦克之间的沟通，坦克和直升机之间的联络，都可由激光来完成。

Robert White, who has successfully transplanted the heads of monkeys and dogs, is ready to move on to humans, in an operation he estimates would cost at least 1 million.

罗伯特·怀特曾经成功地完成猴子和狗的头颅移植手术，现在他正准备在人类身上继续进行这项手术。

Concerns over cellular aging in clones center around telomeres, regions of DNA at the ends of chromosomes which shorten every time a cell divides.

该手术据他估计至少会耗资一百万美元。

In the daytime, differences due to soil influences may be found only in a very shallow layer, perhaps within the first inch above the surface where the before-mentioned vertical heat transport is retarded due to friction influences in the boundary layer.

人们对克隆体细胞的老化的关注主要集中在染色体端粒，即位于染色体末端的脱氧核糖核酸区域。

Such waves occur most frequently at stormy latitudes, where the storms tend to come in groups traveling in the same direction, with only short periods separating them.

这些染色体每分裂一次，其染色体端粒就缩短一次。

More sophisticated models exist which take into account relative cost effectiveness of product lines in a given situation which varies in terms of growth of utilization over a predetermined number of years.

白天，因土壤条件不同而造成的差异只有在十分浅薄的气层中（或许是在地表以上1英寸高度范围内）才可能发现。

Manufacturers provide self-administered questionnaires to aid in the selection of the proper flowers, each of which is thought to correspond to an emotional or psychological state.

在那里风暴常常是成群出现的，它们沿着同一方向移动，彼此间只有很短的间隔时间。

When air is cooled to a point at which the air’s capacity to hold more water vapor is zero, saturation is reached.

还有更复杂的模式，这些模式考虑了在给定的情况下，生产线的相对成本效益。

By the time the pressure has fallen to atmospheric pressure, the temperature will drop also to the steam temperature at that temperature.

而这个给定情况，在预定的若干年里是随着利用的增长而变化的。

Each time the current changes directions, a period of no current, known as slack water, intervenes.

制造商提供自填调查问卷，帮助患者选择合适的花卉种类。

Whenever a wave moves out from a source in uniform medium, it travels in straight lines.

其中的每一种花只对某一特定情绪或心理状态有效。

Typhoon and hurricanes do not form exceptionally large waves, because their winds, although very strong, do not blow long enough from one direction.

当空气进一步冷却到容纳更多水汽的能力为零时，就达到了饱和状态。

In summer people feel sticky in that relative humidity is quite high.

到压力降到了大气压力之时，温度也将降到常压下蒸汽的温度。

Methane liquefies, if it is cooled and compressed.

每当潮流改变方向时，中间都有一段叫做平潮的无潮流阶段。

Seeing that there is often poor visibility, the site chosen as an airport is not appropriate.

每当/凡是波从均匀介质中的波源移出时，它都呈现直线传播。

As a result, the tsunami of 1957 killed no one in Hawaii, though water levels were locally higher than 1946.

台风和飓风并不会形成特大的巨浪，因为这些风虽然很强，但它们并不能沿着同一方向长时间地吹。

The residual effects of the cloud clusters are generally ignored even though the area they cover is perhaps an order of magnitude larger than the convective region itself.

此书处于静止状态，或者用物理术语来讲处于静力平衡，并不是因为没有力作用在它上面，而是因为作用其上的力彼此互相抵消。

Just as water will run downhill, so heat, if left to itself, flows down the temperature “hill” (gradients).

夏季人们感到皮肤黏糊糊的是因为相对湿度很高。

Tuberculosis, once considered a disease of the past, has re-emerged to such an extent that it has been declared a global emergency by WHO.

甲烷会液化，如果它受到冷却和压缩的话。

The broader the range of network services is, the more capabilities a network can provide to users connected to it.

鉴于这里能见度经常欠佳，所以将此地选为机场是不适当的。

Horizontal-cavity lasers emit light at the edge of the chip, in the same plane as the junction layer, whereas vertical-cavity lasers emit light from the flat chip surface.

结果，1957年夏威夷的海啸没有造成一人死亡，虽然局部水位比1946年还高。

After the concept of temperature became understood, there were many years of scientific development before the real nature of heat was established.

云团的残余影响通常是忽略不计的，即使它们覆盖的地区可能比对流区本身大一个量级。

Meteorological science and technology have grown to the extent that behaviors of the atmosphere could be monitored on a global basis.

就像水总是流下山一样，热若听其自然也会沿着“热坡（温度坡度）”而下。

While some labs plan to delete genes from pig donors, others are busy putting in new ones.

曾一度被认为不复存在的肺结核又卷土重来，来势之猛令世界卫生组织向全球发出告急。

The paper and plastic caps prevent heat losses by convection almost entirely, so that after a few weeks when the caps are removed in spring, such plants are better developed and reach maturity earlier than those grown under natural conditions.

网络服务的范围越广，网络就能为接入的用户提供越多的功能。

We define nanotechnology simply as the art and science of building molecular structures so that they are sufficiently large and complex to function as machines or devices.

水平腔激光器是在芯片边缘，在与夹层相同的平面上发光，而垂直腔激光器则是从芯片扁平的表面上发光的。

Each marginal sea, or bay, is affected by the tide in much the same way as the Atlantic is affected by the wave from the Antarctic.

在人们理解了温度的概念以后，又经过多年的科学研究才确定了热的真正性质。

This interrupt routine is like a subroutine, except that instead of being called by an instruction in the program it is triggered by a hardware input signal.

气象科学和技术已发展到可在全球范围内监测大气特性的程度。

By analogy with semiconductor technology one speaks of doping the polymer when it is subjected to oxidation with iodine vapor.

一些实验室计划从猪的器官供体中去除一些基因，而其他一些实验室则正在忙于往器官供体中添加一些新的基因。

As a rule, the temperature in the troposphere decreases steadily with increasing altitude until the tropopause is reached.

这些纸罩和塑料罩几乎全部阻止了对流热的损失，以致几周后到春季将这些盖罩取走时，这些植物比在自然条件下生长要发育得好些，成熟期也要早些。

Users are advised to ignore any overt illness, instead of asking themselves how they feel and what emotions they are experiencing, since the flower remedies are intended to treat psychological states, not physical disease.

我们将纳米技术简单地定义为构建分子结构使其大小和复杂程度足以发挥机器或装置之功能的艺术与科学。

Coke is essential in the winning of iron from its ores and would be prepared for this purpose whether or not the coal tat were collected and utilized.

每一边缘海即海湾都受到潮水的影响，其发生方式与大西洋受到来自南极的波浪影响类似。

Frozen at around -35℃, mercury is not used in thermometers where extremely low temperature may be expected.

这个中断服务程序很像子程序，所不同的是，它不是由程序中的指令调出的，而是由硬件输入信号触发的。

Reportedly the yield per acre has been 30% increased insomuch as modern agricultural technologies are practiced in this hilly region.

与半导体技术相类似，当聚合物受到碘蒸汽氧化之时，就是人们所谓的掺杂聚合物过程。

The induced emf is in such a direction that it opposes the change of current.

通常，对流层的温度一直到对流层顶都是随高度增加而不断降低的。

However, many diabetics would be sicker, or dead, without Rezulin, given that its two alternatives were not available in 1997 and 1998.

由于花卉疗法旨在调理心理状态而非治疗身体疾患，所以患者应该忽略外显的疾病，转而问自己感觉如何以及自己处于何种情绪状态下。

Although chlorofluorocarbons or CFCs do not harm the environment near the ground, they slowly travel upwards to the ozone layer where they are broken down by UV light into chlorine atoms, which eat away at the ozone.

从铁矿中炼取铁，焦煤是必不可少的；为此，无论煤焦油收集和利用与否，焦煤总是要炼的。

The primary deposition of sodium may be shown at a cathode of mercury, when sodium amalgam will be formed and very little hydrogen evolved.

由于水银在-35℃左右会冻结，所以在极端低温可能出现的地区它不用于温度计。

Part or all of the light may be reflected, absorbed, or transmitted by the thing or object that comes into its way.

根据报道，由于现代农业技术在这一带丘陵地区的实行，每英亩的产量已增加30%。

The atomic theory was not accepted until the 19th century.

感应电动势的方向朝向阻止电流发生改变的那个方向。

The hypothesis will be rejected if it is not proved by any experiment.

然而，若是没有Rezulin，若是该药的两种替代药物没有在1997和1998年推出，许多糖尿病患者将会病情加重甚至死亡。

Weather is determined by the simultaneous occurrence of several meteorological elements at a geographical locality or over broad areas of the earth.

虽然氟利昂（CFC）并不损害地面附近的环境，但他们会缓慢上升至臭氧层，在那里被紫外线分解为氯原子，后者大量吞噬臭氧。

This communications link is achieved by the watch using a photo-sensitive cell to pick up dots on cathode-ray-tube screens.

钠的初次沉淀可以在水银阴极看到，这时钠汞齐就将形成，并有少量的氢放出。

Rainbows are formed when sunlight passes through small drops of water in the sky.

一部分的光或全部的光可能被挡住其去路的东西或物体反射、吸收或透射。

It is estimated that in the short time since Rezulin’s introduction, it has been used to treat 1.9 million people.

原子学说直到十九世纪才为人们所接受。

The sense of inferiority that he acquired in his youth has never been totally eradicated.

一个假说如果不能借助实验加以证明的话，就会遭到排斥。

Other questions will be discussed briefly.

天气是由在地球表面的某一地理位置或者广袤地区同时出现的若干气象要素的综合作用所决定的。

The problem must be dealt with at the appropriate time.

这种通信联络是靠手表利用光敏元件读取阴极射线管屏幕上的光电实现的。

More than 3,000,000 cars are now produced by all factories in China every year.

彩虹是阳光穿过天空中的小水滴时形成的。

More power is likely to be needed during the winter.

据估计，自Rezulin面市至今的不长时期内，就已有一百九十万人利用这一药物进行治疗。

It would be astonishing if that loss were not keenly felt.

他在青少年时期留下的自卑感还没有完全消除。

It has been thought that radium radiations might be useful in curing various diseases.

如果人们没有强烈地感受到损失，那倒是令人惊诧了。

As far as 1920s attention was directed towards the problem.

人们认为镭的射线可以用来治疗各种疾病。

The reasonable use must be made of the natural resources.

中国国际威望的不断提高使汉语在国际上的地位得到进一步强化，想学汉语的外国人越来越多了。

Release of the heat of fusion is believed to alter the pressure gradient in such a way as to diminish the destructive winds near the storm center.

有关疾病管理的种种不现实的主张已有所闻，而最新的医疗改革举措也起了推波助澜的作用。

Individual jet maxima are frequently found to be located at the tips of deep low-pressure troughs.

早在20世纪20年代，人们就注意这一问题了。

The problem of the earth becoming warm was seriously discussed by the scientists present.

我们一定要合理利用自然资源。

Changes in architecture are usually not easily made in tightly or “closely” coupled systems of multiminis.

人们认为融解热的释放可以改变气压梯度，使得风暴中心附近的破坏力得以减小。

With the temperature unchanged, the air is made to reach condensation by adding water.

人们常常发现，个别急流的最大风速中心位于深低压槽的底端。

Even today, specific forecasts are only made for the period of 3 to 5 days in advance.

与会的科学家对地球变暖的问题进行了认真的讨论。

During the experiment, moisture was measured twice a day at 20-cm intervals between 0 and 80 cm of the soil.

在多小型机的“紧耦合”或“近耦合”系统中，通常很难做到在其结构上的改变。

An on-line energy detector is used to monitor the laser energy, making the operation procedure simple and laser power accurate.

在温度不变的条件下，通过加入水汽而使空气达到饱和。

Water can be shown as containing impurities.

即便当今也只能对未来3～5天的天气作出具体预报。

It has been proved that drug abuse is one of the approaches to developing AIDS.

在实验中，一天两次对0～80厘米土壤层每隔20厘米处测定温度。

A proton has a positive charge and an electron has a negative charge, but a neutron has neither.

使用在线实时能量探测器检测激光能量，从而简化操作环节、准确调控激光能量。

None of the real structures are absolutely rigid.

可以证明水中含有杂质。

All metals are found not to conduct electricity equally well.

业已证明，吸毒是感染艾滋病的途径之一。

But friction is not always useless, in certain cases it becomes a helpful necessity.

质子带正电荷，电子带负电荷，但中子不带任何电荷。

All germs are invisible to the naked eye.

现实的结构中没有一个是绝对刚性的结构。

In practice, error sometimes always seems unavoidable.

人们发现，并非所有金属都能同样好地导电。

Likewise, few doctors believe that fasting, in itself, has any lasting therapeutic effects.

可是摩擦并不总是无用的，在某些情况下它是有益的、必需的。

DMA involves the isolation of all devices, other than the single device to be used for data transfer, from the memory while the data transfer between memory and the appropriate peripheral is taking place.

同样，很少有医生相信禁食本身会有任何持续的治疗效果。

Edge-emitters cannot be tested until the wafer is chopped up and each laser chip is mounted on a test rig or in the device in which it is to be packaged.

DMA技术要求在存储器与适宜的外设间进行数据传输时，把全部装置（而非仅指用于数据传输的那个装置）都从存储器分离开来。

A book may be compared to your neighbor; if it be good, it cannot last too long; if bad, you cannot get rid of it too early.

一次快速的实情核查证实，计算机实际上不仅没有减少用纸量，相反却使之增加。

We don’t choose our favorite color as we grow up; we are born with our preference.

只有在芯片被切割成形并安装到试验台上，或安装到要组装的激光器上之后，才能对边缘发射型激光器进行测试。

The absence of air also explains why the stars do not seem to twinkle in space, as they do from the earth.

一本书好比你的邻居。

The engine didn’t stop because the fuel was finished.

如果是本好书，保持的时间越久越好；如果是本坏书，则越早摒弃越好。

A probe sent by NASA exploded before reaching the planet last year and it now doesn’t look as if there'll be another Mars visit until the end of the decade.

我们并非是在我们长大成人的过程中选择我们所喜爱的色彩的；我们是生来就具有对某种色彩的偏爱。

No part of the soil can act as plant food unless it is first dissolved.

没有空气也解释了为什么了行星在太空里看起来不像从地球上看上去那样闪烁的原因。

Mining engineers and civil engineers cannot excavate mines or build structures without knowledge of rock mechanics.

这台发动机并非因为燃油耗尽而停车。

Unfortunately, there was not an atom of evidence to convince the scientists in this field.

去年美国宇航局发射的一颗火星探测器在到达火星之前爆炸失事；现在看来，在本十年结束前似乎是不会有下一次的火星探测任务了。

The derivatives of carbonic acid which are of interest to the organic chemists are usually prepared neither from carbon dioxide nor carbonates.

如果植物养料不加以溶解，那么土壤的任何部分都不能起到植物养料的作用。

There exist neither perfect insulators nor perfect conductors.

采矿工程师和土木工程师不懂得岩石力学就不能开凿矿山和修造建筑物。

First comes a gradual change in water level, the forerunner, a few hours ahead of the storm’s arrival.

遗憾的是，没有一丁点证据能令这一领域的科学家们信服。

Then followed the discovery of a new radioactive element by Mrs. Curie, which was named plutonium.

令有机化学家感兴趣的碳酸衍生物通常既不是由二氧化碳，也不是由碳酸盐制备的。

From this accidental discovery developed the enormous benefits of stainless steel.

既不存在完美绝伦的绝缘体，也不存在完美无缺的导电体。

The lightest element is hydrogen, the atom of which consists of a nucleus of only proton, around which revolves one electron.

首先出现水位的逐渐变化，这是风暴到达前几小时的先兆。

In this picture is shown a new type of computer.

然后，随之而来的是居里夫人发现了一种新的放射性元素，命名为钚。

So was born the echo-sounding apparatus, now in general use in ships.

由这一偶然的发现开发出不锈钢的巨大裨益。

Above the troposphere is the stratosphere, followed by the ionosphere and capped by the exosphere.

最轻的元素是氢，其原子由只有一个质子的原子核构成，且只有一个电子环绕该质子运行。

Within this area is a double minimum in pressure with one center collocated with the vorticity maximum and the other about 3 km farther north.

图片中展示的是一种新型计算机。

Among the noxious compounds that form after a few hours of complex chemical cookery is ozone.

这种回声探测仪就这样问世了，而今普遍应用于各种船只。

More intriguing is using the same pump/motor combination to create a regenerative braking system.

在对流层上是平流层，接着是电离层，最上层是外逸层。

Much more important than the element itself are some of its compounds.

在这一区域内有一对最小气压中心，一个与最大涡度中心相重合，另一个则位于更向北3千米左右处。

To be particularly considered are the following mechanisms.

经过几小时复杂的化学变化后所生成的有害化合物中就有臭氧。

Still undergoing pilot tests is another composite fuel, a mixture of coal particles, water and additives.

更为诱人的是利用这种液压泵兼马达装置来床在一个再生制动系统。

Surrounding the earth is a layer of air of unknown thickness.

比这种元素本身更重要得多的是它的某些化合物。

Written on the label is the model of the machine.

要特别给以考虑的是下列机理。

Not until August 1974 did the expeditionary observations begin.

尚在进行中间试验的是另一种符合燃料—煤粉，水和添加剂的混合物。

Not only has the probability of surprise awakened the interest, but also the fact that most of the living world and of the food-producing plants occupy the thin layer beneath the conventional observation height.

包绕地球的是一层不知其厚度为多少的空气。

But only very recently have they solved the problem of finding the right conditions for making a dense deposit which will firmly adhere.

标签上写的是这台机器的型号。

Only when its melting-point temperature is reached does iron start to pass into a liquid.

直到1974年8月考察探险活动才开始。

Coal has been found in this region, and so has oil.

引起人们对此产生兴趣可能不仅是出自惊讶好奇，而且也是由于下列事实：大部分生物和大多数粮食作物都生存于这一常规观测高度一下的浅薄气层中。

The frequencies higher than 20,000 vibrations per second generally cannot be heard, nor can these high frequencies normally be felt.

但只是在最近他们才解决了下列问题，即找出在电镀时能产生牢固黏附作用的致密沉积物的适宜条件。

There is no known nutritional means of curing or preventing infection by HIV, the retrovirus that causes AIDS.

只有当达到熔点温度时，铁才开始变成液体。

Neither can nutritional measures alone prevent wasting.

煤已经在该地区发现，而且也发现了石油。

When the moon changes its position, so do the orientation of the tide-generating forces and the position of the equilibrium tide.

高于每秒两万次震荡的频率一般是无法听见的，而这样高的频率通常也是无法感觉到的。

Indoor relative humidity has a low value in cold weather and is then a better measure of the drying effect on skin than is outdoor relative humidity.

目前还没有找到饮食手段来治疗或预防引发艾滋病的反转录病毒HIV的感染。

Carbon monoxide is poisonous, as are the gases we are going to discuss in the next chapter.

也无法仅靠饮食手段来防止非脂肪组织缺失。

Air occupies space just as does any other fluid.

当月亮的位置改变时，引潮力的取向和平衡潮的位置也随之改变。

Tiny particles of one substance are dispersed throughout the other, as are particles of a solute throughout the solvent in a solution.

寒冷季节室内相对湿度值很低，因而它在量度湿度对皮肤的致干效应方面比室外相对湿度效果更好。

Complicated though the problem is, it can be solved in only two hours with an electronic computer.

如我们将在下一章里讨论的那些气体一样，一氧化碳同样是有毒气体。

Tremendous as was the destructive power of the atom, its potentialities for peace were even greater.

如同我们将在下一章里讨论的那些气体一样，空气也要占据空间。

All magnets behave the same, be they larger or small.

一种物质的微小颗粒在另一种物质中到处扩散的方式同溶液内一种溶剂到处扩散的方式一样。

Simple and clear window display providing operators with a convenient operation environment makes easier editing a patient's data and modifying the surgery parameters.

这问题虽然很复杂，但用一台电子计算机只需两个小时即可解决。

In chemical formula, the symbol for hydrogen is H; for oxygen O; for nitrogen N.

尽管原子具有巨大的破坏力，其用于和平用途的潜力却更加巨大。

It involves the hydration of the silicates in the mixture and probably also of calcium oxide.

所有的磁体，无论大小，都具有相同的性能。

Ice keeps the same temperature while melting.

简单明了的系统窗口显示为操作人员提供了方便的操作环境，使得编辑患者资料和修改手术参数变得更为轻松。

An object, once in motion, will keep on moving because of its inertia.

在化学式中，氢的符号是H，氧的符号是O，氮的符号是N。

If put together and heated to 25℃ at constant pressure, these substances will result in a new compound.

它牵涉到混合料中硅酸盐的水化作用；很有可能地牵涉到氧化钙的水化作用。

Prolonged fasting is an extremely effective—though not necessarily desirable—way to lose weight in a hurry.

如果把这些物质放在一起并在常压下加热到25℃。

BY some estimates, between 50 and 70 percent of patients with chronic pain receive at least temporary relief when treated with acupuncture, and some experience long-term relief as well.

持续性禁食是极其有效的—虽然不是绝对理想的—一种快速减肥方法。

Apart from accumulation of fat, deer are provided with further means by which to survive.

由于分子的内能越小该分子就越稳定，因此共振的存在就相应的会有稳定性的增加。

Sound is conducted through steel in the same manner as through air.

据估计，约50%～70%的慢性疼痛病患者在接受针灸治疗后，至少会有暂时的缓解，而另一些人则能感受到长期的效果。

Large temperature and salinity changes occur in shallow, partially isolated coastal waters, a degree of variability well beyond anything observed in the open ocean.

除了积累脂肪以外，鹿还被赋予了进一步的借以越冬生存的手段。

Everybody should know clearly at which speed to drive their cars when they are driving on the superhighways.

声音通过钢而传导的方式与它通过空气传导的方式完全一样。

The crop did not grow well what with species and what with non-uniform top application of fertilizer, according to an agronomist.

温度和盐度的显著变化出现在浅的、部分孤立的沿海水域，其变化程度远远超过可在公海内观测到的任何因素。

It is this symbol that makes flowcharts so valuable, because it directs us to different routes when necessary.

每一个人都应该清楚地知道，当他们驾车驶上高速公路时，他们应以什么速度驾驶汽车。

It isn’t Watt who invented the telephone.

这种庄稼长得不好，据一位农学家看一方面是由于品种，另一方面是由于追肥不匀。

It was for their discovering polonium and radium that Mrs. Curie and her husband were both awarded the Nobel Physics Prize in 1903.

正是这个符号赋予流程图以极大价值，因为它在必要时会把我们引向不同的路径。

It is only when particles are close enough to exert relatively large forces on one another that they are able to set each other into this type of vibration.

发明电话的并不是瓦特。

It is which experiment should be done first that they will discuss tomorrow.

正是由于发现了钋和镭，居里夫人和丈夫于1903年双双获得了诺贝尔物理学奖。

Why on earth is it that no one has received his inventive idea as scientific?

只有当粒子紧密到能够相互施加较大的力时，它们才能使彼此产生这样的振动。

What is more revolutionary is that the Web can lead to greater political involvement in decision making for ordinary people, via e-voting systems.

他们明天将要讨论的是应该先做哪一个试验。

What I should do next is to carry out the perfect plan.

没有人认为他的富有创造性的见解是科学的，这究竟是为什么？

Acupuncture is promoted as a treatment for pain—and there is absolutely no question that it does in fact provide short-term benefit for many of the people who try it.

更具革命性的是，万维网可以引导普通百姓借助于电子投票系统参与较为重大的政治决策。

This is because it was discovered ten years ago that some conjugated polymers exhibit electro-luminescence:

我们下一步应该做的就是执行这个完美的计划。

they glow when a voltage passes through them.

针灸现在越来越多地用于治疗疼痛—毫无疑问，事实上针灸的确为这一疗法的许多尝试者带来了短期效果。

The understanding of atmospheric processes, which is essential for successful prediction, also affords opportunities to modify weather deliberately for useful purposes and may make it possible to anticipate the inadvertent, deleterious effects before it is too late to avoid them.

例如，原来含有氢、氯、液态水三者的气态混合物系，就水蒸汽和液态水而言，很快便会趋达平衡，其间经由水的气化，直至其气相水蒸汽的分压与处于此物系温度下的液态水的蒸汽压大致相等为止。

In consequence of these forces, and the repulsive forces which occur between all ions or molecules when they get so close to one another that their electronic structures are in contact, the ions piled up together in a regular way, each sodium ion surrounding itself with six chloride ions as nearest neighbors, and keeping all other sodium ions somewhat farther away.

由于这些力的结果，也由于离子或分子相互之间十分靠近以致使其电子结构发生接触而产生排斥力的结果，离子以一种规则的方式聚集在一起，每个钠离子有六个氯离子作为最近的邻居环绕周围，但和其他钠离子保持较远一些的距离。

But even more interesting and significant facts have been disclosed by a study of the products formed by replacing one hydrogen atom of benzene by another atom or group.

用另一原子或基取代苯的一个氢原子就形成了一些产物，而对于这些产物的研究已揭示出一些更为有趣和有意义的事实。

To a greater extent than was formerly thought to be the case the monsoons appear to be in the nature of various kinds and degrees of modification of the general planetary wind system.

季风看来具有可对行星总风系进行各种各样、程度不一的调整的性质，这比以往更为可信。

There are swift flowing rivers, slow, sluggish rivers, mighty rivers with several mouths, rivers that carry vast loads of alluvium to the sea, clear, limpid rivers, rivers that at some seasons of the year have very much more water than at others.

有的河水流湍急，有的河流速缓慢，有的河波涛汹涌有好几处出海口，有的河带着大量冲击土入海，有的河清澈见底，有的河水量在一年中某些季节要远远多于其他季节。

New York City, which has turned its last 20 years of garbage into the highest peak on the Eastern Seaboard, in a Staten Island landfill that will soon run out of space, is preparing to spend $2.5 billion on the construction of eight trash-to-energy plants, and billions more to operate them.

纽约市过去20年里已经用它的垃圾把斯塔登岛填埋场堆积成东海岸最高的山峰，而且该填埋场很快就将没有空地了。

It would damage you at 20,000 feet up too, if you breathed it there, which is why jets flying through the ozone-rich upper atmosphere filter air through a catalytic converter before piping it to the passengers.

因此，该市正准备耗资25亿美元修建八座垃圾发电厂，并且打算再花费几十亿美元让这些发电厂投入运转。

One system for molecular modeling and for the computer-aided design of proteins, the Department of Molecular Biophysics and Biochemistry at Yale reported that an algorithm developed in collaboration with Frederic Richards has been quite successful in generating sequences of hydrophobic amino acids which will successfully pack to form the core of a protein with a specified backbone geometry.

要是在20 000英尺高空吸入臭氧，它也会对人造成伤害。

The voltage of a concentration cell depends on the greater tendency of copper ions, e.g., in the concentrated solution to deposit on copper, on account of the greater osmotic pressure, than copper ions in dilute solution.

正因为如此，喷气式飞机在穿越臭氧很多的大气层上部时，先让空气经过装有催化剂的转化器过滤，然后再通过管道输送给乘客。

Although modified, protein-sparing fasts are considered a reasonably safe way for the dangerously obese to quickly bring down their weight, this approach is no longer favored by most doctors due to the abrupt rebound that almost invariably occurs when the patient resumes eating.

据耶鲁大学分子生物物理学及生物化学系报道，该系与弗雷德里克·理查兹就分子模拟系统以及蛋白质计算机辅助设计系统进行合作，以推导出一种可以产生疏水性氨基酸序列的十分成功的算法，该序列将可成功地聚合生成具有一种特定主轴几何形状的蛋白核。

The efforts that have been made to explain optical phenomena by means of the hypothesis of a medium having the same physical character as an elastic solid body led, in the first instance, to the understanding of a concrete example of a medium which can transmit transverse vibrations, and at a later stage to the definite conclusion that there is no aluminiferous medium having the physical character assumed in the hypothesis.

与稀溶液的铜离子相比，浓溶液的铜离子因浓溶液的渗透压力较大而具有较大的沉积于铜极的倾向；而浓差电池的电压就决定于这一倾向。

At the turn of the century, the world underwent a new revolution driven by information technology and the Internet.Many developed countries have pumped a large amount of capital into the information sector to seek solutions.

尽管蛋白质禁食经过改进后被视为是一种可使过度肥胖者迅速消除体重的合理而安全的方法，但现在大部分医生不再偏爱这种方法。

In China, industrialization has not yet been realized and most companies are operating at a pretty low level of technology and management efficiency.

因为一旦患者恢复饮食，体重绝对会迅速反弹。

Information is at an early stage and information flows tend to be blocked, and also inaccurate.

为了解释光学现象，人们曾试图假设存在一种其物理性质与弹性固体相同的介质。

At present, most companies in China, in particular the China’s state-owned enterprises (SOEs), have retained traditional managerial styles and the organization.

这些努力最初曾使人们了解到一种能传输横向振动的介质，而后得出明确的结论，即不存在具有上述假设中假定的物理性质的含铝介质。

Management and flow of information cannot keep pace with the demands of the market economy, thus hindering economic restructuring and further development.

在世纪交替之际，世界经济经历了一场以信息技术和因特网为驱动力的新变革。

Massive efforts should be made to restructure China’s large and medium-sized SOEs by relying on information technology, particularly when the trade barriers protecting China’s native industry are tumbling down in line with its WTO membership.

许多发达国家将大量资金注入信息产业以寻求出路。

The technology allows the FM receiver to be in sleep mode most of time.

在中国，产业化还没有完全实现，大多数企业仍是在低效率的技术和管理水平上运作。

It will wake up at scheduled intervals to receive data, much like a modem, at 9 600 bits per second.

中国的信息化还处于初级阶段，信息流动往往会阻塞，而且还常常出现信息失真。

As the engine warms up so does the thermostat, and the wax inside the capsule begins to melt and expand.

当前中国的大部分企业，特别是国有企业，仍然保留着传统的管理模式和组织形式。

This expansion drives out the thrust pin, which opens the valve, allowing the hot water to pass through and back to the radiator.

企业的管理和信息的流通无法跟上市场经济的要求，从而阻碍了经济上的重组和进一步发展。

Sulphuric acid enters into the manufacture of explosives, dyestuffs and drugs; it is used in sugar refining and in the preparation of fertilizers.

重组中国的国有大中型企业需要经过大量的努力，这主要依靠信息技术，特别是在保护中国民族工业的贸易壁垒正按照WTO成员国的要求给以摧毁时，就更需要信息技术。

Until this year, scientists knew only of materials that would super-conduct at temperature impractically close to absolute zero.

这种调频接收机在大部分时间里处于休眠状态，只是在设定的时间段醒来，而且酷似调制解调器，以每秒9 600比特的速度接收数据。

A special, patented valve cover design permits all the securing bolts to be tightened equally with the prescribed tension without effort.

随着发动机升温，调节装置的温度也上升，密闭容器内的蜡就开始融化并膨胀，于是膨胀的蜡就会向外顶推止推杆而打开阀门，让热水通过，回到散热器。

But burning too much glucose can dangerously reduce the amount of glucose in the blood.

硫酸被用来制造炸药、燃料、药物、食糖和化肥等。

Where there is sound, there must be sound waves.

在今年以前，科学家们还只知道温度接近绝对零度时（这是不可能办到的）才能超导的材料。

The volume of a gas becomes smaller when the pressure upon it is increased.

阀盖结构特殊，享有专利权；不用费力就能将所有固定栓均匀拧紧，达到规定的拉力。

The finished products must be sampled to check their quality before they leave the factory.

可是，消耗过多的葡萄糖会减少血液中葡萄糖的含量，这是很危险的。

Rivets are permanent fasteners.

如果有声音，就一定有声波。

They depend on deformation of their structure for their holding action.

虽然出现了两种可选择的炼铁法，但预计它们在下一个10年或更长的时间呢不会对高炉的生产产生很大的冲击。

On some sites, this has mean the closure of one or more sinter plants and that the surviving plant must increase its productivity in order to satisfy blast furnace demands.

因此在将来的一段时期内烧结产品将保持在目前的水平。

The chamber formed by the top of the piston and the cylinder head must be virtually air tight for efficient engine operation.

在某些地方，这意味着会有一个或更多的烧结厂关闭，而生存下的烧结厂必须提高生产力以满足高炉的需要。

It is estimated that the new synergy between computers and Net technology will have significant influence on the industry of the future.

由活塞顶盖和气缸盖组成的燃烧室必须完全密封，这样发动机才能有效地运转。

The high-altitude plane was and still is a remarkable bird.

有人预测，新的电脑和网络技术的结合将会对未来工业产生巨大的影响。

It's time to ring farewell to the century of physics and ring in the century of biology.

高空飞机过去是而且现在仍然是一种了不起的飞行器。

High voltage is necessary for long transmission line while low voltage for safe use.

现在正是告别物理学世纪，迎接生物技术世纪的时候了。

Under no circumstances can more work be got out of a machine than is put into it.

远距离输电需要高压，安全用电需要低压。

This experimental result is in inverse ration to that.

旋动开关，就能轻而易举地启动照明装置，供热装置和电动装置。

The principal functions that may be performed by vacuum tubes are rectification, amplification, oscillation, modulation and detection.

真空管的五大功能是：整流、放大、震荡、调制和检波。

A reduction in condensation is achieved by the use of steam jackets.

使用蒸汽夹套可减少冷凝作用。

Rockets have found application for the exploration of the universe.

这个油桶可装10加仑油。

This oil tank has a capacity of ten gallons.

他精通化学。

He has a good knowledge of chemistry.

对确定最佳工艺流程而言，这次实验是绝对必需的。

This experiment is an absolute necessity in determining the best processing route.

这种合金能通过热处理获得良好的综合机械性能。

The combination of mechanical properties of this alloy can be well achieved by heat treatment.

这些材料的特点是：绝缘性好，耐磨性强。

Such materials are characterized by good insulation and high resistance to wear.

循环系统的功能就是把物质输送到身体各处。

The circulatory system functions to convey material from one part of the body to another.

沸点的定义就是气压等于大气压时的温度。

Boiling point is defined as the temperature at which the vapor pressure is equal to the atmospheric pressure.

铁具有多种性能，所以它已成为一般工程结构中的主要材料。

With its many characteristic properties iron has come to be the leading material for general engineering structures.

这部发电机可以给几部机器供电。

This motor can feed several machines.

我们用抽水机给锅炉加水。

We use pumps to feed fresh water into the boiler.

他们用自动加煤机给炉子填煤。

They use mechanical stockers to feed coal into the furnace.

我们可以用几种方法给轴承上油。

We can feed the oil into the bearing in several ways.

通过在炉壁周围使用耐火砖，热损失可以被大大降低。

The heat loss can be considerably reduced by the use of firebricks round the walls of the boiler.

商用食品贮存以及运输在美国极为普遍，人们难以想象若没有制冷这种技术美国会是怎样。

Commercial preservation and transport of food is so common that it would be difficult to imagine an unrefrigerated American.

这种机器可以连续运行五天。

This kind of machine can work in succession for five or six days.

许多舰艇装备着新式导航系统。

There are many naval vessels that are equipped with new navigation systems.

有人宣称，这种天然有机化合物可以通过人工合成。

It is claimed that natural organic compound can be synthesized by artificial process.

人们认为，大型电动机应该使用三相电流。

It is believed that Three-phase current should be used for large motors.

在大量抽取地下水的某些地区，地面下沉非常严重。

Surface subsidence was most serious in certain areas where large quantities of underground water were pumped out.

许多人造材料正在取代某些天然材料，这或者因为天然产品的数量不能满足人类不断增长的需要，或者更多地因为合成物（这是各种人造材料的统名称）的物理性能被选中，甚至受到极大的重视，因而使得它会在准备加以采用的领域获得最大量的应用。

Many man-made substances are replacing certain natural materials because either the quantity of the natural products cannot meet our ever-increasing requirement, or more often, because the physical properties of the synthetic substance, which is the common name for man-made materials, have been chosen, and even emphasized so that it would be of the greatest use in the field which it is to be applied.

各种机器零件，无论多么脏，不管形状多么不规则，当用超声波处理后，都可以清洗得非常干净，甚至像新零件一样。

Various machine parts can be washed very clean and will be as clean as new ones when they are treated by ultrasonics, no matter how dirty and irregularly shaped they maybe.

集成电路装置的尺寸特别小，这就又增加了一个很大的优点：可以在外界给它提供有效的核辐射屏障；这在以前由于重量或价格的限制是不可能做到的。

One of the significant fringe benefits of the remarkably small size of integrated circuit system is that effective external nuclear radiation shields are now feasible, where weight or cost ruled them out before.

承受的荷载与轴心线成直角的是径向轴承，而承受的荷载与轴心线相平行的是止准轴承，这是现代机器上使用的两种主要轴承。

Radial bearings which carry a load acting at right angles to the shaft axis, and thrust bearings which take a load acting parallel to the directions of shaft axis—are two main bearing used in modern machines.

一、本文所述及的，是有关矿物、水和能源等自然资源方面的问题。

This section deals with natural resources such as minerals, water and energy.

联合国成员国已大大地增强了在自然资源方面的各项活动，正力促把现代技术应用到资源开发上去。

The United Nations family has considerably increased its activities in the field of natural resources and is intensifying its efforts to secure the application of modern technology to resources development.

同时还探索着种种新的途径，比如把制订规划和彼此有联系、但又互有差别的各类资源的有关的研究结合起来。

New approaches are also being explored, such as the preparation of projections combining work on related but different groups of resources.

二、联合国秘书处正在为发展中国家派出的人员制订自然资源方面的训练计划。

The United Nations Secretariat is organizing training programs in the field of natural resources for personnel from developing countries, mostly through regional and inter-regional seminars.

计划主要是经由区域性的和跨区的讨论班，来付之实施的。

These seminars are also a useful means of transferring advances in technology to developing countries.

这类讨论班也是一种把先进技术传授到发展中国家去的有效方法。

The Secretary-General has prepared a five-year survey program which is designed to contribute to the development of natural resources by indicating economic and technologically-advanced approaches to the exploration and assessment of these resources.

讨论班有各种论题，比如与资源开发有关的制图学、海水淡化、能源政策，以及探矿中应用的地质化学技术等。

The proposed program consists of nine surveys in the fields of mineral resources, water resources, energy and electricity, as follows:

（1）矿物资源方面：调查发展区域内近海大陆架的矿藏；调查世界铁矿资源；调查重要的有色金属情况；调查发展中国家选定的矿山，要着眼于应用现代技术来找出矿物的新贮藏量，并提高其产量。

In the fields of water resources, a survey of water needs and water resources in potentially water-short developing countries and a survey of the potential for development in international rivers.

（2）水资源方面：调查有可能缺水的那些发展中国家的需水情况和水资源；调查国际河流的开发潜力。

(c) In the field of energy and electricity, a survey of potential geothermal energy resources in developing countries, a survey of oil shale resources and a survey of the needs for small-scale power generation in developing countries.

（3）能源和电力方面：调查发展中国家潜在的地热能源；调查油页岩资源；调查发展中国家对小型发电设备的需求情况。

Each of the nine proposed surveys would have two objectives:

四、上面所提出的九项调查，每一项都有两个目的：其一是对每个有关的发展中国家的自然资源潜力，提供具有重大意义的新情报、新见解和新方法；二是搜集数据。

first, to provide significant new information, ideas and approaches on the natural resources potential of each developing country concerned, and secondly, to gather data that would produce a world-wide perspective of the long-term potential available and needs in the selected areas.

这些数据，从该选定区域长期的潜在效力和需求来看，可能出现一种具有全球意义的远景前程。

They should also be useful in preparing and selecting projects for submission to multilateral or bilateral sources of technical and financial aid.

上述九项调查，在准备和选定项目时，对于提出多边或双边技术援助和财政援助的要求，也会是有用的。

A warm air furnace is a device in which gaseous or liquid fuel is directly fired or electric resistance heaters are used to heat the warm supply air.

暖风炉是一种加热空气的设备，它通过气体或液体燃料直接燃烧，或电阻式加热器来加热空气。

A hot water boiler is an enclosed pressure vessel used as a heat source for space heating in which water is heated to a required temperature and pressure without evaporation.

热水锅炉是一种用作房间供热热源的密闭式的压力容器，它可以把水加热到需要的温度和压力而不引起汽化。

A low-pressure warm air heating system is often equipped with an upflow gas-fired furnace having a furnace heat capacity Qf to air flow ratio Va, Qf/Va, of 50 to 70 Btu/hr. cfm

红外线供热是利用燃气式电加热设备，通过辐射换热对房间局部进行供热的一种供热方式，它可以为居住者提供健康、舒适的生活环境，或者根据生产工艺要求来维持适当的工作环境。

Infrared heating is a process that uses radiant heat transfer from a gas-fired or electrically heated high temperature device to provide space heating on a localized area for the health and comfort of the occupants or to maintain a suitable indoor environment for a manufacturing process.

热量散发是通过向与散热表面接触的空气传热以及由此引起的空气循环而达到的。

The balance of the emission is by conduction to the air in contact with the heating surface, and the resulting circulation of the air warms by convection.

每节有7/4英寸间隔的小管散热器是现在盛行的样式。

The small-tube radiator with spacings of 7/4—in per section is now the prevailing type.

试图通过给铸铁散热器上油漆、加罩或者把它们放置于墙上凹处来改善它们外观的做法，也降低了它们的供热选择。

Attempts to improve the appearances f cast-iron radiators by painting them, covering them, or recessing them in walls also succeed in reducing their heating efficiency.

全面排气通风也称为稀释通风，它不同于局部排气通风，因为后来是 从污染源补集散发的粉尘并将之从空气中除去；而前者则允许污染物散发到工作区空气中，然后将其浓度稀释至可接受程度。

General exhaust ventilation, also called dilution ventilation, is different from local exhaust ventilation because instead of capturing emissions at their source and removing them from the air, general exhaust ventilation allows the contamination to be emitted into the workplace air and then dilutes the contaminant to be emitted into the workplace air and then dilutes the concentration of the contaminant to an acceptable level.

为了获得通过其他开口或排气罩部位的最小接受速度，应避免将通过某些开口的速度设计过高。

Avoid designs that requires that the velocities through some openings be very high in order to develop the minimum acceptable velocity through other openings or parts of the hood.

置换空气可通过开着的门、窗、天窗、邻近空间（有组织进风）；墙和窗上的缝隙、门下的缝隙及屋顶通风孔（无组织进风）在大气压力的作用下自然补充。

Replacement air can be supplied naturally by atmospheric pressure through open doors, windows, wall louvers, and adjacent spaces (acceptable), as well as through cracks in walls and windows, beneath doors and through roof vents (unacceptable).

当聚积在排气罩下方的污染空气量比能被排气罩排出的量大时，多余的空气会从罩下边缘逸出污染工业区。

When some contaminated air collects under the hood than can be removed by it, the air flows from under the brim and contaminates the work area.

在这种情况下，如果没有排气罩反而更好些，因为如果污染空气的密度低于周围空气的密度值，那么这些气体就会上升，并且在由于循环作用最终返回到工作区后，会比留在满的排气罩时由于得到稀释而浓度更小，污染程度更小。

In this case, it would be much better if there were no hood at all because if the density of the contaminated air were less that of the surrounding air, it would then be more diluted and less contaminated than when it left the over-filled hood.

顶棚散流器可能是商用建筑中最常用的气流传输分布设备。

Ceiling diffusers are probably the most common types of ATDS used for air distribution in commercial building.

方形及矩形顶棚散热器可以单面、双面、三面出风，且可以用作补风。

Square and rectangular ceiling diffusers are available in one-, two- and three-way discharge and can be used for supply of extraction.

条缝形散热器有单条缝出口型或多条缝出口型，能连续排成线形横穿顶棚或沿顶棚周边环形布置。

Slot diffusers are available as single or multiple slot outlets and can be used to provide a continuous strip across a ceiling or on the perimeter of a ceiling.

该条缝送风散热器的主要特点是空气输送能力强，流速减少时有改变流态能力，有良好的工作性能，这就使得这种散流器在变风量系统中有吸引力。

The main characteristics of the supply slot diffusers are high air-handling capacity, variable flow pattern capability and good performances at reduced flow rates, which makes them attractive for Variable Air Volume (VAV) systems.

空气调节就是为了保证人体健康和舒适或满足生产工艺要求，将室内空气进行处理并分配送入室内，同时控制并维持室内空气的温度、湿度、流动速度、洁净度、噪声水平及压力，使之达到预先设定的范围。

Air-conditioning is a process that simultaneously conditions air; distributes it combined with the outdoor air to the conditioned space; and at the same time controls and maintains the required space’s temperature, humidity, air movement, air cleanliness, sound level, and pressure differential within predetermined limits for the health and comfort of the occupants, for product processing, or both.

整体式空调系统中，空气主要通过盘管内制冷剂的直接蒸发进行冷却，考燃气炉、电加热器或热泵（采用的是制冷循环的反过程）进行加热。

In a packaged system, air is cooled mainly by direct expansion of refrigerant in coils called DX coils and heated by gas furnace, electric heating, or a heat pump effect, which is the reverse of a referageration cycle.

空气调节过程描述的是湿空气在调解初阶段与末阶段之间的热力学特性，以及湿空气与媒质之间相应的能与质的交换，这些媒质包括水、制冷剂、吸收剂、吸附剂或湿空气本身。

An air-conditioning process describes the change in thermodynamic properties of moist air between the initial and final stages of conditioning as well as the corresponding energy and mass transfers between the moist air and a medium, such as water, refrigerant, absorbent or adsorbent, or moist air itself.

蒸汽将热量传送至压缩机，在压缩机中被压缩，将其温度提高至比室外空气温度更高的值。

The vapor then carries the heat to the compressor, which compresses the vapor and increases its temperature to a value higher than the temperature of the outdoor air.

这里考虑到实际应用，假定物质是连续的，也就是说，对于一个含有大量分子的无穷小的体积来说，可以认为空气动力学特性（例如密度）是有效的。

In the applications considered here, the materials are assumed to behave as a continuum:that is, the smallest volume considered contains enough molecules so that thermodynamic properties (e.g., density) are valid.

气体中，寻热是通过分子间的弹性碰撞引起的；而液体和绝缘的固体中，它是通过晶架结构的纵向振荡产生的。

In gases, conduction is caused by elastic collision of molecules; in liquids and electrically nonconducting solids, it is believed to be caused by longitudinal oscillations of the lattice structure.

虽然一些通用的传热系数关系式已经通过运用基本原理以数学方式推导出来了，但它们往往来源于相关的实验数据。

Although some generalized heat transfer coefficient correlations have been mathematically derived from fundamentals, they are often obtained from correlations of experimental data.

正如Bergles（1998，2001）说得那样，强化传热的技术应用可分为无缘强化（无需内热源）和有源强化（需内热源）两种形式。

As discussed by Bergles (1998, 2001), techniques applied to augment (enhance) heat transfer can be classified as passive (requiring no direct application of external power) or active (requiring external power).

它们可以由防腐材料做成[例如，当冷却气体流（烟气余热回收）时可能会酸性冷凝]，并且很容易被加工成增强效果的表面。

They could be made of materials impervious to corrosion [e.g., by acid condensate when cooling a gaseous stream (flue gas heat recovery)], and could easily be manufactured with enhanced surfaces.

这反过来需要一些更精小（联机的）的紧凑型换热器，和可以响应瞬态系统需求的热管理系统。

This in turn will require smart (on-line/on-demand), compact heat exchangers and thermal management systems that can respond to transient system needs.

我们有可能在事件并没有发生时，用数学的方法预测事件的过程，或者用数学的方法研究事件的各个方面，而不进行费钱又费时的实验。

This makes it possible to predict the course of an event mathematically without actually occurs, or to study aspects of an event mathematically without actually running expensive and time-consuming experiments.

卡诺循环完全可逆，是一个理想的制冷循环模式，它运行在两个固定温度或两种不同且热容量无限大的流体之间。

The Carnot Cycle, which is completely reversible, is a perfect model for a refrigeration cycle operating between two fixed temperature, or between two fluids at different temperatures and each with infinite heat capacity.

由于考虑到初始投资以及维护费用增加等原因，实际的制冷机组采用一个压缩机代替两个压缩机，并采用简单的膨胀阀代替膨胀机将高压制冷剂节流至低压制冷剂。

Because of concerns such as initial cost and increased maintenance requirements, a practical machine has one compressor instead of two and the expander is replaced by a simple expansion valve, which throttles refrigerant from high to low pressure.

采用两级小型压缩机通常比使用一台大型压缩机更为有效，这样涵盖了整个从冷凝压力变化至蒸发压力的范围。

Two small compressor in series have a smaller displacement and usually operate more efficiently than one large compressor that covers the entire pressure range from the evaporator to the condenser.

当使用多级压缩机时，两个压缩机之间的蒸汽应该进行冷却，保证进入下一级压缩机的蒸汽为饱和蒸汽。

When compressor are connected in services, the vapor between stages should be cooled to bring the vapor to saturated conditions before proceeding to the next stage of compression.

共沸混合物是由多种制冷剂混合而成的，它能像纯物质一样蒸发或冷凝而不改变其体积成分，在常压下蒸发或冷凝时其饱和温度也不改变。

An azeotropic is a mixture of multiple components of volatilities (refrigerants) that evaporate and condense as a single substance and do not change in volumetric composition or saturation temperature when they evaporate or condense at constant pressure.

Wyeth发明一种切出相同冰块的方法，此方法既快速又便捷，从而使制冰也突变，同时此方法也减少了仓储业、运输业和销售业由于管理技术所造成的损失。

Wyeth devised a method of quickly and cheaply cutting uniform blocks of ice that transformed the ice industry, making it possible to speed handling techniques in storage, transportation and distribution with less waste.

如果在吸收辐射热之前，楼板与房间内空气处于热平衡状态，热量就会以对流换热的形式传递到室内，同时向其他表面辐射。

If the slab and space air are in thermal equilibrium before the absorption of radiative heat, heat is convected from the outer surface of the slab to the space air as well as radiated to other surface.

渗透是指由于压差，室外空气通过维护结构的缝隙进入室内的现象，渗透不可控制。

Infiltration is the uncontrolled inward flow of unconditioned outdoor air through cracks and openings on the building envelope because of the pressure difference across the envelope.

像水蒸气、氨蒸气这样的这样的蒸气，由于它们易液化，而与其他气体不一样。

A vapor, such as steam or ammonia, differs from a gas by being readily condensable to a liquid.

图7.1（b）表示出一个和黏性剪力有关的速度梯度的简单例子，包括x方向上的流动速度以及y方向上流动速度的变化量。

The velocity gradient associated with viscous shear for a simple case involving flow velocity in the x direction but of varying magnitude in the y direction is illustrated in Figure 7.1 (b).

分析证明，因为较大的紊流动能，紊流边界层比层流边界层更不易分离的实验观察是正确的。

Analyses verify the experimental observation that a turbulent boundary layer is less subject to separation than a laminar one because of its greater kinetic energy.

具体来说，如果没有质量堆积和丢失（如渗出），质量流量比率必须在管道内部与管道外部一致。

Specifically, the mass flow rate into a section of pipe must equal the mass flow rate out of that section of pipe if no mass is accumulated or lost (e.g. from leakage).

流体流动通常都是紊乱的，含有随机扰动或脉动（速度和压强），它们有极其广泛的频率和层次。

Fluid flows are generally turbulent, involving random perturbations or fluctuations of the flow (velocity and pressure), characterized by an extensive hierarchy of scales or frequencies.

流体动力学这一科学起源于古代中国、埃及、美索不达米亚和印度，它随着水力灌溉和航行实际应用中需要对水进行控制而出现。

The science of fluid mechanics began with the need to control water for irrigation and navigation purposes in ancient China, Egypt, Mesopotamia, and India.

在十九世纪，在对待流体机械问题上，形成了两种思想流派，一种是理论流体力学，一种是试验流体力学。

In the nineteenth century, two schools of thoughts arose in the treatment of fluid mechanics, one dealing with the theoretical and the other with practical aspects of fluid now.

空气污染物主要分为粒状和气态两种。

The major classes of air contaminants are particulate and gaseous.

颗粒物包括的粒径范围很广，从大到可见的粉尘到大部分过滤器都无法过滤的亚微观粒子。

The particulate class covers a vast range of particle sizes from dust large enough to be visible to the eye to submicroscopic particles that elude most filters.

关系到人体健康的生物气溶胶直径变化为0.5～30μm，但是由于大量细胞和孢子的凝聚，细菌和真菌气溶胶的直径范围一般为2～8μm。

Bioaerosols of concern to human health range from 0.5 to 30μm in diameter, but generally bacterial and fungal aerosols range from 2 to 8μm in diameter because of agglomeration or rafting of cells or spores.

空气中具有传染性的微粒本身与其他含有气溶胶的颗粒大小、密度和静电荷都一样。

Airborne infectious particles behave physically in the same way as any other aerosol-containing particles with similar size, density, and electrostatic charge.

通常这种研究考察的是某一具体污染物和居住者健康之间的联系，在某些特定的条件下，这种联系是明确的，例如石棉、ETS、PM、HCHO等，但是大多数情况下，并不能建立这种联系。

Usually such studies investigate a link between specific pollutant and occupant health effects.In certain cases such a link is clear, see asbestos, ETS, PM, HCHO and others, but in most cases such links cannot be established.

针对室内空气问题的小型项目是对现有工作的一种重复，它应该是IAQ学科第一阶段的工作，而这一阶段的任务现在应该已经完成了。

Small projects that attempt to establish an indoor problem are duplication of existing work, they reflect efforts of staged of the IAQ science, a stage that has been completed.

我们有一个充满希望的未来，因为过去的事实表明IAQ学者们是努力而专注的。

The future is promising because the recent past indicates that IAQ scientists are both studious and dedicated.

空气采样可以用来确定覆盖某限定时间段的时间加权平均（TWA）暴露值，也可以用来确定短期暴露值，该短期暴露值可确定极其危险物质的暴露数量。

Air sampling can be conducted to determine time-weighted average (TWA) exposures, which covers a defined period of time; or short-term exposures, which determine the magnitude of exposures to materials that are acutely hazardous.

由于大部分热量都是通过体表散发到环境中，因此，通常用单位体表的产热量表示人体的能量代谢率。

Because most of this is transferred to the environment through the skin, it is often convenient to characterize metabolic activity in terms of heat production per unit area of skin.

暴露的危险程度取决于生物危害物的性质和效力，以及暴露数量和持续时间。

The degree of risk from exposure depends on the nature and potency of the biological hazard, and the magnitude and duration of exposure.

由于标准偏差只有0.6K，所以Fanger得出结论：个体的舒适条件每日重复，可能会有微小的变化。

Because the standard deviation was only 0.6K, Fanger concluded that comfort conditions for an individual can be reproduced and will vary only slightly from day to day.

根据统计数据，大多数人90%的时间都是在建筑物内度过的，如今正是各学会和工程圈在整个建筑物设计中重新布置建筑设备工程的适当时机。

According to statistical data, most people spend 90% of their time in buildings, it is the suitable time for societies and projecting circles to relocate building equipment engineering in the whole building design.

老式建筑中仅有一些非常简单的监控系统，只能监控一些简单室内参数，对室内环境质量的判断还是根据人们的感觉。

There ever have been some simple monitoring systems for indoor environment in which only few parameters can be measured, but the evaluation and judgment of environment quality are still based on people’s feeling.

需要注意的是，合理组织的气流不仅仅是影响舒适性的重要因素，同时也是节能最便捷的方式。

What must be attentive are well-organized airflow is not only important factor to impact on thermal comfort, but also most convenient means to save energy.

他提出一种既能制冷又能供热的系统，压缩机在该系统中，不是靠燃烧燃料直接供热，而是间接提供热量。

He proposed a system capable of both heating and cooling in which a compressor would be used as a means of providing indirect heat, instead of equipment that burned a combustible fuel directly.

根据需求进行供热/制冷的双向转换是依靠人工完成的，这需要经验丰富的技工对阀门进行多次开或关，以完成供热/制冷的双向转换。

The reversing action needed to provide heating or cooling on demand was carried out manually, and required the services of experienced mechanics to open or close the dozen or valves that allowed for the shift from heating to cooling and then back again.

经过十多年的研究和开发，热泵设备的性能更加可靠有效，尤为重要的是其运行费用比传统的供热系统低得多。

The research and development, which took place over a decade, has resulted in the manufacture of heat pump equipment that is considered to be reliable and efficient, and more importantly, costs considerably less to operate than conventional heating.

现有燃炉匠成为“备用”系统，只有在温度降低于热泵有效运行温度点以下时，或者热泵损坏需要维修时使用。

The existing furnace will become a “back-up” system, which is only used when temperatures fall below the point where the operation of the heat pump is efficient, or when the heat pump breaks down and needs servicing.

即使现有的井可以利用，也必须采用能使水回灌到地下这种令人满意的方式，通常采用回灌井这种方式。

Also, even if an existing well is utilized, a satisfactory means of delivery the discharge water back to the ground must be available, usually in the form of a discharge well.

然而，从水源热泵系统设计角度很难估计实际能耗，于是为了证实对于给定的气候地区水源热泵是最优的采暖方式，必须计算冬季的能耗。

However, from the SWHP system design standpoint, it is very difficult to estimate the actual energy consumption, thus in order to prove the SWHPs are the optimal heating solution for the given climatic area, the energy consumption in winter have to be computed.

供暖季节水温平均值为9.7℃，比气温平均值高出3.5℃，说明水体较空气热量资源更为丰富。

The average water temperature throughout the winter is 9.7℃, which is 3.5℃ higher than ambient air, indicating that heat resource contained in water body is much more abundant than in ambient air.

服务人员必须具备以下资格：能维修或更换机械和电子元件，能正确回收并处理从系统中导出的制冷剂。

Service personnel must be qualified to repair or replace mechanical and electrical components and to recover and properly recycle or dispose of any refrigerant removed from a system.

额定值是在ARI标准标定条件下、额定名牌电压和额定蒸发器风量不超过每千瓦60L/s时送风管静压下确定的。

Ratings are determined at ARI standard rating conditions, rated nameplate voltage, and prescribed discharge duct static pressures with rated evaporator airflow not exceeding 60L/s per kilowatt.

在分区方面，变风量系统可提供良好的灵活性并且能方便地增容、压缩、调整或关闭部分设备而对中央设备无任何程度的影响。

VAV systems can provide excellent flexibility in zoning and can easily be expanded or contracted, rearranged, or particularly shut down without affecting the central equipment to any degree.

自从变风量系统被构思和开始应用以来，在过去几年中，麻烦的事变风量系统一直存在着问题，这些问题并非已经100%解决或能轻易地被控制。

In the bad news department there have been problems over the past years since the conception and inception of VAV systems, not all of which have been 100% resolved or are very easy to control.

最好是在或靠近设计人员为风机速度自动调节用压力传感器所规定的位置上，也可以在接近风机的末端上进行静压检测，以防止系统原部件的压力过大。

The static pressure checks should preferably be made at, or close to, the position specified by the designer for the pressure sensor for automatic regulation of fan speed, and also at terminals near to the fans, to prevent over-pressurization of system components.

高质量塑料管的出现使得在地板采暖系统中使用低温水成为可能，地板采暖系统完全可以和新热源技术配伍。

The advent of high quality plastics pipes has made possible the utilization of how temperature wager in floor heating system perfectly compatible with the new heat source technology.

地板采暖系统已完全发展成为适合于各种地板结构的采暖形式，把传导、辐射、对流等所有传热方式结合起来，从而适应整个建筑物内理想温度梯度内的要求。

Fully developed for all types of floor construction, U.F.H. combines all types of heat, conduction, radiation and convection, matching the ideal temperature gradient throughout an entire building.

以上概述的地板采暖系统是专门开发用于低级（能源）供热系统。

The floor heating systems outlined above were developed specifically for low grade heating systems.

一些相对新的热源技术在向市场渗透的过程中 阻碍，这是由于它们常常与不恰当的配热系统相连接。

The market penetration of a number of relatively new heating source technologies is being by the fact that they are often interfaced with unsuitable heating distribution systems.

系统热阻随着铝片厚度的增加以及管子间距的减少而减小。

The system’s thermal resistance decreases with increasing aluminum thickness and decreasing pipe spacing.

反之，投资和安装费用就会增加。

Conversely, the capital and installation costs increase.

无论加热器怎样设计，加热水的传热问题就是一定量的热由高温烟气通过金属壁而传递给水的传输过程。

The heat transfer problem in heating water, no matter what the design of the heater, is the transmission of the required amount of heat from hot combustion gases through a metal wall into the water.

应该安装测定集热器出口处传热流体温度的传感器，以便感测流体平均温度，并且能够感测流体是否正在水泵作用下循环。

The sensor, which measures the temperature of the heat transfer fluid at the collector outlet, should be installed so it can sense the average fluid temperature and sense it whether or not the fluid is being circulated by the pump.

新能源的不断开发以及对外星球环境的改造的能力也许会使生活在月球或其他行星上成为可能。

New sources of energy are being developed, and these together with the capacity to manipulate alien environments may make life possible on the moon or other planets.

有些问题具有深奥的伦理道德含义，比如基因操控、器官移植及延续本该结束的生命的能力等问题。

Some have profound ethical implications, e.g, those associated with gene manipulation, organ transplantation, and the capacity to sustain life beyond the point at which it once would have ended.

再者，除机器外，技术还包括技艺，即制作方法，而这些技艺、方法的运用并不一定都要机器。

Moreover, technology includes techniques, or ways to do things, as well as the machines that may or may not be necessary to apply them.

因此，正如人们常常提到的，一个千真万确的情况是，从古到今的科学家中有90%的人活在今天的世界上，新的科学发现现在天天都有。

Thus it is not merely true, as frequently noted, that 90 percent of all the scientists who ever lived are now alive, and that new scientific discoveries are being made every day.

这些因素带来了冶金技术的发展，如铜和青铜的冶炼技术。

These combined factors made possible the development of metal smelting, with copper and later bronze, being the meals of choice.

当今世界，科学技术与商业贸易的联系越来越紧密。

We are in a world now where science and commerce are increasingly bedfellows.

科技的发展正式在科技发展与商业的结合被看成本质上是一件好事的全球自由贸易体系的大环境下进行的。

The development of technology is happening in the context of global free trade regimes which see technological diffusion embedded with commerce as intrinsically a good.

直到不久以前，西方人都普遍认为，古代中国的科学和技术铜欧洲相比是微不足道的。

Until relatively recently the general belief in the West was that the science and technology which had existed in traditional China was of relatively little importance compared with that of Europe.

近一百年来的发展使印刷工业发生了革命性的变化。

Developments in the last 100 years have revolutionized the printing industry.

印刷经历了由艺术到科学，由手工艺到工业技术的转化，但是印刷术的发展还没有终结。

Printing has changed from an art to science, from a craft to a technology.But the development of printing is not over yet.

为了满足人们进行信息传播的需要，新材料、新设备及新工艺正被源源不断地制造出来。

New materials, machines, and methods are constantly being invented in order to satisfy man’s need to communicate.

爆炸背后的科学原理是相当简单的。

The scientific principle behind explosives is simple enough.

固体混合物剧烈燃烧产生大量气体，这些气体因反应所产生的热量而迅速膨胀。

A mixture of solids must burn vigorously to produce a large volume of gas, which rapidly expands from the heat of the reaction.

这表明数学当时已经被应用于我们所称的科学工作中，而且许多希腊的科学工作都是围绕着数学而展开的。

This example illustrates the use of mathematics in what we would call scientific work, and this emphasis on mathematics was central to much of Greek science.

于是，在数学物理课程中就可以这门课程为背景，对应用实例进行介绍，学生们就能够透彻地了解其中的数学知识。

Then, with this as a background, the applications can be presented in the mathematical physics course, and the students will be capable of understanding thoroughly the mathematics involved.

不管是好是坏，数学似乎与军事技术已结成了不解之缘。

For better or worse, mathematics appears linked inexorably with military technology.

而具有特殊意义的事，涉及到力对物体的形状和运动的效应的那些定律，因为这些原理可应用于诸如机器、建筑物和桥梁等设备和结构上。

Of special interest are the laws dealing with the effects of forces upon the form and motion of objects, since these principles apply to all devices and structures such as machines, buildings and bridges.

光电技术使电视、有线或无线图像传播、有声电影以及许多用电来控制机器设备的装置成为可能。

Photoelectricity makes possible television, transmission of pictures by wire or radio, sound motion pictures, and many devices for the control of machinery.

在美国和欧洲也有相似的项目正在进行。

Similar programs are under way in the United States and Europe.

虽然电缆铺设完毕，但是，直到1866年，这条线路才得以持久可靠地运行。

The cable was laid, but not until 1866 was the connection made permanent and reliable.

海洋学家

oceanographer

海底摄影

underwater photography

海洋生物

marine life

夹着冰雹的暴风雨

hailstorm

他们形成数字模式—代表大气过程的系列等式—并在超级计算机上运行，分析和预测大气从雨滴的形成到整个地球大气的环流的每个层次上的行为。

They develop numerical models—sets of equations that represent atmospheric process—and run them on supercomputers to analyze and predict the behavior of the atmosphere on every scale from the formation of raindrops to the circulation of the atmosphere on every scale from the formation of raindrops to the circulation of the atmosphere over the entire earth.

（来回）摆动；（上下）波动

oscillation

浓缩，聚集

concentration

量值，大小

magnitude

人为地

artificially

预告者，前兆

harbinger

瘟疫

plague

小行星

asteroid

赤道地区

equatorial region

一氧化氮

nitrogen oxide

媒介传播的

vector-borne

中暑

heat stroke

二氧化硫

sulphur dioxide

数月前在海牙进行的减少5%的温室气体排放的谈判失败了。

Talks to cut emissions by five percent collapsed in The Hague several months ago.

报告警告说，如若地球温度气温升高5.8℃，随着海洋变暖和极地冰帽的融化，将导致海平面升高3英尺，几千万的孟加拉人和埃及人将无家可归，部分英国低地也面临着同样的危险。

The report warns that a temperature rise of up to 5.8℃, with the warming of the oceans and melting of polar icecaps, will force sea levels to rise by as much as 3 feet, making tens of millions of people in Bangladesh and Egypt homeless.Parts of lowland Britain are also at risk.

气温的升高将部分地归咎于对污染的清除。

A pollution clean-up will be partly to blame for such a temperature rise.

引起酸雨的二氧化硫气体排放的减少，增加了温室气体的影响。

A reduction in emissions of sulphur dioxide, which causes acid rain, has increased the impact of greenhouse gases.

这些气体阻隔了阳光中的热量，而二氧化硫起到使空气变凉的作用。

These gases trap the sun’s heat whereas sulphur dioxide cools the atmosphere.

两栖动物

amphibian

爬行动物

reptile

保温气体

heat-trapping gases

这份报道称人们的活动在一定程度上导致了温室效应。

The report says human activities are partly responsible for the warming temperatures.

气候的变化威胁着当地居民的生活以及当地的经济和环境。

The climate changes threaten people’s lives, the local economy and the environment.

演绎法

induction method

光合作用

photosynthesis

形态相似

physical resemblance

亚马逊河

the Amazon

原生质

protoplasm

渐渐消逝

fade away

细胞学

cytology

组织学

histology

解剖学

anatomy

形态学

morphology

生理学

physiology

胚胎学

embryology

遗传学

genetics

古生物学

paleontology

分类学

taxonomy

生理化学

physiological chemistry

生物气候学

bioclimatology

生物地理学

biogeography

生态学

ecology

生物工程

bioengineering

生物统计学

biostatistics

生物力能学

bioenergetics

微生物学

microbiology

心理学

psychology

细菌学

bacteriology

人类学

anthropology

现代动物学的研究范畴不仅仅集中在对细胞、其各个组成部分和功能的研究，以及拓展细胞学、生理学和生物化学的知识，而且还探索诸如心理学、人类学和生态学等其他学科领域。

Modern zoology has not only concentrated on the cell, its parts and functions, and on expanding the knowledge of cytology, physiology, and biochemistry, but it has also explored such areas as psychology, anthropology, and ecology.

从那时起，人类的生活依赖于对某些植物的控制生产，而不是依赖于从野生的浩繁品种中点滴采撷，其结果则是，在千万年间对野生植物的经验和亲密接触所积累的知识，也就随之逐渐衰减了。

From then on, humans increasingly take their living from the controlled production of a few plants, rather than getting a little here and a little there from many varieties that grew wild—and the accumulated knowledge of tens of thousands of years of experience and intimacy with plants in the wild would begin to fade away.

人类基因工程即人们熟知的基因疗法，是基于我们的基因是我们肌体的防御和治疗系统这一前提的。

Human genetic engineering, also known as gene therapy, is based on the premise that our genes are the defense and healing system of our body.

第二种应用基因治疗疾病的方法，那就是人们所了解的小分子治疗的方法。

The second way to exploit genes to treat disease is known as small-molecule therapy.

在这一研究中，一种小分子（即一种药）可以提供给病人来修改病人体内一个或几个基因。

In this approach, a small molecule (that is, a drug) is given to the patient to modify the function of one or more genes in the body.

医药和生物技术公司，正在对这两种方法进行大量的投资。

Pharmaceutical and biotech companies are investing heavily in both of these approaches.

必然性

inevitability

基因学研究从来没有这样包罗万象，以至于可以涵盖从医学到社会学的每一门学科。

The study of genetics will never be so all encompassing as to gobble up every subject from medicine to sociology.

然而，科学解释的基因信息越多，我们就越了解环境的重要性。

Instead, the more science learns about genes, the more we will learn about the importance of the environment.

这一点同样适用于真实生活：基因缺失非常重要，但它并不是生命的全部。

That goes for real life, too:genes are essential but not the whole story.

DNA重组最重要的实际价值将是得到人类基因和染色体的最新认识。

The most important practical benefit from recombinant-DNA research will be new knowledge about human genes and chromosomes.

它使疾病的诊断、预防和治愈更加合理且有效，给我们用健康基因代替有毛病的基因来治疗某些遗传疾病带来了希望。

This will make the diagnosis, prevention and cure of disease more rational and effective and gives us the hope of curing certain genetic diseases by replacing faulty genes with healthy ones.

很多科学家都相信人的细胞里DNA和RNA遭受破坏可能是正常细胞转化成癌细胞的关键因素。

Many scientists are convinced that damage to DNA and RNA in human cells may be the key factor in the transformation of normal cells into cancer cells.

科学家们还怀疑，带有插入基因的食物改善了它们某一方面的性质，是不是在其他方面也无害呢？其一是这些基因可能引起人们对以前那种食物从没有过的过敏反应。

Scientists are also questioning whether foods with a gene inserted to improve one area of their performance could prove detrimental in another:For one thing, the genes might cause allergic reactions in people who never had a reaction to that before.

随着克隆人类的指日可待，是禁止克隆还是调控克隆已列入美国国家伦理学议事日程。

With the cloning of humans within reach, whether it is to be banned or regulated is now on the nation’s moral agenda.

此时此刻，生物技术领域的最新成就似乎已经成为每个人应思考的问题。

For the moment it seems that the latest achievement in the biotech field has provided everyone with food for thought.

直到18世纪人类才认识到，整个大脑都参与了思想活动。

It was not until the 18th century that man realized that the whole of the brain was involved in the workings of the mind.

人们发现，一个智力上一直活跃的老人，他的头脑比只干体力活的年轻人更敏捷。

It has been found that an old person who has always been mentally active has a quicker mind than a young person who has dome only physical work.

现在人们认为，我们让脑子工作得越多，它就能干更多的工作。

It is now thought that the more work we give our brains, the more work they are able to do.

人造卫星的出现并没有使垂直探测火箭过时，外层空间探测器和月球探测器与卫星的关系更是如此。

The availability of artificial satellites does not make does not make vertical sounding rockets obsolete and this is even more true of deep space and lunar probes in relation to artificial satellites.

跟踪站

tracking station

监测站

monitoring station

观测船

tracking ship

气象卫星

meteorological satellite

地球同步轨道卫星

geostationary satellite

导航卫星

navigation satellite

火箭发射器

rocket launcher

太阳能电池板

solar panel

太空舱

capsule

轨道舱

orbital module

返回舱

re-entry capsule

服务舱

service module

尿样检验

urine test

周三的发射任务显示了中国政府实施空间计划的双重目的—在进行科学探索的同时赢得国际国内声誉。

The fact that Wednesday's mission carried two astronauts reflects the twin purposes of China’s space program, which aims for both scientific gains and kudos at home and abroad.

电子脉冲

electric pulse

数字分析

numerical analysis

微处理器

microprocessor

批量生产

mass production

尖端，新领域

frontier

计算机网络

computer network

无限性

unlimitability

分时系统

time-sharing systems

阴极射线管

cathode-ray tube

要对分时这个要领做很简明的介绍不是件容易的事情，因为这个术语已经变得非常笼统，以致对几十个利益团体以及这些团体里智力水平高低不一的人来说，它具有各种各样不同的意义。

A very brief conceptual introduction to time sharing is not an easy task because the term has already become so generalized that it has a great variety of meanings to scores of interesting groups and wide ranges f intelligence levels in such groups.

热传动

heat transfer

材料特性

properties of materials

正如在其他领域一样，在机械工程中，能够采取重要的出人意料的并能开创出新方法的能力，仍然具有个人的、即兴的特点。

The ability to take the important and unexpected step that opens up new solutions remains in mechanical engineering, as elsewhere, largely a personal and spontaneous characteristics.

工程制图，工程图

engineering drawing

剖视图，截面图

sectional viewmechanical drawing

机械图，机械制图

fabricating material

制作材料，装配材料

on-the-job training

岗位培训

sewer system

驱动这些机器的动力装置是一台50马力的感应电动机。

The power unit for driving the machines is a 50-hp induction motor.

这里我们将提及两种温标:华氏温标和摄氏温标。

We shall mention here two temperature scales, namely, the Fahrenheit scale and the Centigrade scale.

一个物体的速度绝不会超过光速。

A material object cannot have a speed greater than the speed of light.

蒸馏就是要把溶液加热,直到水蒸发,然后再使蒸汽冷凝。

Distillation involves heating the solution until water evaporates, and then condensing the vapor.

半导体器件也称为晶体管，在许多场合替代电子管。

Semiconductor devices, called transistors, are replacing tubes in many applications.

我们知道,所有的物体都有重量并占据空间。

All bodies are known to possess weight and occupy space.

空间狭窄, 旅客的双腿就不能自由活动。

Cramped conditions mean that passengers’ legs cannot move around freely.

严禁乱拆,以免损坏该设备的零件。

It is forbidden to dismantle it without permission so as to avoid any damage to its parts.

由于生理上的局限, 一切生物总是要死亡的。

All living things must, by reason of physiological limitations, die.

去除水中的矿物质叫做软化。

The removal of minerals from water is called softening.

直到十九世纪人们才认识到热能是能量的一种形式。

It was not until the 19th century that heat was considered as a form of energy.

爱因斯坦宣称物质和能量可以互相转化，因此没有“绝对的”时间和空间。

Einstein claimed that matter and energy are interchangeable, so that there is no “absolute” time and space.

物理学研究力,运动,热,光,声,电,磁,辐射和原子结构

Physics studies force, motion, heat, light, sound, electricity, magnetism, radiation, and atomic structure.

这种点剂燃烧常常产生热的凝结颗粒。

The igniter combustion often produces hot condensed particles.

牛顿创立的天体力学真是天衣无缝，以至许多年来科学家们抱怨无空可补。

Newton created a planetary dynamics which was so successful that for many years scientists complained that nothing was left to be done．

还有一个优点即：加装一个高效助风机，以增大其吞吐量，并达到低真空。

These advantages are supplemented by addition of a high capacity booster blower for large throughput and deeper vacuums.

电池并联时提供的电流更大。

We can get more current from cells connected in parallel.

反射定律对一切表面都实用。

The law of reflection holds good for all surfaces.

爱因斯坦的相对论是能解释这种现象的唯一理论。

Einstein’s relativity theory is the only one which can explain such phenomena.

这四颗外层行星的内核可能都由金属、硅酸盐、水构成。

All four (outer planets) probably have cores of metals, silicates, and water.

设计师必须备有所使用材料的储备表。

The designer must have access to stock list of the materials he employs.

要使印刷品的质量到达要求，部件调试及修理必须定期进行。

Part adjustment and repair must be performed on a regular basis if an acceptable printed product is to be the end product.

居住在地震多发地区的人们应该建造能够抗震的房屋。

People who live in the areas where earthquakes are a common occurrence should build houses that are resistant to ground movement.

植物叶子的作用好比动物的肺一样。

Leaves are to the plant what lungs are to the animal.

某些金属具有导电和被磁化的能力。

There are some metals which possess the power to conduct electricity and ability to be magnetized.

纳米技术被认为是21世纪一门重要的制作技术，它将能够低成本地制造出几乎各种化学成分稳定的结构。

Nanotechnology has been described as a key manufacturing technology of the 21st century, which will be able to manufacture almost any chemically stable structure at low cost.

虽然某个元素的所有原子核都含有相同数目的质子，但它们含有的中子数可能不同。

With the same numbers of protons , all nuclei of a given element may have different numbers of neutrons.

如果母亲感染上艾滋病毒，在怀孕或分娩期间就会将艾滋病传染给孩子。

An infected mother can pass AIDS on to her child during pregnancy or childbirth.

为了更清除地阐释直接还原工艺过程，我们对气体产生的工艺流程也进行了简单介绍。

A brief summary of the gas generation schemes facilitates the DR process descriptions.

植物生长的各因素中最重要的是水的供应。

The most important of the factors affecting plant growth is that it requires the supply of water.

医生对血样做了分析，看是否是贫血症。

The doctor analyzed the blood sample for anemia.

太阳的大小看起来有变化，这是由于靠近地平线的空气中有尘粒引起的。

The apparent change in size of the sun is caused by dust in the air near the horizon.

这些石块和铁块的碎片大小不等，大的直径有1000公里，小的不到1公里。

These fragments of rock and iron range from a thousand kilometers in diameter to less than one.

一种新型的计算机越来越引起人们的注意—这种计算机体积小、价钱低、性能优。

A new kind of computer --- small, cheap, fine --- is attracting increasing attention.

细胞呼吸量的大小由生物体的活动程度来决定。

The amount of cell respiration depends upon the degree of activity of the organism.

高科技设备在不断增强视力和听力损伤者的自理能力。

High technology is providing visually and hearing impaired people with increased self-sufficiency.

不锈钢硬度大、强度高。

Stainless steels possess good hardness and high strength.

为了便于讨论，我们将摩擦力忽略不计。

For the purpose of our discussion, let us neglect the friction.

固体分子间的吸引力很大，使得分子排列很坚固。

In solids the force of attraction between the molecules is so great that the arrangement of the molecules becomes rigid.

用榔头轻轻的敲打，接合螺栓便能进入固定的位置。

The coupling bolts should go into place when tapped lightly with a hammer.

制图学是研究绘制地图的科学。

Cartography is the science of making maps.

人们发现，自然界里许多元素，都是各种不同的同位素的混合物。

Many elements in nature are found to be mixtures of different isotopes.

电学上最常用的两个单位是安培和伏特：后者是电压的单位，前者是电流的单位。

The two units used most frequently in electricity are ampere and volt:this is the unit of voltage and that of current.

同性电荷相斥，异性电荷相吸是电学的一个基本规律。

That like charges repel but opposite charges attract is one of the fundamental law of electricity.

航天计划需要大量的液氢和液氧作为火箭燃料。

Space programs demand tremendous quantities of liquid hydrogen and oxygen as rocket fuel.

因此，极容易计算出其弯曲应力。

Thus the bending stress is very easily computed.

不得使用过大的电流。

Too large a current must not be used.

气体在膨胀时对其冷却是一种逆效应。

The converse effect is the cooling of a gas when it expands.

可用交流或直流激励其中任何一个或两个绕组。

Either or both windings may be excited by alternating or direct currents.

几乎任何一种绝缘体都多少具有保留电荷一段时间的能力。

Almost any insulated body possesses to some extent the ability to retain for a time an electric charge.

向心推力轴承有较大的轴向承载能力。

The angular-contact bearing provides a greater thrust capacity.

通过改变晶粒的方位可以改变焊缝的性能。

The properties of the weld can be altered by varying the grain orientation.

同性电荷相斥，异性电荷相吸。

Like charges repel, unlike charges attract.

在射入窗内的阳光里，细微的尘埃象金子一般在闪闪发亮。

In the sunbeam passing through the window there are fine grains of dust shining like gold.

是原子构成了铁、水、氧等类物质。

It is the atoms that make up iron, water, oxygen and the like.

检查孔

inspection eye

观测镜

observers’ eye

电视摄像机

television eye

车床应安装在坚实的底座上。

The lathe should be set on a firm base.

众所周知，碱与酸起反应生成盐。

As we all know, a base reacts with an acid to form a salt.

晶体管有三个电极，即发射极、基极和集电极。

A transistor has three electrodes, the emitter, the base and the collector.

AB线是三角形ABC的底边。

Line AB is the base of the triangle ABC.

数学是所有其它科学的基础，而算术，即数的科学，则是数学的基础。

Mathematics is the base of all other sciences, and arithmetic, the science of numbers, is the base of mathematics.

锌易于从锌矿中提炼。

Zinc is easy to obtain from its ore.

当使用高的浇注温度以确保铸件的薄断面得到良好的充填时，初生奥氏体倾向于形成长而粗大的枝晶。

When high pouring temperatures are used to ensure satisfactory running of thin sections of castings the primary austenite tends to form long coarse dendrites.

白心可锻铸铁脱碳的程度取决于锰硫比和断面厚度。

The extent of decarburisation in a white heart iron depends on manganese to sulphur ratio as well as on section thickness.

铸铁中的石墨不硬，在压力下会变形。

Graphite in cast iron is not hard, it gives way to pressure.

电阻炉将电能转变为热能。

Electric resistance furnaces have their electric energy transformed into heat.

合金是介于混合物和化合物之间的一种中间结构。

Alloy belongs to a half-way house between mixtures and compounds.

断开时间”为7秒，最多不超过14秒。

“Open period” is 7 second, the maximum being twice that.

频率、波长和声速三方面是密切相关的。

The frequency, wave length, and speed of sound are closely related.

辐射能、电能和化学能这三种能均可转变为热能。

Radiant, electrical and chemical energies can all be turned into heat.

水管对通过的水流的阻力取决于下列三个因素：管道长度、管道直径、管道内壁的特性（粗糙或光滑）。

The resistance of the pipe to the flow of water through it depends upon the length of the pipe, the diameter of the pipe, and the feature of the inside walls (rough or smooth).

请注意，“速度”和“速率”这两个词需要解释。

Note that the words “velocity” and “speed” require explanation.

第一批电子计算机使用真空管和其他元件。

The first electronic computers used vacuum tubes and other components.

出口物资不得超过限制范围。

The export is not permitted to exceed its limitation.

电机发热问题的解决方法终于找到了。

Solution to the heating problem of the electric machine was ultimately found.

医生从我身上得到的实践经验,会比从其他普通病人得到的多。

The doctor will get more practice out of me than out of other ordinary patients.

完成勘查工作之后, 登上月球上的两个宇航员便重新回到船舱内。

When the exploration was completed, the two astronauts on the moon would join the moonship once more.

这样一个发电站的修建费用仅占该开发工程总费用的一小部分。

The cost of such a power plant is a relatively small portion of the total cost of the development.

最好的导体电阻最小，最差的导体电阻最大。

The best conductor has the least resistance and the poorest has the greatest.

经济全球化使南北的发展差距、贫富差距进一步扩大。

Economic globalization has widened the gap between the North and the South and between the rich and the poor.

声波分为了两类，即普通声波与超声波。

Sounds are classified into two kinds:sonic and ultrasonic.

力可以分为内力和外力两种。

Forces can be classified as internal and external.

当发电机由蒸气机、燃气轮机或水轮机驱动时,它便能发电。

A generator may generate electricity when driven by a steam engine, gas engine, or waterwheel.

便携式电器,如电炉、电熨斗、或电热水器的布线要格外小心。

The wiring of portable appliances, such as electric fires, irons, or kettles, needs particular care.

我们建议这项实验应在12时前完成。

We suggest that the test (should) be done by 12 o’clock.

本章阐明了电荷与物质之间的关系以及使原子与分子结合构成固体的力的作用。

This chapter has clarified the relation between electric charge and matter, and the nature of the forces that unite atoms and molecules into solids.

物质可以转化为能，能也可以转化为物质。

Matter can be changed into energy, and energy into matter.

人们要掌握科学，必须做出巨大的努力并对之怀有无限的热爱。

Science demands men of great effort and complete devotion.

进行尺寸标注是一项复杂的工作,需要有长期经验才能完成。

Dimensioning is a complicated work and long experiences are required for the mastering of it.

在进行这些测试时, 如果获得的结果始终如一, 这说明设计的实验台的一些性能符合要求。

In carrying out these tests several features were desirable in the design of rig if consistent results are to be obtained.

进行测试是一个复杂的工作, 因此, 须格外仔细。

Testing is a complicated problem, so be careful.

α粒子获得两个电子之后就变成了氦原子。

Upon gaining two electrons the alpha particle becomes a helium atom.

由于种种原因，交流电比直流电用得更为广泛。

For reasons the alternating current is more widely used than the direct current.

把一个磁石的北极对着另一个磁石的北极，这两个磁石就会互相排斥。

If the N pole of one magnet is held toward the N pole of another, the magnets will push away from each other.

这个实验虽然原理简单，却导致了一场影响深远的科学革命。

Simple in principle, the experiment led to a scientific revolution with far-reaching consequences.

由于其它液体太轻，因此，气压表用水银。

Other liquids being too light a barometer uses mercury.

表的指针先从0指向2，然后又回到0。

The pointer of the meter moves from zero to two and goes back to zero again.

由于没有转动件,所需维修工作量可减少到最低限度。

Without moving parts, maintenance requirements are cut to a minimum.

太阳发出的热能搅动大气，于是产生了风。

Heat from the sun stirs up the atmosphere, generating winds.

一般来说，金属都是良导体，其中以银为最好，铜次之。

In general, all the metals are good conductors, with silver the best and copper the second.

一种新型电脑正越来越引起人们的注意,它造价低、体积小、重量轻。

A new kind of computer—cheap, small, light is attracting increasing attention.

科学技术日新月异。

Science and technology are developing rapidly.

速度快、可靠性高,是电子计算机的主要优点。

Speed and reliability are the chief advantage of the electronic computer.

除了安装速度快外,这种类型的结构通常还具有其它特点。

In addition to the speed of erection, these types usually have other advantages.

电器运转时,请勿靠近。

When the machine is in operation, do keep away from it.

试求出下面的未知数。

Calculate the unknown in the following.

水若受热，就会汽化。

Heated, water will change into vapor.

这些早期的汽车速度缓慢，行动笨拙，效率不高。

These early cars were slow, clumsy, and inefficient.

这部打字机真是价廉物美。

This typewriter is indeed cheap and fine.

固体传声效果很好。

Solids transmit sound very well.

科学家经常设法否定自己的假设，推翻自己的理论，并放弃自己的结论。

A scientist constantly tried to defeat his hypotheses, his theories, and his conclusion.

他有望成为电气工程师。

He is expected to be an electrical engineer.

内外圈是根据尺寸分类存放的。

The inner and outer rings are graded and stored according to size.

越压缩，气体越热。

The more compressed it is, the hotter the gas becomes.

既然飞机的质量没有给出，那么可以用这个公式求出来。

Since the airplane’s mass is not given, we can find it by using this formula.

不同的电子仪器具有不同的性能。

Different electronic instruments differ in their property.

在此，我们只讨论新系统的稳定性。

We should concern ourselves here only with the stability of the new system.

专家们认为通过镭辐射治疗各种疾病是可能的。

Experts consider it possible to cure various diseases via radium radiation.

我国第一台电子计算机是1958年生产的。

The first electronic computer was produced in our country in 1958.

氢是最轻的元素，原子量为1.008。

Hydrogen is the lightest element with an atomic weight of 1.008.

两直线平行，同位角相等。

If two lines are parallel the corresponding angles are equal.

几乎所有的物质都热胀冷缩。

Practically all substances expand when heated and contract when cooled.

温度增高，水的体积就增大。

As the temperature increases, the volume of water becomes greater.

正在运转的电机转子具有动能。

A machine rotor has kinetic energy while it is set in motion.

玻璃、橡胶的电阻极高。

Glass and rubber offer a very high resistance.

气压低，水的沸点就低。

When the air pressure gets low, the boiling-point of water becomes low.

地球的确变化很慢，但它确实是在不断地变化。

To be sure, the change of the earth is slow but, nevertheless, it is continuous.

期盼贵方能尽早给我方一个明确的答复。

We expect that you will give us a definite reply at your earliest convenience.

在过去的一个世纪中发现的全球变暖趋势据推测可能是由人为的温室气体造成的。

Global warming observed over the past century has focused attention on manmade greenhouse gas, presumed to be the likely cause.

执法机构继续通缉导致1990年1月15日美国电话电报公司系统崩溃的黑客。

Law enforcement agencies went on a hunt for hackers in the aftermath of the AT&T system crash of 15 January 1990.

早在70年代，麻省理工学院建筑机械实验室就开始尝试在计算机中将语言和手势集成在一起。

Attempts to program a computer to integrate gesture with speech began back in the 1970s at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology Architecture Machine Lab.

使用电子计算机可以大大提高劳动生产率。

The application of electronic computers makes for a tremendous rise in labor productivity.

沙漠化并不意味着沙漠前进不可逆转。

Desertification is not a case of irreversible desert advance.

只要一点鼠标，来自世界另一端的信息便会以每秒绕地球七周半的惊人速度传输到你的电脑屏幕上。

With the click of a mouse, information from the other end of the globe will be transported to your computer screen at the dizzying speed of seven-and-a-half times around the earth per second.

当我们步入下一世纪时，人类社会也正由工业经济向知识经济转变。

As we cross the threshold into the next century, human society is beginning its move from the industrial economy into the knowledge-based economy.

人造纤维能代替天然纤维吗？

Can artificial fibers be used as substitutes for natural fibers?

电子计算机能对工厂的每道工序进行分析。

Computers can provide analyses of every operation in a factory.

我们应以预防疾病为主。

We must place stress on the prevention of diseases.

煤油不象汽油那样容易挥发。

Kerosene is not so volatile as gasoline.

下次地震将在什么时候发生？

When is the next earthquake due?

他们肯定能在短期内建成那座工厂。

They are sure that they’ll be able to build the factory in a short period of time.

功的大小等于力和距离的乘积。

The amount of work is equal to the product of the force by the distance.

铜线容易弯曲。

Copper wire is flexible.

现在中国人热衷于从西方国家进口现代化医疗技术，而越来越多的西方人则热衷于接受中医疗法。

While the Chinese are eager to import modern medical technology from the West, increasing members of Westerners are equally eager in adopting the traditional medical remedies of China.

试件的长度应与所使用的装置相适应。

The test piece shall be of length suitable for the apparatus being used.

热是能的一种形式，其他一切能的形式都能转化为热能。

Heat is a form of energy into which all other forms are convertible.

那儿正在举办新产品展览会。

An exhibition of new products is on there.

在发达国家，机动车辆是空气污染的主要来源，在落后的城市，这种污染也将增加。

Motor vehicles, already the main source of city air pollution in rich countries, will increasingly pollute poor cities, too.

这个化学试验延误了十分钟。

The experiment in chemistry was ten minutes behind.

如果开关接通，电流就流过线路。

The electric current flows through the circuit with the switch on.

这两个物体相距很远，它们之间的吸引力可以忽略不计。

The two bodies are so far apart that the attractive force between them is negligible.

他昨天把机器拆开了。

He took the machine apart yesterday.

由于分子运动而引起的力能使分子分离。

The force due to the motion of molecules tends to keep them apart.

当作用在气体上的压力增大时，气体的体积就缩小。

The volume of a gas becomes smaller when the pressure upon it is increased.

通常用字母 E 表示电动势。

The letter E is commonly used for electromotive force.

没有力的作用，静止的物体不可能开始运动。

No body at rest can be set in motion without a force being acted upon it.

很显然，数控是指机床采用数字来操纵。

It is clear that numerical control is the operation of machine tools by numbers.

许多实验室正在研制治疗爱滋病的药物。

Many laboratories are developing medicines against AIDS.

原子能动力用于远洋船只已经成为现实。

Atomic power for ocean-going vessels is already a reality.

这是一种具有高强度的合金。

This is a kind of alloy with high strength.

只要能产生热，就能使蒸汽机做功。

So long as we have means of producing heat we can keep the steam engine at work.

通常，机器的工作部件是用碳素钢制造的。

Usually the working parts of the machines are made from carbon steels.

中子的作用不同于质子。

Neutrons act differently from protons.

气体和固体的区别在于前者比后者有更大的可压缩性。

Gases differ from solids in that the former have greater compressibility than the latter.

电子计算机的主要特点是计算准确而快速。

The electronic computer is chiefly characterized by its accurate and rapid computations.

水银的重量约为水的十三倍。

Mercury weighs about thirteen times as much as water.

网络和电子商业将会造就一大批自由职业者，从而将对社会结构产生深远的影响。

The net and electronic commerce will foster a large number of freelancers, and this will affect social structure in a big way.

个人计算机使整个世界更新了工作、娱乐和通讯方式。

PCs gave the world a whole new way to work, play and communicate.

他的目标是当一名计算机专家。

He aims to become a computer expert.

在生命过程中，动物的活动方式与植物相反。

In the life process, the animal works in the opposite way to the plant.

电流的变化与电动势成正比，与电阻成反比。

An electric current varies directly as the electromotive force and inversely as the resistance.

这两种化合物都是酸，前者是强酸，后者是弱酸。

Both the compounds are acids, the former is strong and the latter weak.

大气的厚度约为11000米。

The atmosphere is only about eleven kilometers thick.

人类比机器人更灵活而且更富有创造性。

People are so much more flexible and inventive than robots.

在裂变过程中，裂变碎片的放射性很强。

In fission processes the fission fragments are very radioactive.

钢含碳量越高，强度和硬度就越大。

The more carbon the steel contains, the harder and stronger it is.

用电解法生产的效率不象热化学法那样高。

The electrolytic process for producing hydrogen is not so efficient as the thermochemical process.

冰的密度比水小，因而能浮在水面上。

Ice is not as dense as water and it therefore floats.

生产成本的差异与能源密切相关。

The different production cost is closely associated with the sources of power.

玻璃的可溶性比石英大。

Glass is more soluble than quartz.

温度不变，则气体压力和体积成反比。

At constant temperature, the pressure of a gas is inversely proportional to its volume.

无线电波与光波相似，只不过无线电波的波长要长一些。

Radio waves are similar to light waves except that their wave-length is much greater.

我们所需要的频率，甚至比我们称作高频率的还要高。

We need frequencies even higher than those we call very high frequency.

气温升高时，空气密度就减小；空气变冷时，空气密度就增大。

Air density decreases as the temperature goes up and it increases when it gets colder.

越来越多的证据表明，许多塑料制品的化学成分会移动到食物或流体上去，最终进入人体内。

According to a growing body of evidence, the chemicals that make up many plastics may migrate out of the material and into foods and fluids, ending up in your body.

如果没有引力，人们就会一直掉到地球的中心。

One would fall all the way down to the center of the earth without gravity.

在长达两千年的时间里，人们都认为一切重物都比轻物落得快。

For nearly two thousand years it was mistakenly believed that all heavy objects fell faster than light ones.

最普通的加速度是自由落体加速度。

The most common acceleration is that of free falling bodies.

尽管能量的形式可以转换，但能量既不能被创造，有不能被消灭。

Energy can neither be created, nor destroyed, although its form can be changed.

由于这种磁性产生于电，所以称为电磁。

Such magnetism, because it is electrically produced, is called electromagnetism.

氧是物质世界的重要元素之一，其化学性能很活泼。

Oxygen is one of the important elements in the physical world, it is very actively chemically.

操作系统的质量决定着计算机的应用效能。

The quality of the operating system determines how useful the computer is.

下面的这些方程式是由上面的那些方程式推导出来的。

The equations below are derived from those above.

这一页是计算机的简图。

The computer is shown schematically on this page.

印度拥有软件设计方面的技术，而且拥有成千上万能说英语、精通技术的软件工程师。

India has the software skills and thousands of software developers who are English-speaking and technically proficient.

展望未来可以看到石油将在世界上起到令人鼓舞的作用。

A look ahead gives petroleum an exciting role in the world of tomorrow.

在自然界所存在的物质中，只有铀-235可以用作获得核能的材料。

The only naturally occurring substance used as fuel for nuclear power is U-235.

直到40年代初，化学家们才开始将这种技术用于分析工作。

It was not until early 40’s that chemists began to use the technique analytically.

硝酸是一种强烈的反应剂。

Nitric acid is an extremely reactive agent.

广泛应用电子计算机，对科学技术的发展有极大的影响。

The wide application of electronic computers affects tremendously the development of science and technology.

两栖类和鸟类之间有显著的差别。

Amphibians and birds do differ significantly.

虽然身高是一种明显的遗传特征，但是个体的实际身高则取决于基因和环境的相互作用。

While tallness is evidently a hereditary characteristic, any individual’s actual height depends on the interaction between their genes and the environment.

机器人技术与控制论的联系如此密切，以致两者有时被错误地认为是同一回事。

Robotics is so closely associated with cybernetics that it is sometimes mistakenly considered to be synonymous.

工程师为这次设计作了十分周密的准备。

The engineer had prepared meticulously for his design.

气体在低压下导电性最佳。

Gases conduct best at low pressures.

计算机展览会给我们留下了深刻的印象。

The computer exhibition impressed us deeply.

万能车床得到了最广泛的使用，所以在工业上起着重要的作用。

The universal lathe is most widely used and plays an important part in industry.

电子计算机和微处理器对我们来说都十分重要。

Electronic computers and microprocessors are of great importance to us.

中国设计的核动力系统十分精确。

The nuclear power system designed in China is of great precision.

试验很成功。

The experiment was quite a success.

绝大多数青少年在学习和操作电脑方面并不觉得困难。

Most teenagers feel no difficulty in learning and operating computers.

在一定情形下摩擦是绝对必要的。

In certain cases friction is an absolute necessity.

医生们正在给病人做手术，可病人的神经一直十分紧张。

The doctors were operating on the patient, but the patient’s nerve was continually on the stretch.

使用雷达探测水下目标是没有用的。

It is no use employing radar to detect objects in water.

一些老板们非常热情地鼓励雇员们增强环保意识，将汽车换成小一点的。

Some employers are keen to encourage employees to go green, and switch to small cars.

只要稍微修理一下，这台老式发动机就可使用。

With slight repairs the old type of engine can be used.

在科学研究、设计和经济计算方面广泛地应用电子计算机可以使人们从繁重的计算劳动中解放出来。

The wide application of electronic machines in scientific work, in designing and in economic calculations will free man from the labor of complicated computations.

这台发动机一直运转良好。

The engine has given a constantly good performance.

在过去的几年中，激光器件发展迅速，从而为通讯系统的快速进步打开了通路。

Very significant advances in lasers have been make in the past several years that open the door to more rapid progress in optical communications systems.

频繁抽烟有害于健康。

Continual smoking is harmful to health.

每种型号只要稍加改动就能用于这三种系统。

With slight modifications each type can be used for all three systems.

如果需要精确定时，必须注意不要中断定时波。

When precise timing is necessary, care must be taken not to interrupt the timing wave.

我们仔细地研究了这些化学元素的特性。

We have made a careful study of the properties of these chemical elements.

水在4℃以下不断膨胀而不是不断收缩。

Below 4℃ water is continuous expansion instead of continuous contraction.

人类社会的生产活动，由低级向高级逐步发展。

In human society activity in production develops step by step from a lower to a higher level.

增添这种装置将保证工件装卸方便。

The added device will ensure accessibility for part loading and unloading.

他们报告说已成功地把正常人类细胞转化为癌细胞。

They reported they had succeeded in turning normal human cells into cancerous one.

加热面上的迅速蒸发，往往使蒸汽的湿度加大。

Rapid evaporation at the heating-surface tends to make the steam wet.

我们将大规模地发展航空工业。

We shall develop the aircraft industry in a big way.

人们使用超声波能够发现金属是否有裂缝。

By the use of ultrasonic waves, one can find out if there is a flaw in the metal.

正电荷聚集在导体上，使导体的电位增高。

The positive charges being crowded upon a conductor results in the rise of the potential of the conductor.

他假设电子的电荷数与一个氢离子的电荷数相等。

He made the assumption that the electronic charge is numerically equal to the charge on a hydrogen ion.

生物学是在分子基础上研究生命的科学。

Biochemistry is the study of the molecular basis of life.

他们非常熟悉这类晶体管放大器的性能。

They are very familiar with the performance of this type of transistor amplifier.

这种仪表用来测定电瓶的充电程度。

The instrument is used to determine how fully the batteries are charged.

即使在室温条件下，水银的挥发性也很强。

Mercury is appreciably volatile even at room temperature.

大多数人造同位素都具有放射性。

Most isotopes produced artificially are radioactive.

地壳在海洋底下厚度只有大约3英里的地方。

The crust of the earth may be only about 3 miles thick beneath parts of the ocean.

导电性在选择电气材料时很重要。

The electrical conductivity has great importance in selecting electrical materials.

太阳对人身体和精神都有极大的影响。

The sun affects tremendously both the mind and body of a man.

常温下水银在空气中具有很大的稳定性。

At ordinary temperature mercury is greatly stable in air.

工程师为这次设计作了周密的准备。

The engineer had prepared meticulously for his design.

防止污染对保养射流装置是绝对必要的。

Contamination-proof is an absolute necessity in the maintenance of fluidic devices.

我们只有充分发挥人的积极性，才能充分利用机器来改造自然。

Only when we give full play to man’s initiative can we make full use of machines to transform nature.

中国十分重视环境保护。

China pays great attention to the environmental protection.

我们以前讨论光时曾特别注意说明摄谱仪的工作原理。

In our earlier study of light, attention was particularly directed toward the theory of operation of spectrographs.

我们必须弄清楚能是怎样转换的。

It is necessary for us to know how to convert energy.

不断增加密闭容器内的气体温度，会使气体的内压力不断增大。

A continuous increase in the temperature of a gas confined in a container will lead to a continuous increase in the internal pressure within the gas.

如果一个原子含有三个质子，这个原子必然有三个电子，使之不带电荷。

If an atom contains three protons, it must have three electrons to be electrically neutral.

水向下所施加的压力和水的深度成正比。

The downward pressure exerted by water is proportional to its depth.

两分钟做一件事所需的功率大于两小时做同一件事所需的功率。

It takes more power to do a job in two minutes than it does to do the same job in two hours.

仅凭电压的高低、电流的强弱和功率的大小尚不足以区别开来。

The levels of voltage, current and power are, on their own, not sufficient for demarcation.

金属热处理最常用的是煤气炉、油炉和电炉。

Gas, oil, and electric furnaces are most commonly used for heat treating metal.

如果不会制图或是看不懂图纸，就不可能造出一条船，盖出一所房子，或生产出一台机床。

You cannot build a ship, a house, or a machine tool if you do not know how to make a design or how to read it.

每一种保险丝都有一定的电流额定值，该额定值限定了保险丝所能通过的最大安培数。

Every fuse has a definite current rating, indicating that no more than a specified number of amperes can pass through the fuse.

连接金属件的方法很多，选用哪种方法要视金属的种类和所要求的接点强度而定。

There are a number of methods of joining metal articles together, depending on the type of metal and the strength of the joint which is required.

一切金属都是良导体，因为金属里有大量的电子。

All the metals are good conductors because there are a great number of free electrons in them.

市场经济本身是一个长期发展过程的产物，是生产方式和交换方式一系列变革的产物。

Marketing economy is itself the product of long course of development, of a series of revolutions in the modes of production and of exchange.

在这四幅画中，有两幅看起来是真的，另外两幅看起来则是赝品。

Among the four pictures, two appear to be real, others false.

我们必须积极采用新技术，新设备、新工艺、新材料。

We must actively introduce new techniques, equipment, technologies and material.

燃烧在纯氧中比在空气中快得多。

Burning takes place much faster in pure oxygen than in air.

液压弹簧尤其适用于要求承载能力和刚度很高的地方。

Hydraulic springs are particularly suited for applications in which high load capacities and stiffness are required.

我们可以认为物体的整个重量是集中在物体的重心上。

We can regard the entire weight of a body as concentrated at its center of gravity.

安装地下电子装置和租借电话线就要耗资15,000,000美元。

Installing the electronic units in the ground and leasing telephone wires would cost $ 15 million.

引进一项新开发的技术将增加成功的希望。

Introduction of a newly-developed technique will enhance the prospects of success.

必须计入泵内部的摩擦。

Account must be taken of friction occurring within the pump.

要设计一个完善的管路系统必须选择合适的阀门。

Proper valve selection is essential for a well-designed piping system.

应特别注意这几种类型的阀座材料。

Particular attention must be given to the several types of seating materials.

我们曾力图寻找一种提高生产率的方法。

Attempts were made to find out a method for increasing productivity.

由于磁力线的回聚和发散，就必须需要一个分量Br。

Since the lines of magnetic force converge and diverge, there is the necessity for a component Br.

为了使火箭各级全部离开地面，需要有一个巨大的第一次推力。

To get all the stages off the ground, a first big push is needed.

使一个物体运动，就必须做功。

Work must be done in setting a body in motion.

有人建议以核能温差电池作为太阳系远程空间探测器的能源。

Nuclear energy thermoelectric generators are proposed as power sources for the solar system deep space explorers.

通常，标准机床不包含附件。

Attachments are usually not included with standard machine.

墙壁和天花板使用了吸音材料。

Sound absorbing material has been used in walls and ceiling.

在居里温度以上，没有自发的磁化。

Above the Curie temperature there is no spontaneous magnetization.

迄今为止，消息的编码有三种主要的选择。

Up to now, there have been three main options for encoding a message.

可以断言，氧化铜是比氧化汞更为稳定的一种化合物。

It can be concluded that copper oxide is a more stable compound than mercuric oxide.

这里介绍几个概念：判定、模拟、动力学、反馈、稳定性和逻辑设计等。

Several concepts are introduced:decision-making, modeling, dynamics, feedback, stability and logical design.

电路已采取措施来限制晶体管的电压。

Provision is made within the circuitry to limit the transistor voltage.

务必要排除所有故障。

See to it that all troubles should be eliminated.

转子没有直接的连接电线。

No direct electrical connection to the rotor is provided.

必须采取措施驱散因表面摩擦所产生的热。

Provision must be made for dissipating the heat that results from the sliding of surfaces.

由这一实验可以得出结论，带异性电荷的粒子相互吸引的这一说法是正确的。

From this experiment the conclusion is drawn that the theory of oppositely charged particles attracting each other is true.

机翼的用途是使飞机在空中保持不坠。

The wings are responsible for keeping the airplane in the air.

这些试验的设计是用来证实他的理论的。

The experiments are designed to validate his theory.

一个氧原子的质量相当于一个氢原子质量的16倍。

An atom of oxygen is 16 times as much as an atom of hydrogen in weight.

半导体材料的导电性比导体差。

A semi-conductor material is poorer than a conductor in conductivity.

合金钢板的厚度一般为5/64~1/8英寸。

The alloy sheet is usually 5/64~1/8 in thick.

成品的需求量越大，加工方法越完善，则每件产品的生产成本就越低。

The greater the number of finished parts required, the more sophisticated the methods become and the lower the production cost per part.

产生一定的应变所需的应力越大，则材料的刚度也越大。

The greater the stress required to produce a given strain, the stiffer the material is said to be.

好钟的钟摆可以自动补偿温度的变化。

Good clocks have pendulums which are automatically compensated for temperature changes.

由于效率提高，工厂里出的产品比起以前来，价格便宜多了。

Improved efficiency has made the products of manufactories very much cheaper than formerly.

由于大坝倒塌，土地因此被淹。

The collapse of the dam caused the land being flooded.

由于活动受限，导致血液流动受阻。

Restricted movement led to an interruption of blood flow.

磨削是机加工中最常用的精加工方法。

In machining, grinding processes are most often used as finish machining processes.

各种物质导热的能力有很大差别。

There are wide differences in the ability of various substances to conduct heat.

两个表面之间的任何摩擦都会导致材料的温度升高。

Any friction between two surfaces results in a temperature rise of the materials.

铆钉随着冷却而收缩，从而使钢板紧紧地压在一起。

The rivets contract as they cool, drawing the plates together.

同时，声音传播的方向能告诉蝙蝠食物的位置。

And the direction in which the sound is traveling tells the bat where the meal is located.

沸点的定义就是气压等于大气压时的温度。

Boiling point is defined as the temperature at which the vapor pressure is equal to that of the atmosphere.

试验表明，冷却空气的流速至少应为17 m/s。

Tests showed that the cooling air must flow at a rate of at least 17 m/s.

黑洞的作用像宇宙中巨大的吸管。

Black holes act like huge drains in the universe.

这一实验的结果是发现了一种治疗癌症的方法。

The experiment resulted in the discovery of a cure for cancer.

使用表面活性剂的目的就是简化工作过程。

The application of surfactant aims to simplify work processes.

物体的重量在地球上的不同地点都会稍有变化，它取决于引力的大小。

Weight varies slightly in different places of the earth, depending on the force of gravity.

该标度盘刻有分成100等分的标度。

The dial is scaled into one hundred graduations.

雷达的工作原理和手电筒极为相同。

Radar works in very much the same way as the flashlight.

测得的压力为0.1托。

The pressure was determined to be 0.1 torr.

电站尽力保持日夜供电。

The power station managed to maintain its supply of electricity day and night.

快速蒸发往往使蒸汽的湿度加大。

Rapid evaporation tends to make the steam wet.

分子仍然紧密地聚集在一起，但不再继续保持有规则的固定排列形式。

The molecules continue to stay close together, but do not continue to retain a regular fixed arrangement.

橡胶的绝缘性不如空气。

Rubber is a poorer insulator than air.

欧姆定律是物理学上著名的定律之一。

One of the well-known laws of physics is Ohm’s Law.

如果你在球场观看一场比赛，网络会知道你希望掌上电脑提供的是每位球员的简介。

If you’re watching a game in the ballpark, the network will know that player profiles are what you need on your palm-sized computer.

抗腐蚀性是不锈钢的一个最重要的特性。

The most important characteristic of stainless steels is their corrosion resistance.

所有的铸造材料中最常用的要数灰口铸铁。

Of all the cast materials, gray cast iron is the most widely used.

电弧焊是工业上最常用的焊接方法。

The most widely used industrial welding method is arc welding.

通常的经验是物质向前滚动比滑动容易得多。

It is a matter of common experience that it is much easier to roll bodies along than to slide them.

这两种方法都适合于检测裂纹。

Both of these methods are suitable for detecting cracks.

该方程适用于一般情况。

The equation is applicable to the general case.

这种模拟程序适合在大学里使用。

This simulation program is available for use at universities.

由于大多数金属都具有延展性和韧性,所以可以压成薄板和拉成细丝。

As most metals are malleable and ductile, they can be beaten into plates and drawn into wire.

向心推力轴承具有较大的轴向承载能力。

The angular-contact bearing is of greater thrust capacity.

已研究出从城市废水中提取重金属的热酸废水处理法。

A hot-acid method for extracting heavy metals from municipal waste-water has been developed.

人类要控制地震似乎比控制天气更不容易。

Earthquakes seem less easy to be controlled by man than weather.

在世界上所需要的化肥中整整有80%是靠天然气和水蒸气中取得的合成氨来满足的。

Full 80% of the world’s fertilizer requirements are met by synthesizing ammonia氨 from natural gas and steam.

到目前为止，二氧化硫一直被看做是这些污染物中最严重的一种。

Up to now, sulfur dioxide has been regarded as one of the most serious of these pollutants．

电流流过导线时导线就发热。

While a current is flowing through wire, the latter is being heated.

如果原来水用得多一些，温度变化就会小一些。

If more water had been used，the temperature change would have been smaller.

如果早就采用这种新方法就会节约好多时间。

If this new method had been adopted, much time would have been saved.

据说，在最初的时候，可以说什么东西也没有，甚至连空间也没有。

At the beginning, it is said, there was literally nothing, not even space．

能量转换的试验说明能量既不能创造也不能消灭。

The experiments on the transformations of energy show that no energy can be created and none destroyed.

两百多年来蒸汽机的基本结构没有发生大的变化。

The basic design of the steam engine has undergone no major change in over 200 years.

气体既没有一定的形状，也没有一定的体积。

Gas has neither definite shape nor definite volume.

无论哪一种惰性气体，都不会和其它物质化合而形成化合物。

None of the inert gases will combine with other substances to form compounds.

世界上没有任何东西比光传得更快了。

Nothing in the world moves faster than light.

耐火材料和磁性材料都不适合生产这种零件。

Neither refractory materials nor magnetic materials can be used to make the part.

这两个电路他一个也不能分析。

He can analyze neither of the circuits.

这些电子仪表他全都不知道。

He knows none of the electronic meters.

这两种物质并非都是由碳组成的。

Both of the substances are not made up of carbons.

数字示波器不常用在我们的实验中。

Digital oscilloscopes cannot be often used in our experiments.

正离子并不完全相同，他们在电量和重量上都可能有差别。

Positive ions are not all alike and may differ in charge or weight.

摩擦并非总是无用的，在某些场合下，则是有益和必需的。

Friction is not always useless, in certain cases it becomes a helpful necessity．

没有电也就没有现代文明。

Without electricity, there could be no today’s civilization.

要是没有计算机，我们就不可能如此轻而易举地完成这些复杂工作。

Without computer, we could not finish these complicated jobs so easily.

如果没有压差，水也就不会流动。

No flow of water occurs unless there is a difference in pressure.

没有雷达，飞行员在夜间不能进行长途飞行。

In the absence of radar, the pilot in an airplane could not fly for a long distance at night.

要是没有太阳，所有生物在地球上都不能生存。

But for the sun, all living things could not live on the earth.

电转换成某种能量时不可能不产生损耗。

It is impossible for electricity to be converted into certain energy without something lost.

不到安装这些电气保护装置时不应打开包装箱或包装纸。

All these electric protective devices should not be unboxed or unwrapped until the moment for fitting has arrived.

现在的宇宙飞船都能够载人了。

Now no spaceship cannot be loaded with man.

仿真研究的一切都在预料之中。

There is nothing unexpected in the simulation investigation.

有阳光就有阴影。

There can be no sunshine without shadow.

任何规则都有例外。

There is no rule that has no exception.

现代通信手段都有缺点。

There is no modern communication mean that has no disadvantage.

有一利必有一弊。

There is not any advantage without disadvantage.

实验的结果相当好。

The output of the experiment was not half bad.

奇怪的是，天王星几乎没有这种多余的热量。

Curiously, Uranus has almost no such excess heat.

在自然界，金属很少以纯金属的形式存在。

Rarely do metals occur in nature in a pure form by themselves.

我们现有的蓄电池几乎都不足以保证电气火车快速而经济高效的运行。

Barely any of our present batteries would be satisfactory enough to drive the electric train fast and at a reasonable cost.

哪个绕组或哪些绕组上有分接头，对使用者来说这没有多大区别。

It seldom makes such difference to the user which winding or windings are tapped.

这个电厂的装机容量几乎没有什么变化。

The installed capacity in this power plant hardly changes at all.

在一九四九年之前中国几乎没有什么电力供应。

There was little electric power supply in China before 1949.

关于机器损坏情况的信息极少。

Little information is given as to damage of the machine.

英国远洋货轮很少在本国港口停靠。

Much of Britain’s liner fleet rarely sees a British port.

机器的性能没有达到要求。

The performance of the machine is short of the requirements.

没有变压器，他们在实验室自己制作。

Short of transformers, they make their own in their lab.

为了不受谐波的危害，应该在电网中使用一些滤波装置。

Free from harmonics, some filter appliances should be used in power network.

该市的供电系统非常不完善。

The system of power supply in the city leaves much to be desired.

研究证明几乎无人能逃脱互投核弹造成的恶果。

The study confirmed that few people are likely to escape the effects of nuclear exchange.

这个问题我无法理解。

The problem is beyond the reach of my understanding.

你绝对不能拿走这个电压表。

You must do anything but taking away this voltmeter.

零件斜度太大，不宜装配。

The angularity of the parts is too great for proper assembly.

在大多数情况下，直流电压中的纹波或谐波是不利的。

The ripple or harmonics in the direct voltage are objectionable in many cases.

电子小得我们看不见。

Electrons are too small to be seen by us.

现代科学的价值，无论如何重视也不过分。

We cannot estimate the value of modern science too much.

一本书好比你的邻居，如果是好书，读书时间再长也不嫌长，如果是坏书，越早丢开越好。

A book may be compared to your neighbor; if it is good, it cannot last too long; if bad, you cannot get rid of it too early.

他在修机器这件事上花费了很多的功夫。

He took no little pains over repairing the machine.

农业是国民经济的基础，怎么强调也不过分。

It cannot be too much emphasized that agriculture is the foundation of the national economy.

电机停止运转，并非因为电源切断了。

The motor did not stop because the electricity was off.

引擎停止运转并非因为燃料耗尽。

The engine didn’t stop because the fuel was finished.

水力发电不用燃料。

Hydroelectric power generation uses no fuel.

我们不知道储存太阳能的有效方法。

We know of no effective way to store solar energy.

正如我们所知，电不能靠绝缘体来传导。

As we know, electricity cannot be conducted by means of insulators.

目前还尚无一列商业产品中的电瓶系统具有所有这些优点。

No battery system presently in commercial production can offer all of these facilities.

我们认为相移不会与频率成正比。

We don’t consider that the phase shift is proportional to frequency.

多年来原子一直被认为是不可分割的。

For many years the atom was not believed to be divisible.

除了液体金属如水银外，其他液体则被认为是不良导热体。

Liquids, except for liquid metal as mercury, are not considered to be good conductors of heat.

惰性气体既不能燃烧．也不助燃。

The inactive gas neither burns nor supports combustion．

同性电荷相斥、异性电荷相吸是电学的基本定律之一。

That like charges repel but opposite charges attract is one of the fundamental laws of electricity.

正是由于集成电路的研制成功，才有可能把电子器件做得越来越小。

It is due to the development of integrate circuits that there is the possibility to make electronic devices smaller and smaller.

液体没有一定形状，但有一定体积，这是普通常识。

It is common sense that a liquid has no definite shape but it has a definite volume．

科学家们早已预言，总有一天计算机将帮助我们加快艰巨的文字翻译工作。

Scientists have long predicated that computers would one day help speed up the arduous task of translating texts.

营养实验已经证明，维生素在人们健康和成长中是不可缺少的。

Nutritional experiments have made it evident that vitamins are indispensable for one’s health and growth．

气体交换过程遵循一条简单的物理定律，即气体向压力最小的地方流动。

The process of exchange of gases follows a simple law of physics that a gas flows in to the direction of least pressure.

飞机在空中飞行时，如果任何部件发生故障它是不能停下来的，因此，其性能必须绝对可靠，这是一个生死攸关的问题。

The fact that an aeroplane is up in the air and can not stop if anything goes wrong makes it perhaps a matter of life or death that its performance is absolutely dependable.

调制解调器是把一台计算机通过电话线同其他计算机相连接的一种装置。

A modem is a device which connects a computer via telephone lines to other computers．

金属的强度、硬度和可塑性这些性能使它们在工业上得到广泛应用。

Strength, hardness and plasticity of metals are the properties that make them so useful for industry.

世界上有些国家由于终年少雨，农民不得不灌溉他们的田地。

There are some countries in the world where there is little rain at anytime.The farmers have to irrigate their fields.

燃料燃烧时，化学能就转化为光和热能，这和能量守衡定律是一致的。

When fuels burn, chemical energy changes into light and heat energy, which agrees with the law of conservation of energy.

许多大学都配备了“闭路”电视设备，以便为各个教室的千百个学生进行电视讲授和演示。

Many universities have “closed-circuit” television equipment that will telecast lectures and demonstrations to hundreds of students in different classrooms.

如果一种钢除含有碳硫磷以外还含有1%多的锰或0.3%多的硅或者一些碳素钢中不包含的其它元素，那么这种钢便是合金钢。

An “allay” steel is one which, in addition to the contents of carbon, sulphur and phosphorus, contains more than 1 percent or manganese，or more than 0.3 percent of silicon，or some other elements in amounts not encountered in carbon steels.

报上宣布，我国又发射了一颗人造地球卫星。

As is announced in the papers, our country has launched another man-made satellite.

物价普遍上涨,跟六十年代末一样。

There is a general rise in prices such as occurred in the late 60's.

当电子束扫描图像时，图像的光强度变化变成了电强度变化。

As the electron beam scans the image, variations of light intensity of the image are converted into variation in electric energy．

生物学家破译了遗传密码之后，他们发现自己掌握了一种新的语言。

When biologists cracked the genetic code, they found themselves in control of a new language．

已知导线中的电流，只要求出导线两端电位差的伏特数，就不难测出任何长度的导线的电阻。

The resistance of any length of a conductivity wine is easily measured by finding the potential difference in volts between its ends when a known current is flowing.

因为煤、重油和煤气都含有硫化物，所以在它们燃烧时会放出一些二氧化硫。

Some sulphur dioxide is liberated when coal, heavy oil and gas burn, because they all contain sulphur compounds.

地球上的任何物体都会落下来，除非它受到一个大小与重量相等的力的支持。

Any body above the earth will fall unless it is supported by an upward force equal to its weight.

气体的每一个粒子都具有很大的运动能，因此它们一直在快速运动。

Each particle in a gas has a great amount of movement energy so that they are all traveling quite quickly.

为了防止射线漏出，必须用很厚的墙壁将原子反应堆屏蔽起来。

An atomic furnace must be surrounded by heavy thick walls so that the rays cannot get out.

虽然雷达应用无线电波，但与无线电和电视略有区别。

Though radar uses radio waves, it is somewhat different from radio and television.

每个化学元素在周期表中都有一定的原子数和位置，可以据此来推测其特性：如何同别的元素相互作用，能形成什么样的化合物，以及它的物理属性。

Each chemical element had its number and fixed position in the table，and from this it became possible to predict its behavior：how it would react with other elements，what kind of compounds it would form，and what sort of physical properties it would have.

单件生产就是生产少量的零件，批量生产是指生产大量相同的零件。

Manufacturing process may be classified as unit production with small quantities being made and mass production with large numbers of identical parts being produced.

一小部分富有想象力和敬业精神的科学家正在进行这项研究，他们专门研究从各种海洋动物中提取能增进人类健康的物质。

The research work is being done by a small group of dedicated and imaginative scientists who specialize in extracting from various sea animals substances that may improve the health of the human race.

集成电路的产量比去年增加了两倍。

The production of integrated circuits has been increased to three times as compared with last year.

漏电压增加了3借（即增加到原来的4倍）。

The drain voltage has been increased by a factor of four.

化肥产量比1986年增加了4倍。

The output of chemical fertilizer has been raised five times as against l986．

这些机器的效率已提高了2倍或3倍多。

The efficiency of the machines has been more than trebled or quadrupled.

氢原子的重量约为氧原子的1/16（即比氧原子约轻15/16）。

The hydrogen atom is near1y l6 times as light as the oxygen atom.

这种薄膜比普通纸张要薄一半（即是普通纸厚度的1/2）。

This sort of membrane is twice thinner than ordinary paper.

新型晶体管的开关时间缩短了2/3（即缩短到1/3）。

Switching time of the new-type transistor is shortened 3 times.

电压升高9倍，电流强度便降低9/10（即90％）。

When the voltage is stepped up by ten times， the strength of the current is stepped down by ten times.

该设备误差概率降低了4/5。

The equipment reduced the error probability by a factor of 5.

发现迅速减少到1/7。

A rapid decrease by a factor of 7 was observed.

这些产品的主要优点是重量减轻了1/2。

The principal advantage of the products is a two-fold reduction in weight.

但是他相信，通过进一步的研究，最终会找到一种克服排异的方法。过去20年心脏移植手术的成功率直线飙升就是如此。

But he believes more research could eventually find a way to overcome the rejection the way the success rate of heart transplants has soared in the last 20 years.

通过连接技术将能把你所需要的信息和服务集中汇拢。而且无论你在哪儿，无论你在做什么，无论你在使用何种设备，它都能把这些信息和服务传送到你手上。

Universal connectivity will bring together all the information and services you need and make them available to you regardless of where you are, what you are doing, or the kind of device you are using.

中国富有锑、钨、锰、铁等。这些都是重工业有用而必需的金属。

China is rich in antimony, tungsten, manganese, iron, etc. They are useful and necessary metals for heavy industry.

氯碳酸乙酯既是一种酰基氯，也是一种酯。其许多反应都是酰卤所特有的反应。

Ethyl chlorocarbonate is both an acid chloride and an ester; many of its reactions are those characteristic of an acyl halide.

很清楚，情况并非如此。假如真是这样，潮汐预报可能已发布几个世纪了。

This is clearly not the case; if it were true, prediction of the tides could have been done for centuries.

直至最近，零排放汽车的唯一的潜在竞争对手看来很有可能会是电动汽车。汽车制造商声称，电动车对大多数美国人来说，势必会过于昂贵、过于缺乏强劲动力。

Until recently, the only contenders as potential ZEVs (zero-emissions vehicles) seemed likely to be electric vehicles, which the car makers claim will be too expensive and too feeble for most Americans.

它们用纳米取名，而纳米是一种测量单位，其长度为十亿分之一米，是十分方便的用以标定分子尺寸的长度单位。纳米管是在熔炉中由碳电弧和激光所产生的蒸气形成的。

These nanotubes, actually elongated molecules, which take their name from the nanometer, a unit of measurement one-billionth of a meter long—a convenient length for specifying molecular dimensions, form in furnaces from vapor generated by carbon arcs and lasers.

克隆和体外受孕可能会产生异常胎儿。生物学家们正着手寻找原因。

Cloning and IVF (in vitro fertilization) can produce abnormal fetuses, and biologists are starting to find way.

所有这类软件系统都能采集和管理数字化文本和其他图像。不过，开发商们新近增添了不少专项技术，用以进行图像采集、工作流程管理以及文本的采集和格式化。

All document management systems capture and management digitized text and other images, but recently developers have added specialized techniques for image capture, workflow management, text mining and formatting.

事实的真相还有待于证实。不过，假如你患有关节炎，你可能想试一试这个治疗方案，而不去理会有关它的解释。

The truth of the matter has yet to be established; but if you suffer from arthritis, you might want to give the program a try regardless of the explanation.

梅奥假定空气石油两种成分组成的，一是惰性气体，一是活性气体。这一假说由罗瑟福（1772）分离出氮以及谢勒（1773）和普利斯特利（1774）发现氧而得到证实，而拉弗锡（1774）则揭示了大气中氧对燃烧和生命的作用。

Mayrow’s hypothesis that air is composed of two constituents, one inert and one active, was verified by D. Rutherford’s (1772) isolation of nitrogen and the discovery of oxygen by Scheele (1773) and Priestley (1774), while Lavoisier (1774) exposed the role of atmospheric oxygen in combustion and life.

这样还会有另外一个优点：微型碳分子传热比硅快得多，因此更适用于微电子学。军事谋略家们正憧憬着激光通讯时代。

Military planners are already envisioning a day when all communications on a battlefield, between tanks and between tanks and helicopters, to name only two examples, are transmitted by laser.

在这个气层中，前面提及的垂直热输送因边界层中的摩擦影响而被推迟。这样的波浪在风暴生成的纬度带出现极为频繁。

For a long time, we humans have been attracted by moving images, and now we are nearing the time when almost everyone will have opportunity to create polished, professional-looking artwork.

长久以来，我们人类一直为活动影像所吸引。用不了多久，每个人都会有机会去制作精雕细琢的、具有专业风范的艺术作品。

The book remains at rest or, in physical terminology, in static equilibrium not because there are no forces acting on it but because the forces which do act on it annual one another.

其他问题将简单地加以讨论。这个问题必须在适当的时候予以处理。

The international status of Chinese has been further strengthened by the continuous enhancement of China’s international prestige, and thus more and more foreigners want to learn Chinese.

而今中国所有厂家每年生产三百多万辆小汽车。冬季可能需要较多的电力。

Unrealistic claims have been made for disease management and it is easy to be seduced by the latest fashion in healthcare reform.

一切细菌都是肉眼看不见的。在实践中，有时差错似乎总是不可避免的。

A quick reality check confirms that the computer, far from reducing the amount of paper, has actually increased it.

冰在融化时，其温度保持不变。物体一旦运动，就会因惯性而持续运动。

Since a molecule is more stable the less its energy content, the existence of resonance will correspond with increased stability.

这是因为早在十年前人们就发现，一些共轭聚合物表现出电致发光的特性：当有电压通过时，它们就会发光。对大气过程的认知是成功预报的根本，同时也提供了为达到有利目的而能动地调节天气的可能性，并能预见到无意造成的有害影响，免得临期无从避免。

For example, a system initially containing a gaseous mixture of hydrogen, chlorine, and liquid water would very soon closely approach equilibrium with respect to water vapor and liquid water, through the evaporation of water until the partial pressure of water vapor in the gaseous phase became essentially equal to the vapor pressure of liquid water at the temperature of the system.

因为作用于气体的压力增大，故其体积变得更小了。成品在出厂前必须抽样进行质量检查。

Although alternative iron-making processes are emerging, they are not expected to impact significantly on blast production in the next decade and possibly beyond.

铆钉是不可拆连接件。它们依赖于结构的变形来固定。

Consequently, sintering production should be maintained at its present level for some time to come.

机器输出功决不能大于输入功。这项实验结果和那项实验结果成反比。

When you turn a switch, you can easily operate lighting, heating or power-driven electrical devices.

火箭已经用来探索宇宙。激光是近年来最轰动的科学成就之一，因为它可以应用于许多科学领域，也适合各种实践用途。

Laser is one of the most sensational developments in recent years, because of its applicability to many fields of science and its adaptability to practical uses.

因而，每个汽缸都用一个水套围着，水套形成循环回路的一部分，由水泵驱使水在回路中不停地流动，并用由外部鼓进的空气来使水冷却。鼓风用的大型旋转风扇是由主曲轴带动的，而在大型电传动内燃机车上，则由辅助电机带动。

Each cylinder therefore is encased in a water jacket, which forms part of a circuit through which water is pumped continuously, and cooled by means of air drawn in from the outside atmosphere by large rotary fans, worked off the main crankshaft, or, in the larger diesel electric locomotives, by auxiliary motors.

电视机、宇宙飞船和核动力舰艇对今天的人们来说已不是什么新鲜事物，但对于在21世纪20年代末去世的人来说，还似乎是不可思议的东西。考虑到这一点，科学发展的速度之快也就显而易见了。

The increasing speed of scientific development will be obvious if one considers that television, space craft, and nuclear powered ships, which are taken for granted now, would have seemed fantastic to people whose lives ended as recently as 1920.

鱼虽然生活在水中，却也需要氧气，而天然气含有溶解的氧。因此，如果天热过久，水中的溶解氧都散逸掉了，鱼就会死去。

Since natural water contains dissolved oxygen, fishes, which also need oxygen though they live in water, will die if hot days persist so long that the dissolved oxygen is evaporated.

三、联合国秘书长准备好了一份五年调查计划，打算采用经济上合算的、技术上先进的方法来对自然资源进行勘探和估价，从而为这些资源的开发作出贡献。该计划包括矿物资源、水资源、能源和电力方面的九点调查内容，分述如下：

(a) In the field of mineral resources, a survey of off-shore mineral potential in developing areas, a survey of world iron-ore resources, a survey of important non-ferrous metals and a survey of selected mines in developing countries with a view to increasing ore reserves and production through the application of modern technology.

低压暖风供热系统通常采用顺流式燃气炉，它的供热量与送风量的比值为50～70 Btu/hr.cfm， 此燃气炉空气温度可以升高50-70°F。区域控制是这样进行的：传感器感应每个循环回路或区域的回水温度，然后通过调整循环泵的转速或控制阀来调节该区域的循环水量。

Zone control is provided by sensing the return hot water temperature from each individual loop or zone and then varying the water volume flow rate supplied to that zone by modulating the speed of each corresponding on-line circulating pump or its control valve.

热辐射是不同温度区域之间传热的主要机理之一。它有利于导热和对流，因为它既不依赖任何中间物质作为能量载体，也不会受到区域之间的物质干扰。

Radiation, one of the basic mechanisms for energy transfer between different temperature regions, is distinguished from conduction and convection in that it does not depend on an intermediate material as a carrier of energy but rather impeded by the presence of material between the regions.

在日本政府的激励下，房产公司计划为7万户居民修建以硅材料为屋顶瓦片的房子。这些屋顶瓦片能产生足够的电力，从而可以满足大部分居民的用电需要。

Government incentives in Japan have led to plans by housing companies to build 70,000 homes with silicon roofing tiles capable of generating enough electricity to meet most of the residents’ needs.

在早期的试运行过程中，电缆出现故障。在打捞修理时发现电缆覆盖了一层油生命植物，这一事实有违于当时的科学论点，即：在海洋较深的区域没有生命。

At the early attempts, the cable failed and when it was taken out for repairs it was found to be covered in living growths, a fact which defied contemporary scientific opinion that there was no life in the deeper parts of the sea.

此发现与临床观察相一致。临床观察表明，男女精神分裂症的症状不同，而且男性经常较早发病。

The finding correlates with clinical observations of achizophrenics, which show that males and females experience different symptoms and that males are often hit with the disease earlier.

因此，可以把计算机定义为一种高速运行的电子设备。它以被称作程序的指令和被称作数据的字符的形式接收信息，并对这些信息执行数学的和（或）逻辑的操作，然后提供这些运算的结果。

For this reason, computers can be defined as very-high-speed electronic device which accept information in the form of instructions called a program and characters called data, perform mathematical and/or logical operations on the information, and then supply results of these operations.

而且它在市场上的应用非常广泛。在10年之间，专家系统被用来预测股市、帮助医生提高疾病诊断能力、指导矿工找到有望开采的矿藏位置。

And the applications in the market place were extensive, and over the course of ten years, expert systems had been introduced to forecast the stock market, aid doctors with the ability to diagnose disease, and instruct miners to promising mineral locations.

排污系统动力装置是船舶的心脏。

The power plant is the heart of a ship.

虽然中性物体本身是不带电的，但对于带电体来说，它并非中性;当这两个物体彼此接近时，就会产生极性相反的电荷的作用。这就是中性物体被带电体吸引的原因。

The reason that a neutral body is attracted by a charged body is, that although the neutral body is neutral within itself it is not neutral with respect to the charged body, and the two bodies act as if oppositely changed when brought near each other.

制造过程可以分为单件生产和大量生产。前者指的是生产少量的零件，后者则是指生产大量相同的零件。

Manufacturing processes may be classified as unit production with small quantities being made and mass production with large numbers of identical parts being produced.

这个中心正在举办关于科学与文学关系的系列讨论会。与会的诗人和科学家们的讨论议题是：在过去两个多世纪里科学思想对文学和社会变革的影响。

The Center is running a series of talks on the relationship between science and literature, in which poets and scientists discuss how scientific ideas over the past two centuries have influenced literature and social change.

这种观念是错误的。太阳的体积比地球的体积大得多。

The volume of the sun is much larger than that of the earth.

服用新药的病人也许终生都要服药。但由于价格昂贵、疗程复杂，对于那些发展中国家的病人来说，十有八九都不能享用这些药物。

Patients may have to take them for the rest of their lives, and the expense and complexity of the regimen keep them out of reach for the 9 out of 10 patients who live in developing nations.

金属在接触空气、水和湿气体等介质时，会受到破坏性的化学侵蚀，由于这种腐蚀，铁暴露在露天时要牛锈。制造过程可分为单件生产和批量生产。

Iron rusts at its exposure to the open air on account of the corrosion made by the destructive chemical attack of a metal coming into contact with such media as air, water and moisture.